Legal Center
===========================================================================================================

Error

#### Contracts

* [Aritzia - California Disclosure Form and California State Rights](#contract-t-uiejngr)

Test Contract 2
---------------

### Version 3.0

##### Effective December 15th 2022

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit**. Cras finibus mi quis mi sodales, sit amet pulvinar dolor consequat. Suspendisse massa dolor, semper quis vulputate id, accumsan nec erat. In velit orci, tempor cursus efficitur at, viverra a libero. Fusce pretium metus tellus. Sed ornare neque in lorem semper dignissim. Phasellus ultrices mi lectus, in ullamcorper tellus finibus id. Nulla condimentum pretium metus sit amet rhoncus. Nullam varius vehicula odio, nec varius tortor sodales at. Sed placerat dolor id augue vulputate, vitae fringilla odio semper. Morbi elementum orci rutrum purus scelerisque aliquam.

Duis a tincidunt sem, quis finibus ligula. Vivamus at sollicitudin orci. Etiam diam est, tempus vel fringilla vitae, gravida eu diam. Vivamus finibus luctus eros, et sagittis ex lacinia ut. Quisque eu imperdiet metus. Nulla sagittis diam quis ligula tempus venenatis. Nam lectus ligula, tristique et vulputate non, interdum eu lorem. Proin lacinia ipsum at nisl pretium, ut fringilla nibh mollis. Sed sagittis cursus ligula vel placerat.

Website Terms
-------------

### Version 3.0

##### Effective October 19th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

Website Terms

Certn Holdings Inc., including its affiliates Certn (Canada) Inc., Certn (USA) Inc. and any other wholly owned subsidiaries (“**Certn**”, “**we**”, “**us**” or “**our**”) provides the content and services available on this website (the “**Website**”). Except as otherwise provided herein, these website terms (the “**Terms**”) shall govern your access to and use of the services, including features and content available on this Website and other websites offered by Certn, its affiliates and partners, including but not limited to: obtaining, delivering, and managing background reports and related documentation; obtaining status information regarding background reports; Certn’s processes for generating background reports and resolving potential inaccuracies; requesting a copy of your consumer file; and/or any disputes relating to your background check (collectively, the “**Services**”). Your access to, review of, and/or use of the Services is conditioned on your acceptance of and compliance with these Terms.  

General

1. By accessing the Website and/or using the Services, you agree to be bound by these Terms and our [](https://get.chekyourself.co/termsofuse/clkn/https/certn.co/privacy-policy/)Privacy Policy, as well as any additional service terms governing your use of a particular Service, all of which are incorporated herein by reference. The provisions contained in these Terms are in addition to, and do not override, any service agreement signed by related to the Services (the “**Services Agreement**”). **IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THESE TERMS, YOU MAY NOT USE OR ACCESS THE WEBSITE.**
2. You must be 18 years old, or the age of majority in your jurisdiction, in order to generate a background check or use the Services. This Website is not directed to children under 13 years old. If you are under 13 years old, you may not provide personal information to us, make a purchase on the Website, or register on the Website.
3. Certn may revise the Terms at any time without notice to you. The revised Terms will be effective when posted to the Website. Notwithstanding the foregoing, Certn will provide notice of any revisions that may substantively impact or restrict your use of the Website and/or Services.
4. These Terms apply to any and all Certn customers and users of Certn’s Services, including but not limited to individuals, small and large businesses, and nonprofit organizations, who utilize the Services, as well as all others who access the Services, including but not limited to website visitors and users of affiliate websites which allow access to Certn’s Services (“**Customers**” “**Users**,” “**you**,” or “**your**”) including each User’s heirs, assigns and successors. If you use the Services on behalf of a business entity, you represent and warrant that you have the authority to bind that entity, your acceptance of the Terms will be deemed an acceptance by that entity, and “you” and “your” herein shall refer to that entity.
5. Subject to the age restrictions outlined above, you may be able to submit information to us through your use of the Services. You agree to provide us with accurate information about yourself, including any information you may submit for background checks conducted about or requested by you. You further agree that your submission of such information is subject to our Privacy Policy.
6. To the extent these Terms conflict with your Services Agreement, the Services Agreement governs. If you enter into an agreement with Certn providing different or additional terms regarding the Services and there is a conflict between a provision in these Terms and a provision in such agreement, the latter takes precedence with respect to the provision in conflict.

Restrictions

7. You agree not to access or use the Website for any unlawful purpose or for any other purpose other than that for which Certn makes it available. You acknowledge that you shall not: (a) transmit data that is illegal, harmful, threatening, insulting, disturbing, injurious, obscene, defamatory, unacceptable from a racial or ethnic perspective; (b) violate any our Intellectual Property Rights; (c) unlawfully gather information about others; (d) use any information obtained from the Website in order to harass, abuse, or harm another person; (e) attempt to impersonate another User or person or use the username of another User; (f) publish or otherwise transmit any malicious software or other computer codes, files or programs designed to interrupt, disrupt or restrict the operation of our Website, our computer software, hardware, telecommunications equipment or to disrupt the normal transactions onto our Website; (g) use any robot, spider, offline reader, site search, retrieval application or other manual or automatic device or process to retrieve, index, data mine or in any way reproduce or circumvent the structure or presentation of the Website, its contents, or any processed data; (h) make improper use of our support services, submit false requests, or make any speculative or fraudulent background request orders; (i) modify, adapt, sub-license, “frame”, “mirror”, translate, sell, reverse engineer, decompile or disassemble any portion of the Website or otherwise attempt to derive any source code or underlying ideas or algorithms of any part of the Website or Services thereto; (j) use, or attempt to use, the Website for unauthorized purposes; (k) use the Website for the benefit of any third party without Certn’s prior written permission; (l) create derivative works based on the Website or use the Website to develop a competitive product offering; or (m) modify, remove, or obscure any copyright, trademark, patent or other notices or legends that appear on the Website.

User Account

8. You may need to register an account with Certn in order to utilize the Services. You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your account, username, and password and for restricting access to your computer. You agree to accept responsibility for all activities that occur with your permission or authorization under your account, username and/or password. If you are accessing and using the Website and Services on someone else’s behalf, you represent that you have the authority to bind that person as the principal to all Terms provided herein. We reserve the right to refuse service and/or terminate accounts without prior notice if these Terms are violated or if we decide, in our sole discretion, that it would be in our best interest to do so.  

Third-Party Services

10. At your sole discretion, you may choose to take advantage of certain services offered through the Website that are created, offered, supported and maintained by third parties (“**Third-Party Developers**”) unaffiliated with Certn or its affiliates (collectively, “**Third-Party Services**”). Notwithstanding anything to the contrary in these Terms, you acknowledge and agree that: (a) you access or deploy Third-Party Services through the Website at your sole discretion; (b) you should read the terms and conditions and privacy policies associated with any Third-Party Services which govern your use of such Third-Party Services; and (c) Certn does not own or control Third-Party Developers or the Third-Party Services.
11. Certn does not in any way warrant the accuracy, reliability, security, completeness, usefulness, non-infringement, or quality of any Third-Party Services. You agree that you bear all risks associated with using or relying on Third-Party Services.

Intellectual Property and Limited License

12. All intellectual property rights related to the Website and Services shall be owned by Certn absolutely and in their entirety. These rights include database rights, patents, copyrights, trademarks (whether registered or unregistered), trade secrets, design rights (whether registered or unregistered) know-how, mask works, moral rights, and all similar rights that may exist now or later in any jurisdiction, including without limitation any applications and registrations for the foregoing, and the Certn name, logos, designs, domain names, graphics, icons, scripts, service marks, features, functions, text, graphics, button icons, scripts, service marks, images, software, data compilations and other distinctive brand features, and the compilation and organization thereof (collectively, “**Intellectual Property Rights**”). All such Intellectual Property Rights are and will remain the exclusive property of Certn and its subsidiaries, affiliates, partners and licensors, and are protected by Canadian, United States and international laws, including laws governing copyrights and trademarks. Except as explicitly provided herein, or as required under applicable law, nothing in these Terms gives you a right to use the Intellectual Property Rights, and neither the Services nor any portion of the Website may be used reproduced, duplicated, copied, sold, resold, accessed, modified, or otherwise exploited, in whole or in part, for any purpose without our express, prior written consent.
13. Subject to these Terms, Certn grants you a worldwide, limited, revocable, non-exclusive license to access and use the Website and Services as they are provided to you by Certn for your personal, non-commercial use only. The license is non-transferable and non-assignable, and you shall not grant to any third party any right, permission, license or sublicense with respect to any of the rights granted hereunder without Certn’s prior written permission, which it may withhold in its sole discretion. You acknowledge that Certn is the owner and licensor of the Intellectual Property Rights and that your use of the Intellectual Property Rights confers no additional interest in or ownership of the Intellectual Property Rights. Violation of any provision of this license may result in immediate termination of the license, in Certn’s sole discretion.
14. We may invite you to chat or participate in blogs, online forums and other functionality and may provide you with the opportunity to create, submit, publish, or broadcast content and materials to our Website and/or to or via the Website, forms, emails, chat agents, popups, including, without limitation, text, writings, video, audio, photographs, graphics, comments, suggestions or other material (collectively "**Contributions**"). Any Contributions you transmit to Certn will be treated as non-confidential and non-proprietary.

Authorization for Background Check & Certain Rights Under Consumer Rights Legislation, including the FCRA

15. The Services may allow you to request a copy of your background check or background reports about you. By requesting a copy, you authorize Certn and its contractors/providers to use the information you provide to us for purposes of conducting background checks and producing reports for you. You agree that Certn has no obligation to monitor or edit the information you submit to us and that you are solely responsible for the completeness and accuracy thereof.
16. In connection with conducting background checks, Certn may collect certain data including, without limitation, DMV records, criminal records, and other publicly available information. Certn shall treat such data in accordance with our Privacy Policy.
17. To the extent that your request or use of the Services pertain to a US resident, you further acknowledge receipt of and certify that you have reviewed and fully understand the following three statutory notices:
    1. Summary of Your Rights Under the Fair Credit Reporting Act (16 C.F.R. Part 601) located at [http://files.consumerfinance.gov/f/201504\_cfpb\_summary\_your-rights-under-fcra.pdf](http://files.consumerfinance.gov/f/201504_cfpb_summary_your-rights-under-fcra.pdf)
    2. Remedying the Effects of Identity Theft located at [http://files.consumerfinance.gov/f/201410\_cfpb\_summary\_remedying-the-effects-of-id-theft-fcra.pdf](http://files.consumerfinance.gov/f/201410_cfpb_summary_remedying-the-effects-of-id-theft-fcra.pdf)
    3. Notice to Users of Consumer Reports (16 C.F.R. Part 601) located at [https://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/CFR-2012-title12-vol8/pdf/CFR-2012-title12-vol8-part1022-appN.pdf](https://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/CFR-2012-title12-vol8/pdf/CFR-2012-title12-vol8-part1022-appN.pdf)
18. Nothing in these Terms shall impact your right: a) to access certain information in your file by contacting us, or b) to notify us and request that we investigate information in your background check that you believe is inaccurate or incomplete, each as provided in 15 U.S.C. §§ 1681c-1, 1681g, and 1681i, of the FCRA.

Fees

19. In connection with your use of the Services, Certn may charge certain fees (“Fees”) when you order a background report. You agree to pay all applicable Fees or charges based on the terms then in effect. Once Services have been initiated, Fees are nonrefundable. Payment processing services provided by our third-party payment processor are subject to its terms.

Termination

20. You agree that Certn will not be liable to you or any third-party for any termination or limitation of your access to, or use of, the Website.

Disclaimer

21. Except where expressly provided otherwise, the Website is provided on an “as is” and “as available” basis. Certn expressly disclaims all warranties of any kind, whether express or implied, including, but not limited to, the implied warranties of merchantability, fitness for a particular purpose, and non-infringement with respect to the Website and all content provided on, or through, the Website. Certn makes no warranty that: (a) the Website or content will meet your requirements; (b) the Website will be available on an uninterrupted, timely, secure, or error-free basis; (c) the results that may be obtained from the use of the Website, or any content provided on or through the Website, will be absolutely accurate, error-free or reliable; or (d) any content obtained by you on or through the Website will meet your expectations.
22. You acknowledge that: (i) the Website uses the internet for data transfer and internet-connected servers to store background information, sometimes with third-party providers, using industry standard security measures; and (ii) no security measures are 100% effective.

Indemnification

23. You shall indemnify and hold harmless Certn, its affiliates, and subsidiaries and their respective officers, directors, employees, and agents from and against any and all damages, penalties, losses, liabilities, judgments, settlements, awards, costs, and expenses (including reasonable attorneys’ fees and expenses) arising out of or in connection with any third-party claims, assertions, demands, causes of action, suits, proceedings or other actions, whether at law or in equity, related in any manner to: (i) any breach by you of these Terms (ii) your violation of applicable laws or ordinances, or (iii) your negligence, misconduct, recklessness, or errors or omissions.

Limitation of Liability

24. TO THE MAXIMUM EXTENT PERMITTED BY LAW, CERTN AND ITS SUBSIDIARIES, AFFILIATES, PARTNERS, LICENSORS, DIRECTORS, OFFICERS, EMPLOYEES AND AGENTS WILL NOT BE RESPONSIBLE OR LIABLE IN CONTRACT, WARRANTY OR IN TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE) FOR ANY (a) INTERRUPTION OF SERVICES; (b) ACCESS DELAYS OR ACCESS INTERRUPTIONS TO THE SITE; (c) DATA NON-DELIVERY, MISDELIVERY, CORRUPTION, DESTRUCTION, OR OTHER MODIFICATION; (d) LOSS OR DAMAGES OF ANY SORT INCURRED AS A RESULT OF DEALINGS WITH OR THE PRESENCE OF OFF-WEBSITE LINKS ON THE SITE; (e) COMPUTER VIRUSES, SYSTEM FAILURES, OR MALFUNCTIONS WHICH MAY OCCUR IN CONNECTION WITH YOUR USE OF THE SITE OR SERVICES; (f) ANY INACCURACIES, ERRORS OR OMISSIONS IN CONTENT OR (g) EVENTS BEYOND OUR REASONABLE CONTROL.
25. FURTHER, CERTN WILL NOT BE LIABLE IN CONTRACT, WARRANTY, OR IN TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE) OR ANY OTHER LEGAL THEORY FOR ANY INDIRECT, PUNITIVE, SPECIAL, RELIANCE, INCIDENTAL, CONSEQUENTIAL OR SIMILAR DAMAGES OF ANY KIND (INCLUDING LOSS OF REVENUE OR PROFITS) ARISING OUT OF OR RELATING TO THESE TERMS, THE SITE OR YOUR USE THEREOF, INCLUDING THE USE OR INABILITY TO USE THE SERVICES, OR FOR ANY INFORMATION OBTAINED FROM OR THROUGH THE SERVICES, EVEN IF CERTN HAS BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES AND IN NO EVENT EXCEED THE AMOUNT PAID TO CERTN OR ITS PARTNERS UNDER FOR THE SERVICES DURING THE TWELVE MONTH PERIOD IMMEDIATELY PRECEDING THE INITIATION OF ANY CLAIM FOR DAMAGES.
26. CERTN IS NOT LIABLE FOR THE OUTCOMES OF THE RESULTS. YOUR SOLE AND EXCLUSIVE REMEDY WITH RESPECT TO THE CONTENTS OF THE REPORTS IS TO DISPUTE THE RESULTS.  
    
27. THE FOREGOING PARAGRAPHS SHALL NOT EXCLUDE OR LIMIT LIABILITY IN RESPECT OF ANY CLAIM, DEMAND OR ACTION FOR DAMAGES RESULTING FROM GROSS NEGLIGENCE, FRAUD OR WILFUL MISCONDUCT OF CERTN OR ITS EMPLOYEES.
28. Some jurisdictions do not allow the disclaimer or exclusion of certain warranties of the disclaimer, exclusion, or limitation of certain liabilities. To the extent that they are held to be legally invalid, disclaimers, exclusions, and limitations set out in these Terms do not apply to you and all other terms will remain in full force and effect.

Governing Law

28. All matters relating to the Services and your access to, and use of, the Website and content provided on or through the Website, will be governed by the laws in the province of British Columbia and the federal laws of Canada applicable therein.

Miscellaneous

29. The parties are independent contractors. Nothing contained in these Terms shall be construed as creating any employment, agency, partnership, franchise, joint venture, or other form of joint enterprise or authority to bind the other party.
30. Any waiver of a provision of these Terms will only be valid if provided in writing and applies only to the specific occurrence so waived. Failure to enforce any provision will not constitute a waiver.
31. Nothing in these Terms will limit a party’s ability to seek equitable relief.
32. Section headings are not to be used in the interpretation hereof.
33. In the event that any of the provisions in the Terms are held to be invalid or unenforceable in whole or in part, all other provisions will nevertheless continue to be valid and enforceable with the invalid or unenforceable parts severed from the remainder of the Terms

Notices and Consent to Receive Notices Electronically

34. You consent to receive any agreements, notices, disclosures and other communications (collectively, “**Notices**”) to which these Terms refer from us electronically including without limitation by e-mail or by posting notices on this Website. You agree that all Notices that we provide to you electronically satisfy any legal requirement that such communications be in writing.
35. Unless otherwise specified in these Terms, all notices under these Terms will be in writing and will be deemed to have been duly given when received, if personally delivered or sent by certified or registered mail, return receipt requested; when receipt is electronically confirmed, if transmitted by facsimile or email; or the day after it is sent, if sent for next day delivery by recognized overnight delivery service.
36. If you have any questions about these Terms, you can contact customer support via email sent to [support@certn.co](mailto:support@certn.co).

Privacy Policy
--------------

### Version 2.1

##### Effective August 1st 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

Privacy Policy
==============

Our mission is to help you foster certainty and trust by providing international data verification and background screening services. Our commitment to protecting your right to privacy is central to our mission of fostering certainty and trust. This Policy describes how we collect, use, and share your personal information, including:

\- to provide you with a better experience on our Website through the collection of anonymized browsing statistical data from the use of cookies or other technologies;

\- to manage your account when you have signed-up with us, including to manage your registration, if applicable, and provide better assistance and support;

\- to contact our Clients or Consumers by email, telephone, or other equivalent forms of electronic communication, where necessary and related to the Service requested;

\- to provide you with news and general information about our Services;

\- to issue a consumer report on you, if you have submitted and consented to a screening application with us, or with our Client.

By using Certn’s Websites and Services, as defined below, you are confirming that you have read, fully understand, and agree to this Policy.

1. **WHO ARE WE AND WHO ARE YOU?**

This privacy policy (“**Policy**”) describes how Certn Holdings Inc. and its affiliates,, including Certn (Canada) Inc., Certn (USA) Inc., Credence Background Screening (UK) and any other wholly owned subsidiary (collectively “**Certn**” or “**we**” or “**our**”), collects, uses, discloses, and processes Personal Information in connection with websites owned by Certn (“**Website**(**s**)”), as well as its products and services (our “**Services**”).

This Policy applies to the following users:

* “**Consumers**”: Individuals about which we have received information for the purpose of using our Website(s) or performing our Services.
* “**Clients**”: Organizations or individuals using our Services.
* “**Website Visitors**”: Individuals, Consumers or Clients of legal age accessing our Website.

We do not knowingly solicit information from anyone under the age of thirteen (13). If you become aware of any Personal Information shared by or on behalf of a child, please contact us using the contact information provided in the “Contact Us” section below.

2. **WHAT IS PERSONAL INFORMATION AND WHAT DO WE DO WITH IT?**

For the purposes of this Policy, “**Personal Information**” is any information that identifies, relates to, describes, is capable of being associated with, or could reasonably be linked, directly or indirectly, to or with an identified or identifiable individual.

Personal Information does not include business information, such as our Clients’ business address and telephone number.

We collect, process and disclose only the Personal Information required in the course of providing our Services. “**Processing**” (or “**processes**” or “**processed**”) includes any operation or set of operations which is performed on Personal Information, or on sets of Personal Information, whether or not by automated means. This includes the collection, recording, organization, structuring, storage, adaptation or alteration, retrieval, consultation, use, disclosure by transmission, transfer, dissemination or otherwise making available, alignment or combination, restriction, erasure or destruction of Personal Information.

We do not make decisions about you, automated or otherwise, and we do not attempt to analyze or predict your behavior, preferences, interests, health or other personal characteristics. However, we may carry out automated Processing on our Client’s instructions.

By using our Website or our Services, you consent to the Processing of your Personal Information subject to the provisions of this Policy. **If you do not agree with this Policy or do not wish to provide your Personal Information to us, please do not use our Website or Services.**

If you choose to provide us with a limited scope of Personal Information, we may not be able to provide our full range of Services or deliver the best experience on our Website.

3. **WHAT ARE OUR PRINCIPLES FOR PROCESSING INFORMATION?**

We are committed to protecting your Personal Information and will adhere to the following principles regardless of the type of data Processing we conduct for you:

1. **Lawfulness, fairness and transparency in Processing Personal Information:** All Personal Information collected in relation to our Services is Processed on the basis of the mutual contractual interest of our Client and the Consumer.
2. **Integrity and confidentiality:** Certn protects data against unauthorized or unlawful access and accidental damage. We are SOC 2, SOC 3 and ISO 27001 certified. To learn more on how we protect personal and non-personal information, please reach out to our privacy officers (contact information below).
3. **Purpose limitation:** Our terms stipulate that Clients are required to certify a Permissible Purpose, as defined below, prior to using our Services. Consumers are informed of the Permissible Purpose before we Process any Personal Information.
4. **Data minimization:** We only collect the Personal Information necessary to provide the Services in accordance with the Permissible Purpose.
5. **Storage limitation:** Certn will only keep data for as long as necessary for the fulfillment of the defined Permissible Purpose, our legal responsibilities or for delivering our contractual commitments.
6. **Data accuracy:** Certn takes reasonable steps to ensure that processed Personal Information is complete, current, and accurate. To ensure all data is verified accurately, we encourage Consumers to review their data entries prior to submitting a verification check through our platform. We provide applicants with the option to correct their Personal Information and process disputes for any reported inaccuracies.
7. **Accountability:** Certn believes in transparent data Processing and Consumer control. We work with our Clients and our staff to maintain Consumer privacy rights and industry standard policies and procedures for operationalizing privacy in all data processing activities internally and externally. Certn has appointed a designated Privacy Officer and we encourage you to reach out to them at [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co) with any questions or comments you may have in relation to this Policy or the Processing of your Personal Information.

4. **HOW IS THIS POLICY UPDATED?**

We reserve the right to modify this Policy at any time. All Website Visitors are encouraged to periodically review this Policy to stay informed of updates. Your continued use of our Website and Services following the posting of changes to this Policy will mean you agree with, and consent to be bound by, the new revised Policy.

5. **WHAT PERSONAL INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT, WHY, HOW AND FROM WHOM?**

**Legal Basis for Processing**

We Process your Personal Information (i) to provide our Services, (ii) to communicate with you, (iii) for security and fraud prevention, and (iv) to comply with the law. We may also use Personal Information for other purposes, subject to your consent. We will not Process your Personal Information unless we have the legal right to do so.

To Process your Personal Information lawfully, we rely on at least one legal basis as set forth by applicable law. Depending on your relationship with us, the legal basis to Process your Personal Information may include, among other things, your consent, the requirement to Process data for the performance of a contract with you, to comply with a legal obligation, or on the basis of legitimate interest.

If our legal basis for collecting and using Personal Information is your consent, you can withdraw or modify your consent for future collection or use of your Personal Information at any time, and we will explain the consequences of doing so. If we use your Personal Information for sales or marketing purposes, you can ask us to stop at any time and we will do so.

**Permissible Purpose for Processing**

Our Clients must certify that they have a Permissible Purpose before we can Process Personal Information for the purposes of providing the Services. “Permissible Purpose” includes employment purposes, tenancy purposes or in accordance with the written instructions of the Consumer with whom the Client intends to contract with.

We will not reuse Personal Information for any other purpose other than the one for which it was collected, unless one or more of the following is true:

* the new use is compatible with the original one, meaning you should reasonably expect it;
* we have notified you of the new use and given you an opportunity to object to it; or
* the new use is otherwise permitted or required by law.

We collect, use, and disclose Consumer Personal Information when the Consumer is aware of the Permissible Purpose for which the information will be Processed, and has given his or her consent to such Processing, except where the Processing of Personal Information without consent is permitted or required by law. Subject to regulatory requirements, operating our Services in certain jurisdictions requires us or our Clients to obtain additional or specific consents in the form of additional consent form/s, telephone call/s, through an online platform or other methods. Where the Consumer does not provide such consent or specific consent directly to us, but to our Clients, we require our Clients to obtain the Consumer’s consent prior to providing us with the Consumer’s Personal Information subject to verification for any of our Services. The Consumer may withdraw such consent previously granted at any time by contacting us. Withdrawing such consent does not affect the lawfulness of any processing based on the consent before the withdrawal.

**What Information do we Process?**

* Non-Personal Information Processing: We Process non-Personal Information in order to track trends and analyze use patterns of our Website and our platform. Non-Personal Information (“non-Personal Information”) means information or content other than Personal Information, including, for example, aggregated or anonymized information about our users and other information that does not identify any individual.
* Website Visitor information Processing: We may log your operating system name and version, device identifier, browser type, operating system, Internet Protocol (IP) address, screen resolution, the pages you viewed on our Websites, how long you spent on a page, access times, general location information such as city, state or geographic area, and information about your use of and actions on our Website/s.
* Client Personal Information Processing: When you subscribe to our Services, you may be asked to enter your full name, e-mail, business name, business address, phone number, billing address, card address, and other information provided by customer through custom fields, if any. Financial information, such as data related to your payment method (e.g., valid credit card number, card brand, expiration date) is never collected by us either through our Website or otherwise. Upon processing payments, you are transferred to a secure page on the website of Stripe or some other PCI DSS certified payment service provider. That page may be dressed in our “livery”, but it is not managed by us. All financial information is Processed by our payment processor and you are encouraged to review their privacy policy and contact them directly for responses to your questions.
* Consumer Personal Information Processing: Certn will only collect Consumer Personal Information from you if you voluntarily choose to provide such information in connection with a background check authorized by you and/or applicable laws. The type of Personal Information that Certn may collect about you through our Website or otherwise will vary depending on local regulations and the data verification Service request. For clarity, below is a non-exclusive list of the Personal Information we may collect, the reason for the collection, and the course of collection pertaining to the provision of our Services.

Some information, including criminal records, credit information and biometric data, may be considered sensitive or may be subject to special protections in some jurisdictions. Such information will not be collected in every case, and will not be collected where prohibited by law, and where permitted, will only be collected and used in accordance with applicable law.

|     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- |
| **Personal Information We May Collect** | **Reason For Collection** | **Course of Collection** |
| Your name(s) | Required for identification. Former names may be needed to conduct a complete background check, as old records may be held under a former name. | Provided by you, either as the Consumer or Client, public records, credit reporting agencies, or third parties you have consented to us contacting |
| Date of birth | Required for identification. | Provided by you |
| Place of birth | Required for some of our services. | Provided by you |
| Identification documentation and biometric data | If we are requested to verify your identity through our OneID Service, we use a biometric system based on facial recognition technology (biometric data) to verify and confirm your identity live online by matching a real-time picture of your face to the photo on your identification document. | Provided by you |
| Contact information | Some of our services require us to collect residential address history. Further, to ensure we are able to get in touch with you for the purpose of providing services, we may require your mailing address, email address or telephone number.<br><br>We will only use contact information for the purpose of providing services and comply with our Client’s instructions and our legal obligations. We will not contact you for any other reason. | Provided by you, credit reporting agencies, or public records |
| Government-issued identity numbers | Some services require this information, as records we need to retrieve from third parties are often associated with a government identity number.<br><br>This may include criminal records, credit files, employment history or driving records. | Provided by you |
| Criminal history and police records | Necessary for criminal record checks. | Provided by you, law enforcement or other government agencies, courts, or public records |
| Credit or bankruptcy history | Some services require us to obtain financial or identity information found in a credit file with a credit bureau or in public record information. | Credit reporting agencies, government agencies, or public records |
| Employment history | To verify employment or activity history over a certain period of time | Provided by you, our Client, current or past employers or their record-keeping service providers, agencies that placed you with your current or past employers, or references you have provided |
| Education history | To verify education or activity history over a certain period of time. | Provided by you, our Client, educational institutions you have attended or their record-keeping service providers for educational institutions you have attended, government education authorities in jurisdictions where you have attended school, or references you have provided |
| Professional credentials, designations, memberships, sanctions or reprimands | To verify standing as a certain type of professional, participation or completion of professional development courses, or the existence of professional sanctions or reprimands. | Provided by you, our Client, professional organizations with which you have been associated, or their recordkeeping service providers, public records, or references you have provided |
| Opinions about you | To conduct reference interviews.<br><br>Additionally, opinions may be provided during verifications of employment or volunteering. | Provided by you, our Client, your current or past employers or their recordkeeping service providers, agencies that placed you with your current or past employers, or references you have provided |
| Appearance on government watch or sanctions lists | Some Clients wish to check for presence on government watch or sanctions lists. | Provided by law enforcement or other government agencies, public information |
| Eligibility to work | To verify potential employees’ legal status in the jurisdiction where they operate. | Provided by you, our Client, or government agencies |
| Driving records | To check driver’s license validity and driving history. | Provided by you, our Client, or government agencies |
| Directorship and corporate governance history | To verify current or past involvement with corporations as a director or officer. | Provided by you, our Client, public records, corporations with which you have had previous involvement. |
| Public record information and negative media | Some services require us to obtain public record information including negative media results. | Provided by you, our Client, government agencies, or public records |
| Telephone call recordings | We monitor some phone calls for quality assurance and training purposes. | Provided by you |
| Drug test results (for USA Consumers only) | We provide results for controlled substances issued by drug testing labs | Provided by labs after your drug testing |

**How do we Process Personal Information?**

Most of the Personal Information we collect comes from you, either directly or through one of our Clients. Our processes for collecting and transcribing Personal Information are automated to the greatest extent possible and are subject to rigorous quality controls. Information that is found to be inaccurate, either through our own audits or following your request for correction, is updated.

When we provide Services directly to Consumers:

* You determine what Personal Information we collect, and its purpose;
* Once we receive your consent, we collect and Process information in accordance with applicable laws; and
* You control and own the Personal Information, and can request remediation or deletion at any time.

When we provide Services to Clients:

* The Client provides instructions on what Personal Information to collect, and how to collect it;
* If appropriate, the Client ensures that Consumers are notified of, or provide consent for, the collection and Processing of their Personal Information in accordance with applicable laws;
* The Client ensures that Personal Information is collected and Processed lawfully, fairly and in a transparent manner, consistent with the Permissible Purpose;
* The Client confirms that Personal Information is accurate and, when necessary, kept up to date, rectified or erased; and
* The Client ensures that appropriate safeguards are in place to protect Personal Information;

We are generally responsible for the following aspects of collection and Processing of Personal Information:

* We carry out the Services requested by our Client or Consumer, in accordance with their instructions;
* We protect Personal Information in our custody against loss, theft, or any unauthorized access, disclosure, copying, use or modification, in a way that is appropriate to how sensitive it is, and in accordance with our Client’s instructions, and applicable laws;
* We comply with any legal obligations we may have as a data processor, custodian, service provider or similar under applicable laws.

Collection of Personal Information for security purposes is done based on our legitimate interest and legal obligation to ensure Personal Information in our custody is protected.

6. **HOW IS PERSONAL INFORMATION SHARED AND WHEN DO WE ENGAGE IN CROSS-BORDER PROCESSING?**

Personal Information we collect is stored on infrastructure provided by AWS within Canada, as well as the United States, the United Kingdom and Australia (“Storage Locations”). It may be necessary for us to collect, Process and disclose Personal Information across borders, including outside of our Storage Locations for the purposes of verifying work or education history, as well as providing other similar Services. As such, we may transfer your Personal Information on the basis of:

1. Adequacy decision
2. Appropriate safeguards
3. Your consent
4. Other jurisdictional considerations

In cases where the Client is located in, or the Consumer is residing or has resided in, the state of California, the province of Quebec, the UK, Australia, the EU, and/or the EEA, specific requirements may apply to the transfer of Personal Information. When you browse our Website, you consent to this Policy. Furthermore, when you submit your information, you consent to such cross-border transfer.

We take all measures reasonably necessary to ensure that your Personal Information is treated securely and in accordance with this Policy, and we will not transfer Personal Information to an organization or a country unless there are adequate controls in place to ensure the security of your data.

If you have any questions as to whether your information will be Processed overseas, and/or if you have any restrictions or conditions regarding the release of your information across borders, please contact us as soon as possible so we may discuss your specific requirements.

7. **WHO ELSE MAY ACCESS COLLECTED INFORMATION?**

In addition to those parties specified in the figure above, the following third parties may have legitimate access to your Personal Information:

* auditors for the performance of contracted or statutory compliance audits;
* Certn affiliates and partners who are participating in the delivery of our Services; and
* third-parties that perform services for us or on our behalf, including but not limited to payment processing, data analysis, email delivery, SaaS, IaaS, or PaaS services.

When we provide Services to a Client, the Consumer Personal Information is Processed and reported through our secure platform. Apart from our Clients and in addition to authorized Certn personnel who may access your Personal Information for the purposes outlined in this Policy, we may provide your Personal Information to authorities or partner companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as offering customer service or processing your payment. For more information on the third-party companies who provide such services to us, please click [here](https://info.certn.co/dpa-subprocessors/).

In exceptional circumstances, we may be requested to communicate Personal Information with law enforcement agencies, national security agencies, courts, or other similar institutions as required by law. If in receipt of a production order, subpoena, warrant, or other enforceable demand, we will act in compliance as required by the applicable laws. We do not sell or disclose your Personal Information to governments, marketing or advertising services, other Clients, or anyone else except as outlined in this Policy or as required by law.

8. **HOW DO WE STORE AND PROTECT PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

We are SOC2, SOC3 and ISO27001 certified and maintain advanced technical, administrative, organizational, physical, electronic and procedural safeguards that comply with those standards and protect your Personal Information from unauthorized access, loss, misuse, interference or alteration during its collection, use, disclosure, and storage. We perform security audits, vulnerability scans, and penetration tests on a regular basis to ensure compliance with industry security practices and standards.

All our staff, suppliers and contractors are security vetted prior to taking up employment. All staff are data protection trained and are aware of their responsibilities. Such training is conducted repeatedly on a regular or random basis, but at least once a year.

We limit access to Personal Information to individuals with a legitimate business need consistent with the reason and purpose for which the information was provided. We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your Personal Information when orders are placed or when you enter, submit, or access your Personal Information. We encrypt Processed information both in transit and at rest. All supplied sensitive information is transmitted via Transport Layer Security (TLS) technology and then stored in our database and only accessed by those authorized with special access rights to our systems, who are required to keep the information confidential.

In addition, we have processes in place to encourage our Clients to comply with applicable privacy laws and security standards. Such processes include but are not limited to entering into binding agreements with our Clients and conducting mutual random audits of each other’s internal procedures and practices to ensure that regulatory standards and security levels are mutually met and exceeded at all times.

9. **HOW LONG IS YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION RETAINED?**

We will retain your information for as long as needed to provide you with our Services and/or as necessary to comply with our contractual and legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

Data required to establish proof of a right or a contract will be stored for the duration provided by applicable law. Upon your request to terminate your account, we will deactivate or delete your account and information from our active databases. However, some information may be retained in our files to prevent fraud, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigations, enforce our terms and/or compliance with legal requirements.

In relation to Consumer Personal Information, unless records have been subject to a deletion request, the retention and disposal schedule shall be no more than three (3) years. Exceptions may exist for specific data sets as governed by regulatory or third-party data providers’ retention requirements. For example, we will not store any of your biometric data following the completion of your identity verification via OneID. Where required, we may keep general information as a log and for auditing purposes.

10. **HOW TO EXERCISE YOUR PRIVACY RIGHTS?**

Regardless of your place of residence, we will review any privacy request free of charge and take steps to support you in exercising your privacy rights to:(i) be informed, (ii) access, (iii) rectification, (iv) erasure, (v) processing restrictions, (vi) data portability, (vii) object processing, (viii) not be subject to a decision based on automated decision making, and (ix) file a complaint

You can use the details in the “Contact us” section to raise any requests or questions for exercising your privacy rights.

Upon receipt of a written request, and after verifying you as the data owner, we respond to privacy right requests, disputes and complaints as soon as practicable, and in any event, within the time limits prescribed by law. However, where we refuse to do so, we will give you a written notice setting out the reasons within 30 days of the receipt of your request.

For the purposes of compliance and where required by law or contract, prior to actioning any privacy right request, we will inform the Client connected to such request, if any, as well as any other third parties who may have Processed your Personal Information.

11. **ARE THERE ADDITIONAL JURISDICTIONAL CONSIDERATIONS**

**USA California**

For purposes of the California Consumer Privacy Act (“CCPA”), we do not “sell” Consumer Personal Information to third parties for direct marketing purposes. Personal Information Processed for the purposes of delivering a background check is exempt from CCPA.

To the extent that you are a California resident and in the event we may have Processed categories of your Personal Information beyond the CCPA exemption in relation to delivering a background check, you have the right to access your Personal Information, delete it, have it disclosed, opt out of sales, and be free from discrimination. You can contact us to exercise any of these rights. For compliance purposes, we may require additional information from you in order to honor your request.

**USA Nevada**

We do not sell Consumer Personal Information to third parties for direct marketing purposes.

**EU, EEA, Swiss and UK residents**

Subject to the consideration that we occasionally Process Personal Information of EU, EEA, Swiss and UK residents, we have taken measures to comply with those jurisdictional standards and ensure that all recipients of any such Personal Information provide an adequate level of data protection based on, but not limited to, commitments to standard contractual clauses and/or international data transfer agreement/s as applicable.

EU, EEA, Swiss and UK Consumers have certain rights regarding the Processing of Personal Information. If you are an EU/EEA/UK resident, you have:

* the right to request details of the Personal Information we have about you;
* the right to ask that we update your information if it is inaccurate or incomplete;
* the right to ask that we delete your information in certain circumstances;
* the right to withdraw your consent to the use of your information where we are relying on that consent;
* in some circumstances, you have the right to receive some of your information in a usable format and/or request we transmit that data to a third party where this is technically feasible;
* the right to request that we restrict the Processing of your Personal Information in certain circumstances; and
* the right to lodge a complaint with your local data protection authority if you think we have not been able to assist you.

If you would like to exercise your rights in relation to your consumer report, we will support your request in our capacity as a data processor and in alignment with our Client who ordered the report in their capacity as a controller.

To log your request, please contact us. We will contact you if we need additional information from you in order to deliver the applicable information or undertake specific actions to honor your request in exercising your rights.

**Brazil**

Brazilian residents may have certain rights to:

* confirm whether we Process your Personal Information;
* request access to your Personal Information that is being Processed by us;
* rectify incomplete, inaccurate or outdated Personal Information;
* request the anonymization, blocking or deletion of unnecessary or excessive information or information Processed in noncompliance with the provisions of the LGPD (Lei Geral de Proteção de Dados Pessoais);
* request data portability;
* be informed about third parties with whom your Personal Information has been shared; and
* request a review of automated decisions that affect your interests.

To exercise your rights in relation to your consumer report, we will support your request in our capacity as a processor and in alignment with our Client who ordered the report in their capacity as a controller.

To log your request, please contact us by using our contact details provided below. We will contact you if we need additional information from you in order to deliver the applicable information or undertake specific actions to honor your request in exercising your rights.

**Australia**

Please see section 15 below.

12. **HOW DO WE USE COOKIES?**

Our Website uses cookies and other similar technologies to provide functionality, analyze traffic and personalize some of your web content.

**What are cookies?**

Cookies are small text data files that are sent to your computer or mobile device by a Website while browsing. You will be presented with information about our cookies and an option to accept all cookies or customize your cookie preferences when you first visit our Website and occasionally from the cookie banner thereafter. You can consent to or refuse all cookies at any time when browsing the Website. You can choose and manage all of your cookies at any time through your browser settings. If you disable cookies you may be unable to access or fully use certain parts or functionalities of the Website.

There are different kinds of cookies with different functions:

* **Session cookies:** these are only stored on your computer during your web session. They are automatically deleted when the browser is closed. They usually store an anonymous session ID allowing you to browse a Website without having to log in to each page. They do not collect any information from your computer.
* **Persistent cookies:** a persistent cookie is one stored as a file on your computer, and it remains there when you close your web browser. The cookie can be read by the Website that created it when you visit that Website again.
* **First-party cookies:** the function of this type of cookie is to retain your preferences for a particular Website for the entity that owns that Website. They are stored and sent between Certn’s servers and your computer’s hard drive. They are not used for anything other than for personalization as set by you. These cookies may be either session or persistent cookies.
* **Third-party cookies:** the function of this type of cookie is to retain your interaction with a particular Website for an entity that does not own that Website. They are stored and sent between a third-party’s server and your computer’s hard drive. These cookies are usually persistent cookies.

First-party cookies are necessary for the proper operation of our Website. Our Website also allows for the use of third-party cookies, which can be read externally by other organizations. As such, we cannot be responsible for third party cookies, i.e., cookies that are not initiated by us. Our service platforms, which we use to collect information from Consumers and Clients, do not use third-party cookies.

**Using cookies**

**Necessary Cookies:** By using our Website, you agree that we can store and access necessary cookies on your device. These cookies do not gather information about you that could be used for marketing or remembering where you have been on the internet.

**Statistic cookies:** These are anonymous and cannot be used to identify you. Statistic cookies help us improve our Website functions and collect information on how you use the Website (such as how often you visit our Website, the links you clicked on, the pages you prefer most). Consenting to those cookies will allow us to produce anonymous statistical reports for Website improvement purposes.

**Preferences cookies:** In order to remember the choices you have previously made (such as selected language or saved username and password), to allow for quicker browsing, and provide enhanced features we need to enable preference cookies. The information these cookies collect is usually anonymized.

**Marketing cookies:** These may be set across websites by third parties. They do not store personal information but identify your browser and your internet device to help advertisers in showing you relevant advertisements.

**Website log data:** Certn’s web servers log the following information during visits to our Website: IP addresses, type of operating system, time and duration of visit, web pages visited and browser type. We do not link server log information to any other information in a way that would enable the identification of Website Visitors to our Website. Apart from analyzing such logs to provide you with a better experience on our Website, server logs may be reviewed for security purposes and if necessary, to detect unauthorized activity on our Website. In such cases, server log data, containing IP addresses, would be shared with law enforcement bodies in order that they may identify users in connection with their investigation of the unauthorized activities.

13. **WHO IS THE PRIVACY OFFICER?**

We have a dedicated privacy officer who may be contacted in relation to any privacy or data protection issues at [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co).

14. **CONTACT US**

If there are any questions regarding this Policy, the practices of this Website or your dealings with this Website, you may contact us at privacy@certn.co or use the available options set out below:

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| **CANADA**<br><br>Certn (Canada) Inc. | 1006 Fort St<br><br>Unit 300<br><br>Victoria, BC V8V 3K4<br><br>+1-844-987-0690<br><br>[privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co) for any privacy-related questions<br><br>[support@certn.co](mailto:support@certn.co) for any support questions<br><br>[compliance@certn.co](mailto:compliance@certn.co) for any compliance questions<br><br>[legal@certn.co](mailto:legal@certn.co) for any legal matters |
| **UNITED STATES**<br><br>Certn (USA) Inc. | Trust Center<br><br>1209 Orange Street<br><br>Wilmington, New Castle County, Delaware, 19801<br><br>+1-844-987-0690<br><br>[privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co) for any privacy-related questions<br><br>[support@certn.co](mailto:support@certn.co) for any support questions<br><br>[compliance@certn.co](mailto:compliance@certn.co) for any compliance questions<br><br>[legal@certn.co](mailto:legal@certn.co) for any legal matters |
| **UNITED KINGDOM**<br><br>Credence Background Screening Limited | 160 London Road<br><br>Sevenoaks, Kent, TN13 1BT<br><br>+44 (0)1732 748 900<br><br>[contact@credence.co.uk](mailto:contact@credence.co.uk) and [support@credence.co.uk](mailto:support@credence.co.uk) for general queries<br><br>[dpo@credence.co.uk](mailto:dpo@credence.co.uk) for privacy-related queries |
| **AUSTRALIA**<br><br>InterCheck Global Pty. Ltd. | 356 Collins Street<br><br>Melbourne, 3000, Victoria<br><br>+61 (03) 8820 4069<br><br>[help@intercheck.com.au](mailto:help@intercheck.com.au) |

15. **AUSTRALIA - INTERCHECK GLOBAL PTY LTD.**

Certn recently partnered with InterCheck Global Pty Ltd. (“**InterCheck Australia**”) for the purposes of providing specific services in Australia. If you are located in Australia, either as a Consumer or a Client, the above terms are subject to and restricted by this section. Any reference to “**we**”, “**us**” “**our**” or “**Certn**” shall specifically include InterCheck Australia.

1.   
    1. Our Privacy Pledge

We understand that privacy is important to you and we value your trust in engaging with our services. That’s why, InterCheck Australia is fully committed to protecting your personal and sensitive information and aims to be clear and open about how we use your information to provide you with our services.

Information security and privacy is at the front of everything we do, so you can continue to have trust and confidence in dealing with our organisation now, and well into the future.

As such InterCheck Australia is fully committed to keeping your personal information confidential. We ensure compliance with federal and state Australian Privacy Laws and the Australian Privacy Principles as set out in the Privacy Act 1988.

This policy explains how we gather, handle, store, share, destroy and use your personal information and provides clear guidelines for you, so you can understand how we manage and protect your information.

2.   
    2. Introduction

InterCheck Australia provides verification services for and on behalf of our clients who engage us to provide employment screening and probity checks of potential or existing employees, volunteers, contractors and consultants, to assess their suitability for employment or a position of trust. This service extends to individuals who require verification services for and on behalf of themselves for employment, positions of trust or verification purposes.

3.   
    3. Why do we collect personal information?

InterCheck Australia is an Australian company that provides background checks and verification services to both individuals and businesses. In order to provide our services InterCheck Australia needs to collect personal and sensitive information from individuals for the purpose of conducting our services. We may also use some of this information to better understand your needs, as a customer, so we can better design and improve our products and services and to potentially let you know about other products and services you may be interested in.

4.   
    4. What information do we collect?

In the course of business, it is necessary for us to collect Personal Information. We collect different personal and sensitive information depending on the product or service that you have requested or how you have engaged with our services. The information we collect from you may include:

1. **For Criminal History Checks:** Sourced from the Australian Federal Police AFP and/or Australian Criminal Intelligence Commission (ACIC) -Name including Surname, Given name(s), all previously known names including aliases. Contact information including phone numbers and email addresses. Date of Birth and Place of Birth. Sensitive information including, Gender type, Biometric information, such as photographs collected from your phone or a webcam. Demographic information, such as occupation, place of residence for the past five years. Identity documents including License permits (driver’s license, firearms license) or Passport details. Information or opinion relating to the applicant’s current or previous application process, including information relating to the applicant’s check purpose, including the place of work.
2. **For other Background Checks or Verification Checks:** For the purpose of providing verification services, we may need to collect: Qualification or memberships, Resume information, occupations, references and referees details, contact details, addresses, date and place of birth, skills, qualifications, residential history, credit or bank details, citizenship and immigration status, professional or trade associations and memberships or accreditations, employment history and past responsibility or any other information relating to your career.
3. **Identity Document Information:** For the purpose of identity verification and to confirm that the person making the application and giving consent are the same; we may need to collect Identity documents and information, including Biometric information, such as a live photograph in order to link the applicant to the identity documents.
4. **Contact and Business Information:** In order to provide our services and support in a professional and effective manner, we may collect information such as, email address, phone numbers, residential business and postal addresses, occupation and role, credit card details and business information, including ABN contact details that allows us to transact with the individual and/or provide them with our services and support.

5.   
    5. Sensitive information

Due to the nature of the products and services that InterCheck Australia provides, some of your personal information that we collect and hold will be ‘sensitive information.’ This information will only be obtained with your consent and we will only use it for the purpose for which you provided, except where otherwise allowed by law. Some types of sensitive information we collect include citizenship and immigration status, criminal history information, biometric and demographic information and gender information.

6.   
    6. How do we collect your personal information?

The personal or sensitive information we collect about you is that in which you provide to us or which you authorise us to obtain.

InterCheck Australia collects this information either directly from you or from your employer/or a 3rd party, only when you have provided consent for them to provide the information. All information collected is done so lawfully, fairly, and not in an intrusive way and will only be collected with your consent.

We collect personal information in the following ways:

* Via our secure online application form on our website.
* When you complete and send a signed hard copy application form, either via the post or electronically.
* In person, over the phone or via email, for example, when you engage with our Help Desk; customers are made aware of the risks involved in sending any information including personal information such as identity documents, by mail or email in these instances.
* When you connect to a third party or connect to our services via a third party, for example, an integration partner, and have consented and are aware that InterCheck Australia will be collecting the information for the purpose of providing our employment screening services.
* In the course of providing services to you. We may also collect information about you from third party suppliers and government database services, for the purposes of Identifying you and linking you to the provided identity documents.

7.   
    7. Use and disclosure of your personal information

We’re careful about how we use your information. The primary reason we collect, use and share your personal information is to enable the delivery of our products and services. We may also use your information to better understand your needs, so we can better design and improve our products and services and to potentially let you know about other products and services you may be interested in.

We collect, hold, use and disclose personal information for a variety of business purposes including:

* to provide the products or services you have requested from us; including:
* to lodge Nationally Coordinated Criminal History Checks Application and receive Police Check results from the National Police Checking Service, the service administered and operated by ACIC.
* to comply with our obligations under the agreement we have with the Australian Criminal Intelligence Commission (ACIC) regarding the National Police Checking Service. For more information about our agreement with the ACIC please refer below.
* to conduct a Visa Entitlement Verification Online (VEVO) check or to verify identity through the Australian Department of home affairs.
* for proof of identity purposes.
* to contact and communicate with you and to handle and respond to your enquiries, complaints or concerns.
* to process payments.
* to contact and communicate with you.
* for any other purpose we explain when the personal information was collected, including the use and disclosures outlined in this Policy; and
* to help improve our business, products and services and to help manage our business.
* to communicate with you about the relationship with us, including being able to provide our products and services to you.
* to comply with laws, obligations and to provide assistance to government or law enforcement authorities.
* to be able to lodge an application for and receive the results of an identity verification check with the document issuer through the Department of Home Affairs Document Verification Service (DVS).

8.   
    8. Accreditation with the Australian Criminal Intelligence Commission (ACIC)

InterCheck Australia is a duly accredited body, in accordance with its agreement under the ‘Agreement for controlled access by duly Accredited Bodies to Nationally Coordinated Criminal History Checks’ (‘Agreement’) in order to undertake the fulfillment NCCHC for eligible applicants.

This agreement sets out the obligations and requirements necessary for InterCheck Australia to maintain accreditation status and access to the National Police Checking Service. If you wish to contact the ACIC please direct all enquiries via email to [npcs@acic.gov.au](mailto:npcs@acic.gov.au)

9.   
    9. Providing you new products or services

From time to time, we may also use your information to tell you about products or services (including 3rd parties) we think you might be interested in. To do this, we may contact you by email, phone, SMS, social media, mail or other forms of advertising.

10.   
    10. Opting “In” or “Out”

If you do not want us to send you marketing communications via email you can opt out at any time by using the unsubscribe option available. To opt out of all other means of communication, please contact our Data Protection Officer using the contact details provided below.

11.   
    11. How long will we keep your personal information?

We will keep your information for as long as you are a customer of InterCheck Australia, or pursuant to our legal obligations. For example, Australian Criminal History Checks are deleted after 12 months and identity documents supporting that same application must be retained for 12 months and deleted within 15 months.

12.   
    12. Who do we disclose your personal information to?

We will disclose your information only in accordance with the professional services we provide as set out in this Policy. During the process of providing our services and depending on the products or services being provided or the reason for your interaction with InterCheck Australia we may share information about you with third parties, such as:

* Third party suppliers including but not limited to providers of criminal checks, law enforcement agencies, regulatory and licensing bodies, credit agencies, public registries, court or tribunal records, education providers or professional organisations
* Current employers or previous employers, for example, to confirm your employment
* Partner organisations
* Government agencies and law enforcement agencies or regulators
* Businesses who do some of our work for us – including direct marketing and IT support
* Auditors

13.   
    13. Do we share the result of your background checks with 3rd parties?

* Where you have provided consent, in connection with a background screen ordered by one of InterCheck Australia’s business clients, InterCheck Australia will share your background check result with that client.
* If InterCheck Australia provides you with the option of sharing the results of the services you have obtained with one or more organisations, and you choose to share those results, InterCheck Australia will share the results with those organisations (but will not share any underlying information provided to InterCheck Australia to obtain the results).
* We may disclose personal information to a third party who has been provided with your background check results, including a Police Check result, to allow that third party to verify that result, through a verification functionality or feature. Where you have consented to us forwarding your Background Check results including a Police Check result, to a third party you also consent to us making that information available to that third party via a verification functionality or feature.
* When you disclose personal information to a third party by giving them a copy of your Background Check result or Police Check result (either in electronic or hard copy) you also consent to us also disclosing your personal information to that third party through a verification functionality or feature.
* You acknowledge and agree that such disclosure through a verification functionality or feature is appropriate and necessary to maintain security and integrity of the personal information contained in any of your background check or police checks results.

14.   
    14. How do we store and protect your personal information?

InterCheck Australia is committed to protecting and securing your personal information. We take reasonable precautions to ensure that all your personal information that we hold is safeguarded and protected from misuse, loss, unauthorised use, modification or disclosure, through the implementation of technical, physical and administrative information security safeguards as prescribed in our Enterprise Information Security Policy.

The confidentiality and integrity of personal information is protected by:

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| Secure storage | Your information is stored using enterprise-grade cloud hosting services secure with AES-256 encryption in the AWS data center located in Sydney. |
| Staff Training | InterCheck Australia embeds privacy and security into our culture. We train our staff in how to keep your information safe and secure by driving awareness and procedure compliance into our business activities. |
| System Security | Restricting access to our internal systems using technical access controls on a need-to-know basis. Firewalls restrict access to internal system components to a whitelist of trusted IPs. Running antivirus and anti- malware scanners with up-to-date threat signatures.Regular patching of servers and workstations running current operating systems and modern browsers. |
| Building and Physical Security | We control access to sensitive areas, management of physical and electronic documents, and secure document disposal. Physical security measures are in place preventing unauthorised access to our premises; |
| Transactional Security | We enforce secure socket layer (SSL) connections for every page of our website and our application. The use of SSL means that data traffic between your computer and our site is encrypted and protected at all times |
| Audit and Testing | InterCheck Australia employs independent, industry certified, security experts with the experience and track record to support our security aims. |
| Destroying or de-identifying data when no longer required | We will store the information associated with your account for the time period required to comply with applicable record keeping laws. For example, in the case of Police Checks we are obliged to retain information used to submit your request for at least 12 months, and to delete the check result itself within 12 months.Otherwise, we will keep the information until such time as you delete your account. When we no longer need information, we take reasonable steps to destroy or de- identify it. |

15.   
    15. Transfer of personal information overseas

For the purpose of conducting an Australian Nationally Coordinated Criminal History Check, InterCheck Australia will not transfer or store any data related to this service overseas without your consent and the consent of the ACIC.

For other types of background checks within our product range and in the course of carrying out these services, we may need to transfer personal information overseas in order to liaise with information providers, potential or past employer’s and/or our offshore related entities. We will transfer personal information overseas only if:

* the candidate has consented to the transfer,
* the transfer is necessary for us to provide the client with their requested service,
* it is not practical to obtain a candidate’s consent, the transfer is for the candidate’s benefit and the candidate’s consent would likely be given; or
* we have taken reasonable steps to ensure that a candidate’s personal information will not be held, used, or disclosed by the recipient in a manner inconsistent with this Policy and the Privacy Act.

16.   
    16. Transaction information

We do not store any card information directly. ANZ Bank Australia captures all card information on our behalf and in accordance with their own data security policies.

17.   
    17. Minors and children’s privacy

We will generally seek parent or guardian consent to collect the personal information of children under 16. However, if we are legally obliged to provide the product to a person aged under 16 without such consent then we may not obtain consent in those circumstances. For some products provided by InterCheck Australia we are required to obtain parental or guardian consent for persons aged under 18 years of age, for example, Australian criminal history checks. Consent of parents or guardians will need to be obtained in those circumstances.

18.   
    18. How can you access your personal information and correct it if it is wrong?

You have a right to request access to your personal information which we hold about you at any time. You can make such a request by contacting the InterCheck Australia Privacy Officer or the InterCheck Australia support team using the contact details set out in this Policy. We will always confirm your identity before giving access to your personal information. InterCheck Australia will provide this personal information free of charge to the candidate unless there is an exceptional subject under relevant Privacy Laws.

If candidates are able to establish that the information InterCheck Australia holds about them is not accurate, complete or up to date, the candidate can then request us to correct the information. We will then take reasonable steps to correct this information or if necessary, discuss alternative actions with the candidate.

Candidates may request access to their personal information that InterCheck Australia holds about them by contacting our support team on (03) 8820 4069 or via email help@intercheck.com.au, where we manage all queries, disputes and complaints.

19.   
    19. Disputing Your Criminal History Check Results (issued by ACIC)

If you believe that the result returned on your Police Check is incorrect, then you do have a right to dispute the result. To Dispute your result, you can contact InterCheck Australia directly on the number or email below, and we will advise you of all information and supporting evidence you need to provide us, in order for InterCheck Australia to lodge the ACIC’s Nationally coordinated criminal history check Dispute Form (dispute form) to the ACIC.

The Police will then investigate the dispute including reviewing all information and supporting evidence and provide the outcome to you (either being successful or unsuccessful).

For more information on the dispute process, see our dispute help page. If you have further questions, please contact us at [help@intercheck.com.au](mailto:help@intercheck.com.au) or call us on (03) 8820 4069 for assistance.

20.   
    20. Addressing privacy concerns or complaints

At InterCheck we value our customers. We will always aim to be fair and responsive. If you have a complaint you have the right to expect that we will handle it in a friendly and professional way. Customers have the right to express concerns about the way we handle their personal information and we strive to address such concerns in a professional and timely manner. Customers having queries about our privacy practices, this Policy or having a complaint about our service can contact our Privacy Officer to resolve their complaints.

When we receive a complaint, we look on it as valuable feedback that may help us to improve the services we offer and to ensure your needs are met in a satisfactory and appropriate manner.

Customers can send their privacy queries or complaints to:

**The Privacy Officer InterCheck Australia**

**PO Box 213, Flinders Lane Vic 8009**

Our Privacy Officer can also be contacted on: Email: [help@intercheck.com.au](mailto:help@intercheck.com.au)

Phone: (03) 8820 4069

We will make all efforts possible to investigate your complaint and advise you of the outcome as soon as possible. If the matter is not resolved to your satisfaction you can then refer your complaint to the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner who can be contacted through the following website: [https://www.oaic.gov.au/privacy/privacy-](https://www.oaic.gov.au/privacy/privacy-complaints/) [complaints/](https://www.oaic.gov.au/privacy/privacy-complaints/)

21.   
    21. Changes to our Privacy Policy

This Policy may be amended, depending if our business operations change or if any Privacy Laws are changed. If this is the case, then an updated version will replace and will supersede this Privacy Statement and will be available on our web site for viewing.

22.   
    22. Visiting our website

InterCheck Australia’s web sites including [www.intercheck.com.au,](http://www.intercheck.com.au/) like most other commercial web sites, may collect information from your visit. This information is used to administer and improve our websites only. We do not identify you personally. We may collect the following information from your visit by use of cookies. Cookies are small data files that are downloaded from our web servers and stored on your hard drive. A cookie does not identify individuals personally, but it does identify computers. Most browsers can be configured to refuse to accept cookies. You can also delete cookies from your hard drive. However, doing so may hinder the URL of and webpage from which you accessed our site (“the referrer”).

23.   
    23. Additional information and applicable legislation

This privacy policy is applicable with Australian Crime Commission Act 2002.

If you require additional information about privacy please visit the following site: [www.privacy.gov.au/](http://www.privacy.gov.au/)

Service Agreement
-----------------

### Version 4.2

##### Effective November 22nd 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**SERVICE TERMS**

These service terms (“**Terms**”) contain the terms and conditions that govern your access to and use of the background check platform and portals offered by Certn (the “**Platform**”) and is an agreement between Certn and you, or the entity you are authorized to represent (“**You**” or “**Your**”). These Terms take effect when You sign an order form, if applicable (“**Order** **Form**”), click the “Continue” button or checkbox presented with these terms or, if earlier, when You use any of Certn’s service offerings (the “**Effective** **Date**”). You represent to Certn that You are lawfully able to enter into these Terms.

If You are entering into these Terms and creating an Account on behalf of an entity, such as the company You work for, You represent to Certn that You have legal authority to bind that entity. If You do not have such authority, or if You do not agree with these Terms, You must not click “Continue” and You may not use Certn’s service offerings. If You are entering into these Terms and creating the Account for an End User, You as the Initial User, represent to Certn that You have legal authority to bind the End User. The End User will be liable for the actions of the Initial User and any Additional User. For avoidance of doubt, if the End User has signed an Order Form, or a separate master services agreement with Certn (“**MSA**”), these Terms will be subject to any terms agreed to within such document.

Certn may revise these Terms at any time without notice to You. The revised Terms will be effective when posted to the applicable website owned by Certn, including certn.co (“**Website**(**s**)”). Notwithstanding the foregoing, Certn will provide notice of any revisions that may impact or restrict Your use of the Website and/or Services.

1. **DEFINITIONS.**
    1. “**Account**” means the End User’s account with Certn associated with the Initial User’s email address, and any Additional User’s email address, subject to validation by Certn.“Additional Users” means any affiliates, or subsidiaries of the Initial User or the End User who Certn has credentialed and approved in writing to access the Platform in accordance with these Terms.
    2. “**API**” means the application programming interface(s) including (i) invite flow; or (ii) quickscreen flow used to provide access to the Platform.
    3. “**Certn**” means Certn Holdings Inc. and its subsidiaries and affiliates, including without limitation Certn (Canada) Inc., Certn (USA) Inc., Certn (UK) Ltd., and InterCheck Global Pty Ltd..
    4. “**Certn** **Forms**” means any standard consent, disclosure, authorization, adverse action and notification forms made available by Certn for Your review upon request.
    5. “**Consumer**” means an individual applicant who is subject to the Services in support of their application for employment or engagement as an independent contractor by You, or for any other Permissible Purpose authorized by Certn during the credentialing process.
    6. “**Credit** **Bureau**” means as applicable TransUnion International UK Ltd., Equifax Canada Co, Equifax Information Services LLC or Equifax Workforce Solutions LLC, a provider of Equifax Verification Services or another approved credit bureau.
    7. “**Employment** **Purposes**” means the specific Permissible Purpose of a Report concerning the evaluation of individuals for employment, promotion, reassignment or retention as an employee or independent contractor.
    8. “**End** **User**” means the corporate entity making use of the Report in accordance with consumer reporting legislation, including the Fair Credit Reporting Act, 15 U.S.C. § 1681 et seq (“FCRA”).
    9. “**Initial** **User**” means the initial representative of the End User with the full corporate power and authority to bind the End User of an account.
    10. “**Permissible** **Purpose**” means for (i) Employment Purposes, where the Consumer has given prior written permission; (ii) any other permissible purpose under the law (including Section 8 of the Consumer Reporting Act (Ontario) and Section 604(a) of the FCRA, as applicable); or (iii) in accordance with the GDPR, where the End User has determined the lawful basis for processing personal data (if End User is the controller) or obtained confirmation from the controller that the lawful basis has been determined (if End User requests the Services on behalf of the controller) as applicable; as declared by the End User prior to ordering.
    11. “**Report**” means a consumer report or other applicable screening product offered on the Platform, including reports containing credit information and Investigative Consumer Reports (if applicable), as defined under Section 603(d) of the FCRA.
    12. “**Services**” means verification and background screening services including the delivery and management of Reports and related documentation, and obtaining status information regarding the collection of such information.
    13. “**User**” means You, the Initial User, the End User and Additional Users, as applicable.
2. **SERVICES.**
    1. The Services are provided in accordance with the descriptions available to you within the Platform, API documents, or as set out in Your Order form, as applicable. It is Your responsibility to read and review the Service descriptions prior to ordering a Report.
    2. You agree to use the Reports and Platform in compliance with applicable laws, rules and regulations, whether federal, provincial, state, local or international, including but not limited to consumer reporting and data protection legislation (“**Laws**”).
3. **INTERNATIONAL DATA PROCESSING TERMS.**  
      
    The parties agree to abide by those terms and conditions set out in the [Data Processing Addendum](https://vault.pactsafe.io/s/5d800911-f26c-4e3a-884d-85117a81799b/legal.html?g=37964&contract-ryclhyapj) [(](https://docs.google.com/document/d/1B-0ULFJiOsb8M0ZEIXes9ImOgKuM4LlV/edit)the “DPA”) and any applicable data protection legislation with respect to the handling of Personal Information (as defined in the DPA), including any information, data and other content, in any form, provided, entered or uploaded to the Platform in connection with the Services.
4. **CERTIFICATIONS.**
    1. By entering into these Terms and/or creating an Account, and each time You request or access a Report, You are certifying that You, being the End User or a User acting as an agent of the End User, have direct knowledge of the facts and You certify and agree that:
        1. You have a legitimate need and Permissible Purpose for ordering Reports and utilizing the Services;
        2. if the Report is applicable to a United States resident, such purpose is consistent with Section 604(a) of the FCRA and any comparable state specific purpose requirements;
        3. to the extent the Services are subject to the application of UK GDPR or EU GDPR or the Report is applicable to individuals residing in the United Kingdom or the European Union, that You have an explicit lawful basis aligned with the Permissible Purpose to enable the lawful processing of Personal Information, in accordance with the applicable data protection Laws;
        4. that You will only request and use the Reports for the Permissible Purpose;;
        5. that You are acting in compliance with any additional provincial, state or local requirements for requesting, obtaining and using the Reports (including credit or criminal information, if applicable); and
        6. that the Consumer may have the right under applicable regulations to a copy of their Report, as such, if a request is made directly to You, You agree to provide a copy of the Report to the Consumer or to immediately pass on the request to Certn to provide a copy of the Report to the Consumer on Your behalf.
    2. To the extent You are requesting Reports within the United States or the Consumer is a resident of the United States:
        1. You acknowledge the receipt of and certify that You have reviewed and fully understand the following statutory notices:[](https://files.consumerfinance.gov/f/201504_cfpb_summary_your-rights-under-fcra.pdf)
            * [A Summary of Your Rights Under the FCRA](https://files.consumerfinance.gov/f/201504_cfpb_summary_your-rights-under-fcra.pdf);[](https://files.consumerfinance.gov/f/201410_cfpb_summary_remedying-the-effects-of-id-theft-fcra.pdf)[](https://files.consumerfinance.gov/f/201410_cfpb_summary_remedying-the-effects-of-id-theft-fcra.pdf)
            * [Remedying the Effects of Identity Theft](https://files.consumerfinance.gov/f/201410_cfpb_summary_remedying-the-effects-of-id-theft-fcra.pdf); and[](https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/CFR-2012-title12-vol8/pdf/CFR-2012-title12-vol8-part1022-appN.pdf)[](https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/CFR-2012-title12-vol8/pdf/CFR-2012-title12-vol8-part1022-appN.pdf)
            * [Notice to Users of Consumer Reports – Obligations of Users Under the FCRA](https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/CFR-2012-title12-vol8/pdf/CFR-2012-title12-vol8-part1022-appN.pdf).
        2. If you are using a quickscreen API or Certn is not collecting consents or providing disclosures to Consumers through the Platform on Your behalf, You agree and certify that prior to procurement or causing the procurement of a Report for a Permissible Purpose: (i) a clear and conspicuous disclosure will be made in writing to the Consumer in a document that satisfies all of the requirements of the FCRA as well as any applicable state or local Laws, (ii) the Consumer has authorized in writing the procurement of the Report by End User, including providing of all necessary consents required under applicable privacy and data protection Laws; and (iii), You shall clearly and accurately disclose to the Consumer that an Investigative Consumer Report may include information as to the Consumer’s character, general reputation, personal characteristics and/or mode of living.
        3. Before taking any adverse action based in whole or in part on a Report, You must adhere to certain obligations and if Certn is providing End User with access to an adverse action tool, End User confirms that it has reviewed and utilized the appropriate adverse action/letters based on the Consumer’s residence and place of work in accordance with the adverse action requirements, You also agree to the following:
            1. Prior to issuing pre-adverse or adverse action letters, the End User shall seek the advice of independent legal counsel to ensure compliance with applicable Laws and regulations. Certn expressly disclaims any liability for reliance on the information contained in this section.
            2. End User will not initiate the pre-adverse and adverse action notice process until: (i) Certn has completed all search components of the Report and/or Investigative Consumer Report, (ii) Certn has provided the complete Report and/or Investigative Consumer Report to End User, and (iii) End User has reviewed the contents of the Report and/or Investigative Consumer Report.
            3. At a minimum, if using a Report for Employment Purposes, before taking any adverse action based in whole or in part on the Report, You must provide to the Consumer to whom the Report relates: (a) a pre-adverse action notice/letter stating that End User is considering taking adverse action; (b) a copy of the full and complete Report including Certn’s contact information; (c) a copy of the notice titled “A Summary of Your Rights Under the Fair Credit Reporting Act” and any applicable state summary of rights; and (d) a reasonable opportunity of time to correct any erroneous information contained in the Report.
            4. If You thereafter take any adverse action with respect to an employment decision, or the Consumer is denied tenancy or any other adverse action is taken as related to any other permissible purpose described in Section 604(a) of the FCRA, You must provide a final adverse action notice to the Consumer to whom the Report relates in compliance with the FCRA and any applicable state Laws.
            5. You acknowledge that, before taking adverse action based on a criminal record, the [EEOC Criminal History Guidance](https://www.eeoc.gov/laws/guidance/enforcement-guidance-consideration-arrest-and-conviction-records-employment-decisions) recommends that You perform an individualized assessment and/or other considerations.
            6. If You are taking adverse action in California, You shall comply with California Civil Code Sections 1785.20 and 1786.40 and provide Consumer with a written notice of his/her rights under the ICRA and the CCRAA, as defined below.
        4. You certify and understand that the End User (or You as an agent of the End User) are responsible for complying with federal, provincial, state and/or local regulatory requirements, restrictions and Laws, including but not limited to, data protection legislation, the FCRA, individualized assessments, as instructed by the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, local Ban the Box laws, fair chance and fair hiring laws, HUD guidelines, and fair chance to housing laws.
    3. Additional certifications. You certify and agree:
        1. Not to use or attempt to use the Platform for unauthorized purposes or for the benefit of any unauthorized third party.
        2. To use each Report on a one-time use basis and within a reasonable period of time.
        3. To hold the Reports in strict confidence and not disclose the Reports in a manner inconsistent with applicable data protection Laws.
        4. To the extent Certn is not collecting consents, authorization and disclosures on the End User’s behalf, that the End User shall collect and retain copies of all written authorizations and disclosures for a period of three (3) years and make such documentation available to Certn upon request.
        5. That Certn may review End User records that are reasonably required to demonstrate compliance with these Terms at any time upon reasonable prior notice during the Term, and for three (3) years thereafter.
5. **JURISDICTION SPECIFIC REQUIREMENTS.**
    1. **United States (Federal)**: YOU ACKNOWLEDGE THAT THE FCRA PROVIDES THAT ANY PERSON WHO KNOWINGLY AND WILLFULLY OBTAINS INFORMATION ON A CONSUMER FROM A CONSUMER REPORTING AGENCY UNDER FALSE PRETENSES SHALL BE FINED UNDER TITLE 18 OF THE UNITED STATES CODE OR IMPRISONED NOT MORE THAN TWO YEARS, OR BOTH.
    2. **California**: You confirm You have read and understand your obligations under the Investigative Consumer Reporting Agencies Act (“ICRAA”), California Civil Code Sections 1786 et seq., and the Consumer Credit Reporting Agencies Act (“CCRAA”), California Civil Code Sections 1785.1 et seq., when ordering a Report in California. Further, if applicable, You will request and use Reports solely for permissible purpose(s) identified under California Civil Code Sections 1785.11 and 1786.12.
    3. **Vermont**: You confirm You have read and understand the consumer reporting restrictions set out in [Section 2480e](https://legislature.vermont.gov/statutes/section/09/063/02480e) when ordering any Reports in Vermont.
    4. **New York City, New York**: You, as the End User, or as an agent acting on behalf of the End User, shall comply with all applicable requirements under New York City Humans Rights Law (“NYCHRL”). You make the following certifications with respect to NYCHRL: (A) End User shall not obtain or evaluate criminal history information about an applicant or employee until after a conditional offer of employment, promotion, or transfer has been extended to him or her; (B) End User shall not inquire about or consider criminal history that is prohibited from being considered under NYCHRL; (C) End User shall engage in any required individualized assessment process before taking adverse action against a Consumer; and (D) End User shall follow all legally-required pre- and post-adverse action procedures including, but not limited to, ensuring all pre- and post-adverse action communications include all information required under the law and are sent at the appropriate times. Notwithstanding any limitations of liability set out in these Terms, You shall indemnify and hold harmless Certn, its affiliates, and subsidiaries and their respective officers, directors, employees, agents, and insurers from and against any and all damages, penalties, losses, liabilities, judgments, settlements, awards, costs, and expenses (including reasonable attorneys’ fees and expenses) arising out of or in connection with any third- party claims, assertions, demands, causes of action, suits, proceedings or other actions, whether at law or in equity, related in any manner to End User’s failure to comply with NYCHRL.
6. **SERVICE SPECIFIC CERTIFICATIONS.**
    1. **USA MVR**: If You request MVRs and/or driving records, You certify and agree that You will do so in strict compliance with the US Driver’s Privacy Protection Act (“DPPA”, at 18 U.S.C. § 2721 et seq.) and any applicable state laws, specifically, You will use this information only in the normal course of business (i) to obtain lawful information relating to the holder of a commercial driver’s license, or (ii) to verify information provided by the Consumer.
    2. **USA SSN Trace**: If Reports include Social Security Number Trace (“SSN Trace”), You agree not to use SSN Trace results in any way, directly or indirectly, for Employment Purposes. Further, You agree that You will not use SSN Trace information in any way that would violate the privacy obligations or any other terms and provisions of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (15 U.S.C 6801 et seq.) or the DPPA (18.U.S.C. Section 2721 et seq.) or any other similar U.S. state or local statute, rule or regulation.
    3. **USA Criminal**: Certn offers county courthouse, federal, and multi-state/nationwide database level searches, to be ordered at Your discretion. You agree and acknowledge that Certn is not liable for any records that exist within unsearched databases. Certn only reports pending court matters and conviction records and will report a minimum of seven (7) years of conviction information, where allowed by any applicable fair credit reporting laws, unless End User provides additional reporting instructions in a separate document executed by the End User and the Consumer. End User assumes full responsibility for determining whether reported information may be used in the jurisdiction where the Consumer lives, works, or is applying for work, as applicable.
    4. **UK Criminal:** If You request criminal record results on a Consumer resident in the United Kingdom, You agree to fully comply with the sections of the codes related to employers or clients of umbrella bodies of the Disclosure & Barring Service (“DBS”), Disclosure Scotland (“DS”) and/or AccessNI (“ANI”), or relevant processing standards (each a “Code”), and specifically to: (i) ensure Consumers are aware of and receive a copy of the applicable Code at the start of the recruitment process; (ii) implement a written policy specifying the process and criteria used by the End User for employment, recruitment and/or hiring decisions regarding Consumers with criminal record history; (iii) notify Certn of who within Your organization is entitled to receive disclosure information and promptly notify Certn of any changes thereto; and (iv) unless the Background Check can be processed with a Digital ID Verification Check by Certn on Your behalf and You requested this, You shall comply with the process of ensuring the true identity of the Consumer in accordance with the relevant guidelines issues by DBS, DS or ANI from time to time.
    5. **UK Cifas:** If You request a Cifas Check in the Cifas Databases (as defined in the Cifas Insider Threat Database Handbook), You (i) warrant that You are a member of Cifas and that You shall not continue to request these checks if for any reason You are no longer a Cifas member; (ii) acknowledge that Certn is a Vetting Specialist (as defined in the Cifas Insider Threat Database Handbook) and You are a full filing member, and as such the majority of the responsibilities, requirements and actions set out in the Cifas Insider Threat Database Handbook will be borne by You and not Certn. For the avoidance of doubt, Certn will be searching the database and providing Data (as defined in the Cifas Insider Threat Database Handbook) to You, and where a Match exists (as defined in the Cifas Insider Threat Database Handbook) You must investigate that Match and if appropriate make a filing in accordance with Principle 1: Reciprocity of the Cifas Insider Threat Database Handbook; (iii) hereby irrevocably You shall indemnify and agree to hold Certn (including its affiliates) harmless (hereinafter Indemnity) against: (A) any and all claims or actions, damages, expenses and legal costs, which Certn (including its affiliates) may suffer or incur in connection with or arising from Your failure to comply with the terms of this section; (B) any and all claims for compensation and legal costs, which Certn (including its affiliates) may suffer or incur as a result of any contravention by You of any of the requirements of the Data Protection Legislation or any applicable Laws, who alleges to have suffered damage or distress with or arising from Your use of the Cifas Insider Threat Database Handbook; (C) any and all claims, actions, damages, loss, expenses and legal costs (on a full indemnity basis) which Certn (including its affiliates) may suffer or incur in connection with, or arising from, any claim that You have breached the Cifas Insider Threat Database Handbook, or have contravened or failed to comply with any Laws (including, but not limited to, any statute, statutory instrument or the Common Law) whether or not You have complied with the Cifas Insider Threat Database Handbook; and (iv) this Indemnity is in addition, and without prejudice, to any other indemnity executed by You pursuant to the Cifas Insider Threat Database Handbook or these Terms and does not limit the force or effect of any such other indemnity in any way.
    6. **UK Digital ID Verification:** When using a certified identity service provider (“IDSP”) to carry out identity checks utilizing Identification Document Validation Technology (“IDVT”) for criminal record checks or right to work checks in the UK, You must be satisfied that the photo and the biographic details recorded are consistent with the person presenting themselves for work. This is part of the process to establish a statutory excuse against a civil penalty if the individual is later found to be working illegally. You must retain a clear copy of the Digital ID Verification output for the duration of employment and for two (2) years after the employment has ended. Certn (A) shall verify each Consumer’s identity via IDVT’s Medium Level of Confidence (as defined by United Kingdom government’s guide for IDVT, as amended from time to time); and (B) agrees that the provision of the Digital ID Verification services shall be dependent on Certn and/or its subcontractor’s status as a certified IDSP.
    7. **Credit Reports and Information**: If You request Credit Information, you agree to comply with all applicable state, provincial and federal requirements. Specifically, You understand and agree that:
        1. **Validation Process:** Prior to ordering any information provided by a Credit Bureau (“Credit Information”) from Certn, the Credit Bureau may require that the End User pass an on-site, virtual inspection of its business premises.
        2. **Additional Credit Certifications**. If Credit Information is requested:
            1. Certn may, at the request of the Credit Bureau, conduct periodic audits of End User’s compliance with these Terms, specifically the access to and treatment of Credit Information. Any failure to cooperate in a reasonable audit fully and promptly constitutes grounds for immediate suspension of service or termination of these Terms.
            2. End User shall indemnify and hold harmless Certn and the Credit Bureau from any and all liabilities of whatever kind or nature that may arise from or relate to (i) the termination of access to Credit Information based on any findings of an audit requested by Credit Bureau; (ii) the dissemination or disclosure of Credit Information by End User, its employees, or agents, in contravention of the conditions set forth in the Terms or applicable Laws; or (iii) End User’s wilful misconduct, fraud, gross negligence or violation of the Terms, notwithstanding any limitations of liability set out elsewhere in the Terms.
            3. End User shall secure all hard and electronic copies of Credit Information within its offices and facilities, if applicable, so that unauthorized persons cannot easily access it;
            4. End User shall shred or destroy all hard copies of Credit Information and delete or render unreadable any electronic files containing Credit Information, after it is no longer needed and when laws permit destruction;
            5. End User shall secure all devices used to access Credit Information in a physically secure location, accessible only to Users, and implement reasonable security measures when the devices are not in use;
            6. End User shall cooperate fully with Credit Bureau in the event of a breach involving End User’s access to Credit Information through the Platform.
            7. If End User is a landlord or property management firm, End User attests that if it is requesting Credit Information for pre-rental inquiry purposes, it has received a completed rental application from the Applicant that includes information required to reasonably identify the Applicant and the End User has duly reviewed the information.
        3. **Restricted Categories**: The End User certifies that it is not a(n): private detective, private detective agency, private investigative company, bail bondsman, attorney, law firm, credit counseling firm, financial counseling firm, credit repair clinic, pawn shop, check cashing company, genealogical or heir research firm, dating service, massage or tattoo service, businesses operating within apartments or unrestricted residential locations, individual seeking information for personal use, adult entertainment service of any kind, company locating missing children, third-party repossession company, company that charges advance fees for debt or mortgage assistance relief (excluding refinancing of a dwelling loan or services offered by attorneys), company issuing, selling, or operating through subscriptions (e.g., magazines, book clubs, record clubs), company or individual involved in spiritual counseling, or any entity that is not an end user or decision maker, unless approved in writing by Equifax. For clarity, if the End User is resident in the United Kingdom and the credit check is performed on current or former British residents, this provision does not apply.
        4. **Credit Bureau Discretion**: The Credit Bureau reserves the right, at its sole discretion, to deny access to Credit Information to certain Users, even if they meet the qualifications set forth herein.
        5. **US Credit Scores**: If End User is using a US credit score, End User certifies that it will comply with the Dodd-Frank Act and all applicable regulations relating to using a credit score.
        6. **UK Credit:** Certn and the Credit Bureau will have the right to enforce the terms and conditions referred to herein in accordance with the United Kingdom Contracts (Rights of Third Parties) Act 1999.
        7. **Exclusive Use and Confidentiality:** Any Credit Information shall be maintained with the utmost confidentiality, except when disclosure to others is authorized by the Consumer or permitted by applicable Laws. Users are strictly prohibited from obtaining Credit Information on themselves, associates, or any other individuals except in the course of their official duties and in connection with the Permissible Purpose. End User shall not under any circumstance sell, transfer, distribute or otherwise make any Credit Information provided to a User, available to, or use the Credit Information on behalf of, any other third party.
        8. **Disclaimer of Accuracy and Liability Release**: Neither Certn nor the Credit Bureau make warranties or representations as to the suitability of the Credit Information for any particular purpose. End User acknowledges that End User is responsible for satisfying itself that the Credit Information is suitable for any use. End User acknowledges that data collected for the purpose of reporting Credit Information is obtained through potentially fallible sources and understands that accuracy is not guaranteed by Credit Bureau. End User releases Credit Bureau and its affiliated companies, agents, employees, and independent contractors from any liability, even in cases of negligence, arising from Credit Bureau, and from any losses or expenses incurred by End User, directly or indirectly, due to reliance on Credit Information.
7. **SECURITY.**
    1. End User shall maintain an information security program that contains administrative, technical, and physical safeguards appropriate to the End User’s size and complexity and the nature and scope of its activities, and such safeguards shall be reasonably designed to (i) ensure the security and confidentiality of the information provided by Certn, (ii) protect against any anticipated threats or hazards to the security or integrity of such information, and (iii) protect against unauthorized access, use, disclosure, modification, destruction or any other interference of such information that could result in substantial harm or inconvenience to any Consumer.
    2. In addition to the foregoing, End User will maintain a privacy or human resources policy that is clearly and accurately disclosed to Consumers and complies with applicable Laws and will maintain strict procedures to ensure that personnel are not able to use the Reports or personal information related thereto for improper, illegal or unauthorized purposes.
    3. You agree not to: (i) copy, distribute, rent, lease, lend, sublicense or transfer the Platform, or make the Platform available to any third party, including Your affiliates, parents or subsidiaries without Certn’s express prior written consent, (ii) modify, decompile, reverse engineer, or disassemble the Platform or otherwise attempt to discover any underlying source code, ideas, algorithms, file formats or programming interfaces, (iii) create derivative works based on the Platform; (iv) modify, remove, or obscure any copyright, trademark, patent or other notices or legends that appear on the Platform; (v) use the Platform to develop a competitive product offering; (vi) use any agents, robots, scripts, spiders, or other automated means to access or manage the Platform; or (vii) allow Your personnel to access the Platform or request Reports for improper, illegal or unauthorized purposes, including on themselves, associates, or any other person except in the exercise of their official duties.
    4. Certn will make API keys available to You to access the Platform, if applicable. You are responsible for securing Your API keys, and You agree not to publish or share them with any unauthorized persons, including Your service providers, except as approved by Certn in writing. You will contact [security@certn.co](mailto:security@certn.co) immediately if You become aware of any unauthorized use of Your API keys.
8. **CONFIDENTIAL INFORMATION.**
    1. Each party will keep confidential, all information and materials provided or made available, directly or indirectly, by the other party that is marked as confidential or proprietary, or is identified as confidential or proprietary at the time of disclosure, or the nature of the information and the manner of disclosure are such that a reasonable person would understand it to be confidential (collectively, “**Confidential** **Information**”). Certn’s Confidential Information includes but is not limited to, the features, functionality and content of the Platform and any planned modifications or updates thereto, Fees and pricing information.
    2. Each party will maintain all Confidential Information in strict confidence by using at least the same level of care that it uses for its own confidential information, but in no case less than a prudent and reasonable standard of care. Each party may use Confidential Information solely for the purposes of performing its obligations or exercising its rights hereunder. Information that either party can establish: (a) was lawfully in a party’s possession before receipt from the other party; or (b) is or becomes a matter of public knowledge through no fault of the receiving party; or (c) was independently developed or discovered by a party without the benefit of any Confidential Information of the other party, shall not be considered Confidential Information under these Terms. Each party may disclose Confidential Information solely to its employees and representatives that have a need to know to accomplish the purposes of these Terms and each of whom are bound to protect the Confidential Information from unauthorized use and disclosure under the terms of a written agreement with terms as protective of the Confidential Information as those set forth in these Terms. Each party may also disclose Confidential Information in response to a valid order of a court or other governmental body or as otherwise required by law to be disclosed; provided that, the responding party gives sufficient notice to the disclosing party to enable the disclosing party to take protective measures, and/or in any event only disclose the exact Confidential Information, or portion thereof, specifically requested.
    3. Each party agrees that any violation of these confidentiality provisions will cause irreparable injury to the other party entitling the other party to injunctive relief or other equitable relief, in addition to, and not in lieu of, any other remedies such party may be entitled to. The disclosure of Confidential Information will be governed by these Terms, which supersedes any previous confidentiality or nondisclosure agreement executed by or on behalf of the parties. Any such Confidential Information will be treated as if it were disclosed under these Terms as of the date of such exchange.
9. **FEES.**
    1. You shall pay Certn for each Service requested at the rate set forth in the Platform, Your MSA or Order Form, as applicable (the “**Fees**”) plus any additional variable pass through costs and fees that may be imposed by governmental entities or third parties for the Services that You request, including, but not limited to, verification fees, court fees, county processing fees, multi-state fees, and international fees, and taxes clearly set out in Your invoice. You are responsible for each Service You request, including Reports resulting in a return of “clear,” “unable to verify,” or other similar result, and/or from user error in inputting data, duplicate entries, and/or cancellations by You or Consumer. Unless otherwise stated in your MSA or Order Form, payment of any accrued Fees shall be due within thirty (30) days of Your receipt of an invoice. The foregoing sentence will not apply to those Services paid for by credit card at the time of ordering.
    2. Certn reserves the right to adjust the Fees annually, which will be communicated to you with at least thirty (30) days' notice.
    3. Notwithstanding 9(b), in the event any government or regulatory authority increases its fees for any Services provided, Certn may adjust the Fees accordingly to fully pass through such increased costs to You. You will be notified of any such Fee adjustments at least thirty (30) days in advance.
10. **WITHHOLDING TAXES.**  
      
    Certn may withhold any taxes on Your behalf as required by You in accordance with applicable Laws. You shall solely bear the responsibility to acknowledge all relevant tax laws, regulations, and requirements applicable in your jurisdiction about such withholdings and shall inform Certn of the specific amount to be withheld and any other similar requirement. You agree to provide Certn timely and accurate information regarding any changes in tax laws or obligations that may affect the withholding process. Certn shall not be liable for any penalties, fines, or other liabilities arising from Your failure to acknowledge and/or inform Certn of applicable tax laws or any taxes related to this agreement.
11. **ACCESS TO CONSENTS.**  
      
    You acknowledge and agree that to maintain compliance with legal, regulatory, and contractual obligations, Certn reserves the right to conduct audits at its discretion to verify that consents, authorizations, and disclosures have been presented and obtained by You when accessing the Services via API, and that such consents are in full compliance with applicable laws and regulations. These audits may be conducted by Certn or a third-party auditor appointed by Certn, and you agree to cooperate fully with any such audits, providing access to all relevant records and documentation upon request.
12. **USAGE DATA.**  
      
    Certn owns all right, title and interest in and to all data collected by Certn related to the operation of the Platform and Your use thereof (“**Usage Data**”). Usage Data may include Platform performance metrics and analytics, but does not include any personal information or public records. Certn will not disclose Usage Data to any third party in a manner that identifies You without Your consent other than (i) to third party service providers who use it for the sole benefit of Certn or as required to provide You the Platform; or (ii) as may be required by law or legal process.
13. **INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY.**
    1. Certn owns, or has exclusive rights to, all title, interest, and proprietary rights relating to patents, copyrights, trademarks, trade secrets, know-how, mask works, moral rights, and all similar rights that may exist now or later in any jurisdiction, including without limitation any applications and registrations for the foregoing (“**Intellectual** **Property** **Rights**”) in and to the Platform and any software, technology, materials and information related to the Platform, whether currently existing or later developed.
    2. You own all right, title, interest, and Intellectual Property Rights, in and to the Reports and any software application owned or controlled by You (excluding any APIs or Certn trademarks incorporated therein).
    3. If You provide any feedback to Certn, You agree to assign all right, title and interest in and to such feedback to Certn and agree that Certn may freely use and exploit such feedback without compensation to You.
14. **INDEMNIFICATION.**
    1. You agree to defend and indemnify and hold harmless Certn, and its directors, officers and employees from and against any third party liabilities, damages, losses, judgments, costs, expenses (including reasonable attorneys’ fees), claims, actions, demands and suits (collectively “**Certn Claims**”) arising out of or relating to: (a) Your breach of any certifications, (b) any decision or action by You to provide a copy of the Report to a third party in violation of these Terms, or (c) fraudulent or malicious conduct by the End User or the End User’s employees.
    2. Certn agrees to defend and indemnify End User, and its directors, officers and employees from and against any third party liabilities, damages, losses, judgments, costs, expenses (including reasonable attorneys’ fees), claims, actions, demands and suits (collectively “**End User Claims**”) arising out of or relating to: (a) the infringement or violation of intellectual property rights, including but not limited to patents, trademarks, trade secrets, and copyrights, arising from the use of the Platform or Services, or (b) fraudulent or malicious conduct by Certn or Certn’s employees.
15. **DISCLAIMER.**
    1. YOU ACKNOWLEDGE THAT CERTN OBTAINS THE INFORMATION IN ITS REPORTS FROM THIRD PARTY SOURCES “AS IS”, AND THEREFORE PROVIDES THE INFORMATION TO YOU ON AN “AS IS'' AND “AS AVAILABLE” BASIS. CERTN MAKES NO REPRESENTATION OR WARRANTY, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO, IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR PARTICULAR PURPOSE, OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES ARISING FROM THE COURSE OF DEALING OR A COURSE OF PERFORMANCE WITH RESPECT TO THE ACCURACY, VALIDITY, OR COMPLETENESS OF ANY REPORTS THAT THE REPORTS WILL MEET YOUR NEEDS, OR WILL BE PROVIDED ON AN UNINTERRUPTED BASIS, UNLESS SUCH GUARANTEE OR WARRANT CANNOT LAWFULLY BE EXCLUDED OR MODIFIED; CERTN EXPRESSLY DISCLAIMS ANY AND ALL SUCH REPRESENTATIONS AND WARRANTIES. EXCEPT AS EXPRESSLY SET FORTH IN THESE TERMS, CERTN EXPRESSLY DISCLAIMS THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, NONINFRINGEMENT, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND IMPLIED WARRANTIES ARISING FROM COURSE OF DEALING OR PERFORMANCE. CERTN AND ITS SUPPLIERS, LICENSORS, PARTNERS AND SERVICE PROVIDERS DO NOT WARRANT THAT THE FUNCTIONALITY AND INFORMATION PROVIDED BY THE PLATFORM WILL BE CORRECT, UNINTERRUPTED OR ERROR-FREE OR THAT DEFECTS WILL BE CORRECTED.
    2. CERTN IS NOT LIABLE FOR ANY OUTCOMES OR DECISIONS MADE BASED ON THE RESULTS PROVIDED IN THE REPORTS. YOUR SOLE AND EXCLUSIVE REMEDY WITH RESPECT TO THE CONTENTS OF THE REPORTS IS TO DISPUTE THE RESULTS.
    3. ANY PROMOTIONAL MATERIAL PROVIDED BY CERTN IS FOR INFORMATION PURPOSES ONLY AND DOES NOT FORM PART OF THESE TERMS OR HAVE ANY CONTRACTUAL FORCE.
16. **LIMITATION OF LIABILITY.**
    1. TO THE MAXIMUM EXTENT PERMITTED BY LAW, NEITHER PARTY SHALL BE LIABLE FOR ANY INDIRECT, PUNITIVE, SPECIAL, RELIANCE, INCIDENTAL, CONSEQUENTIAL OR SIMILAR DAMAGES (INCLUDING LOSS OF REVENUE OR PROFITS) ARISING OUT OF OR RELATING TO THESE TERMS, INCLUDING THE USE OR INABILITY TO USE THE SERVICE, OR FOR ANY INFORMATION OBTAINED FROM OR THROUGH THE SERVICE, ANY INTERRUPTION, INACCURACY OR ERROR IN THE CONTENT, EVEN IF CERTN HAS BEEN PREVIOUSLY ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES.
    2. EITHER PARTY'S CUMULATIVE AND AGGREGATE LIABILITY ARISING OUT OF THESE TERMS SHALL BE LIMITED TO THE GREATER OF THE AMOUNT THE END USER ACCRUED DURING THE TWELVE (12) MONTH PERIOD PRECEDING THE DATE OF THE CLAIM, OR USD$100,000.00. RECOVERY OF THIS AMOUNT IS EACH PARTY'S SOLE AND EXCLUSIVE REMEDY HEREUNDER AND THE PARTIES AGREE THAT THE LIMITATIONS AND DISCLAIMERS OF LIABILITY SET FORTH IN THIS SECTION WILL APPLY EVEN IF ANY LIMITED REMEDY SPECIFIED IN THESE TERMS IS FOUND TO HAVE FAILED OF ITS ESSENTIAL PURPOSE AND REGARDLESS OF THE THEORY OF LIABILITY. THE PARTIES AGREE THAT THE LIMITATIONS AND DISCLAIMERS OF LIABILITY UNDER THIS SECTION CONSTITUTE A FUNDAMENTAL BASIS OF THEIR BARGAIN.
    3. NOTWITHSTANDING ANY OTHER PROVISION CONTAINED IN THESE TERMS, NEITHER PARTY SHALL LIMIT OR EXCLUDE ITS LIABILITY UNDER SECTION 14 (INDEMNIFICATION) OR FOR CLAIMS ARISING OUT OF FRAUD, WILLFUL MISCONDUCT, OR GROSS NEGLIGENCE.
17. **UPDATES.**
    1. Certn may change its providers, the Platform features, and the production, support, delivery, layout or maintenance of the Reports from time to time, or discontinue the provision of a Report, in its sole discretion, provided that no such change will result in any material reduction in the utility, functionality, or integrity of Certn’s services to You. Certn will use commercially reasonable efforts to provide at least thirty (30) days’ advance notice to You regarding any material and adverse changes to the Services.
    2. You acknowledge that Certn may update a Report as part of Certn’s quality assurance review within thirty (30) days of a Report completion date. In such cases, Certn will provide You and the Consumer a copy of the updated Report.
18. **TERM AND TERMINATION.**
    1. The agreement between the parties will continue from Effective Date until terminated by one or both of the parties in accordance with the below (“**Term**”).
    2. Certn may suspend, limit or terminate Your access to or use of the Platform, the Services or Account at any time if: (i) the End User does not timely pay all Fees due; (ii) in the sole discretion of Certn such action is necessary to prevent material errors or harm; (iii) You attempt to access or use the Platform or Reports in an unauthorized or unlawful manner; (iv) Certn reasonably believes that You have breached these Terms; (v) requested to do so by a third party data provider or regulatory body; or (vii) a material change in existing legal requirements adversely affects Your access to the Services. Certn may (but is not obligated to) terminate Your account if You are inactive on the Platform for more than six (6) months.
    3. Either party may terminate these Terms for any reason upon thirty (30) days written notice to the other party; provided that, You shall remain liable for all Fees incurred up to the termination date.
19. **NOT LEGAL ADVICE.**
    1. Certn does not, and cannot, provide legal advice or other compliance related services to You or guarantee Your compliance with Laws in Your use of the Platform or Reports. You understand that any documentation, information, conversations or communication with Certn’s representatives regarding searches, verifications or other services offered by Certn are not to be considered a legal opinion regarding such use. You agree to consult with your own legal counsel (1) about the use of Reports including but not limited to, the legality of using or relying on reported information; and (2) to review any Certn Forms as well as the content of prescribed authorizations, notices, adverse or pre-adverse action letters and any attachments to these Terms for compliance with all Laws. You agree that the provision of such notices, pre-adverse or adverse action letters and the contents thereof is Your sole responsibility. You acknowledge and agree that You have no obligation to use, and are solely responsible for independently vetting the contents of, any sample forms that Certn has provided to You.
    2. Any information released by Certn (including but not limited to the Reports) shall in no way be construed as Certn’s opinion on the solvency, capability, aptitude, experience, financial standing, creditworthiness, integrity or motives of any party or Consumer reported upon. The application of Reports and any other information resulting from the use of the Services requires You to use Your own judgment and skill. Information resulting from the Services merely reflects a recording of information received by Certn from various sources from time to time and as such Certn accepts no liability for any opinions, recommendations, forecasts, comments made, or actions and decisions taken in reliance on such information.
20. **GENERAL.**
    1. **Governing Law**. If the End User is located in the United States, these Terms shall be governed by, and construed in accordance with, the laws of the state of Delaware without giving effect to the conflict of laws principles thereof. If the End User is located in the United Kingdom or the European Union, these Terms shall be governed by the laws of England and Wales without regard to conflict of laws principles that would require the application of the laws of another jurisdiction. If the End User is located in Australia or the Asian Pacific region, these Terms shall be governed by the laws of the state of Victoria, Australia and the Commonwealth of Australia without regard to conflict of laws principles that would require the application of the laws of another jurisdiction. If the End User is located in Canada or anywhere other than the jurisdictions mentioned above, these Terms shall be governed by the laws of the Province of British Columbia without regard to conflict of laws principles that would require the application of the laws of another jurisdiction.
    2. **Assignment**. You may not assign any of Your rights or obligations under these Terms without the prior written consent of Certn, such consent will not be unreasonably withheld. Subject to the foregoing, the rights and obligations under these Terms shall ensure to the benefit of and are binding on the Your permitted assignees, transferees and successors. Any attempted assignment in violation of this clause is void.
    3. **Consumer** **Arbitration** **Provisions**. To the extent You have a terms of use or similar document or agreement applicable to Consumers that includes an arbitration provision, You agree to add the following language (or language that is substantively the same) to that arbitration provision: “Our rights and obligations under this arbitration provision shall inure to the benefit of the consumer reporting agency regardless of whether the consumer reporting agency is named as a co-defendant with us or named individually in a claim that would otherwise be subject to this arbitration provision if brought against us.”
    4. **Sanctions** **Compliance**. Neither You, nor any person having a direct or indirect beneficial interest in Your entity has been or is (i) the subject of sanctions administered or enforced by the United States (including without limitation the U.S. Department of the Treasury’s Office of Foreign Asset Control), the United Kingdom, the European Union, Canada or any other governmental authority (collectively, “Sanctions”), (ii) organized or resident in a country or territory that is the subject of country-wide or territory-wide Sanctions, or (iii) otherwise a party with which Certn is prohibited from dealing with under applicable Laws.
    5. **Insurance**. The parties shall, during the Term, maintain, in full force and effect, appropriate insurance coverage in accordance with the best industry standards applicable to such party.
    6. **Integration**. These Terms, along with the Website terms, the DPA and any appendices, documents or attachments referenced directly herein, reflect the parties’ entire agreement relating to its subject and supersedes any prior or contemporaneous agreements on that subject. For avoidance of doubt, if You have signed a separate MSA or Order Form, the terms of that instrument shall govern the relationship between the parties and supersede these Terms, as specifically set out in such agreement.
    7. **Force** **Majeure**. Certn will not be responsible for any failure or delay in its performance under these Terms due to causes beyond its reasonable control, including, but not limited to, labor disputes, strikes, lockouts, internet or telecommunications failures; shortages of or inability to obtain labor, energy, or supplies; war, terrorism, riot, acts of God or governmental action; acts by hackers or other malicious third parties and problems with the Internet generally, and such performance shall be excused to the extent that it is prevented or delayed by reason of any of the foregoing.
    8. **Relationship**. These terms do not create an agency, partnership or joint venture, or authority to bind the other party.
    9. **Severable**. If any provision is found unenforceable, it and any related provisions will be interpreted to best accomplish the unenforceable provisions essential purpose.
    10. **No** **Waiver**. Any waiver of a provision of these Terms will only be valid if provided in writing and applies only to the specific occurrence so waived. Failure to enforce any provision will not constitute a waiver.
    11. **Equitable** **Relief**. Nothing in these Terms will limit a party’s ability to seek equitable relief. Section headings are not to be used in the interpretation hereof.
    12. **Survival**. All provisions that, by their nature, are intended to survive, including but not limited to payment obligations, disclaimers of warranties, confidentiality, indemnities, and limitations of liability, shall survive the termination of these Terms, including those provisions set out in any addenda, attachments, exhibits and/or schedules attached hereto.
21. **SUPPORT.**  
      
    You can request Platform support during Certn’s normal business hours via email sent to [support@certn.co](mailto:support@certn.co). While Certn makes commercially reasonable efforts to ensure continuous availability of the Platform, Certn makes no representation, warranty or guarantee regarding the continuous availability or performance of the Platform.
22. **NOTICES.**
    1. An electronic communication (“**Electronic Notice**”) shall be deemed written notice for purposes of this Services Agreement if sent to the electronic mail address below or as specified by the receiving party. Electronic Notice shall be deemed received at the time the party sending Electronic Notice receives verification of receipt by the receiving party.

Notice to Certn: [compliance@certn.co](mailto:compliance@certn.co) or by mail to 1006 Fort St Suite 300, Victoria, BC V8V 3K4.

Data Processing Addendum
------------------------

### Version 1.3

##### Effective January 23rd 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

Data Processing Addendum

This Data Processing Addendum (“**DPA**”) forms part of the Services Agreement signed by you (the “**Client**”) when you created your account (the “**Agreement**”).

1. **Definitions.** Capitalized terms not defined herein shall have the meanings assigned to such terms in the Agreement. In the event of any conflict between certain provisions of this DPA and the provisions of the Agreement, the provisions of this DPA shall prevail over the conflicting provisions of the Agreement solely with respect to the Processing of Personal Information.

1. “**CCPA**” means the California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018, Cal. Civ. Code §1798.100 et. seq., and its implementing regulations.
2. “**CPA**” means the Colorado Privacy Act of 2021.
3. “**Data Controller**” (or the “**Controller**”) a legal person, public authority, agency, or other body which, alone or jointly with others, determines the purposes and means of the Processing of Personal Information and gives instructions regarding processing activities to Certn; for the purposes of the Agreement the Client is the Data Controller.
4. “**Data Processor**” (or the “**Processor**”) means the legal entity that processes the Personal Information on behalf of the Data Controller; for the purposes of the Agreement Certn, as defined in the Agreement, is the Data Processor.
5. “**Data Subject Access Request**” means a form for the Consumer (or the “**Data Subject**” as defined in GDPR) to request access, copy, amendment, dispute, delete or any additional actions to their Personal Information subject to the applicable Data Protection Legislation.
6. “**FADP**” the Swiss Federal Act on Data Protection.
7. “**GDPR**” means the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation (EU) 2016/679.
8. “**LGPD**” General Data Protection Law (Lei Geral de Proteção de Dados).
9. “**Personal Information**” or “**Personal Data**” means any information that identifies, relates to, describes, is capable of being associated with, or could reasonably be linked, directly or indirectly, to or with an identified or identifiable Consumer, which is processed by Certn solely on behalf of the Client, under this DPA and the Agreement.
10. “**Processing**” (or “**Process**” or “**Processed**”) means any operation or set of operations which is performed on Personal Information or on sets of Personal Information, whether or not by automated means, such as collection, recording, organization, structuring, storage, adaptation or alteration, retrieval, consultation, use, disclosure by transmission, dissemination or otherwise making available, alignment or combination, restriction, erasure or destruction.
11. “**Processing Purpose**” the Permissible Purpose, as defined in the Agreement.
12. “**Standard Contractual Clauses**” (“**SCCs**”) means the Standard Contractual Clauses as set out [here](https://certn.co/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/STANDARD-CONTRACTUAL-CLAUSES.pdf) forming part of this with respect to Controller to Processor transfers pursuant to the European Commission’s Decision (EU) 2021/914 of 4 June 2021 (as maybe updated by the European Commission from time to time).
13. “**Sub-processor**” means a Sub-processor engaged, appointed and supervised by Certn who agrees to receive and process Personal Information under the terms of this DPA and solely for the purposes of processing or delivering data, subject to the terms of the Agreement.
14. “**UK Data Protection Laws**” means all laws relating to data protection, the processing of Personal Information, privacy and/or electronic communications in force from time to time in the UK, including the UK GDPR and the Data Protection Act 2018.
15. “**UK GDPR**” means the United Kingdom General Data Protection Regulation, as it forms part of the law of England and Wales, Scotland and Northern Ireland by virtue of section 3 of the European Union (Withdrawal) Act 2018.
16. “**VCDPA**” means the Virginia Consumer Data Protection Act.

3. **Roles.** The Parties acknowledge and agree that with respect to the Processing and transfers of Personal Information subject to the material and territorial scope of GDPR, FADP, LGPD, CPA and the VCDPA : (i) the Client is the Controller of Personal Information; (ii) Certn is the Processor of such Personal Information; and (iii) for the purposes of the CCPA (and to the extent applicable), Client is the “**Business**” and Certn is the “**Service Provider**” (as such terms are defined in the CCPA). As a Consumer Reporting Agency (“**CRA**”), Certn is not considered a data broker and is therefore exempt from the CCPA (see Section 1798.99.80 (d) (1)). The California Civil Code includes exemptions for CRAs (see §1798.145(d)(1) for details).
4. **General.**

1. Each Party shall comply with all Applicable Laws with respect of its handling of Personal Information and undertakes to use best efforts to assist the other in each Party’s compliance with any obligations under Applicable Laws and shall not perform its obligations under this DPA in such a manner as to cause the other Party to breach any of its obligations under Applicable Laws to the extent it is aware, or ought reasonably to have been aware, that the same would be a breach of such obligations.
2. Certn shall process Personal Information only on documented instructions from the Client in accordance with the Processing Purpose, unless required to do so by the Applicable Laws. Subsequent instructions may also be given by the Client throughout the duration of the Processing of Personal Information. Such instructions shall always be documented.
3. Certn shall immediately inform the Client if Certn believes that the instructions given by the Client (or Controller) infringe Applicable Laws.

6. **Purpose limitation.** Certn shall only process the Personal Information for the Processing Purpose, to the extent, and in such a manner, as is necessary for the performance of the Services. Certn will not process the Personal Information for any other purpose or in a way that does not comply with the Agreement (including this Schedule) or Applicable Laws.
7. **Erasure or return of Personal Information.**

1. Certn shall only Process the Personal Information provided by the Client during the Term of the Agreement.
2. Unless otherwise agreed between the Parties, the provisions in Annex I.B shall apply in relation to the data retention and erasure schedules.

9. **Security of Processing.**

1. Certn shall maintain commercially reasonable standards to ensure the security of the Personal Information, including protection against accidental or unlawful destruction, loss, alteration, unauthorized disclosure or access to that data (personal data breach). A copy of Certn’s technical and organizational measures are set out in Annex II. If the Processing involves Personal Information revealing sensitive or biometric data for the purpose of uniquely identifying a natural person, or data relating to criminal convictions and offences, Certn shall apply specific restrictions and/or additional safeguards as reasonably required by the Client from time to time.
2. In assessing the appropriate level of security, both Parties shall take due account of the risks involved in the Processing, the nature of the Personal Information and the nature, scope, context and purposes of Processing.
3. In the event of a Personal Information breach, either Party shall notify the other without undue delay, and at the latest within 24 hours, after having become aware of the breach. Such notification shall contain the details of a contact point where more information concerning the Personal Information breach can be obtained, a description of the nature of the breach (including, where possible, categories and approximate number of data subjects and data records concerned), its likely consequences and the measures taken or proposed to be taken to mitigate its possible adverse effects. Where, and insofar as, it is not possible to provide all information at the same time, the initial notification shall contain the information then available and further information shall be provided as it becomes available without undue delay.

11. **Consumer rights.** Certn shall promptly notify the Client if it receives a Data Subject Access Request. Client shall be responsible for responding to Data Subject Access Requests and, however, to the extent the Client, does not have the ability to address a Data Subject Access Request, Certn, shall, where required by law or upon the Client’s request, provide reasonable efforts to assist the Client in responding to such Data Subject Access Request without additional costs during the timeframe of the Applicable Law.
12. **Subprocessors.**

1. Certn’s Sub-processors (found [here](https://trust.certn.co/)) shall be the entities engaged by Certn who agree to receive Personal Information from the Processor exclusively for Processing activities to be carried out on behalf of the Client’s instructions. The Client acknowledges and agrees that Certn’s Affiliates (a) may be retained as Sub-processors; and (b) may each engage third-party Sub-processors in connection with the provision of the Services. Certn may remove, replace, or appoint suitable and reliable further Sub-processors, with notice to the Client, at its own discretion.
2. Notwithstanding the above, Client may reasonably object to Certn’s use of a new Sub-processor, for reasons relating to the protection of Personal Information intended to be Processed by such Sub-processor, by notifying Certn promptly in writing within three (3) business days after receipt of Certn’s notice. Such written objection shall include those reasons for objecting to Processor’s use of such a new Sub-processor. Failure to object to such a new Sub-processor in writing within three (3) business days following Certn’s notice shall be deemed as acceptance of the new Sub-Processor. In the event the Client reasonably objects to a new Sub-processor, as permitted above, Certn may:

1. stop using the Sub-processor with regard to the Personal Information submitted by the Client;
2. take the corrective steps as requested by the Client in its objection;
3. cease to provide (temporarily or permanently) the particular aspect of the Service that would involve the use of such Sub-processor with regard to the Personal Information submitted by the Client; and
4. provide Client with a written description of commercially reasonable alternative(s), if any, to such engagement, including without limitation modification to the Services.

4. If Certn, in its sole discretion, cannot provide any alternative(s) listed above, or if the Client does not agree to any such alternative(s) if provided, Certn and the Client may terminate the Agreement in accordance with the terms of the Agreement. Termination shall not relieve Client of any fees owed to Certn under the Agreement. Until a decision is made regarding the new Sub-processor, Certn may, where necessary, temporarily suspend the Processing of the affected Personal Information and/or suspend access to the account and Client will have no further claims against Processor due to the temporary suspension or the termination of the Agreement (including, without limitation, requesting refunds).
5. Certn shall ensure that all authorized Sub-processors have executed confidentiality agreements that prevent them from unauthorized Processing of Client Personal Information both during and after their engagement by Certn. In addition, Certn shall, (e.g., by way of contract or other legal act) impose on the Sub-processor the same data protection obligations as set out in this DPA.

14. **International Data transfers.**

1. **International data transfers subject to the SCCs.** Where the transfer of Personal Information is made subject to the SCCs, the “data importer” thereunder shall be either the Processor or its Sub-processor, as the case may be and as determined by Processor, and the “data exporter” shall be the Controller of such Personal Information. The Processor shall ensure that the relevant Sub-processor shall (where applicable) comply with the data importer’s obligations, and the Controller shall comply with the data exporter obligations, in each case under the applicable SCCs.
2. **International data transfers from and to countries that offer adequate level of data protection.** Personal Information may be transferred from EU Member States and the EEA member countries (Norway, Liechtenstein, and Iceland) (collectively, “EEA”) to countries that offer an adequate level of data protection (including Canada) under or pursuant to the adequacy decisions published by the relevant data protection authorities of the EEA or the European Commission (“Adequacy Decisions”), as relevant and applicable , without any further safeguard being necessary.
3. **Transfers from Switzerland.** To the extent that the Swiss Supervisory Authority considers the SCCs to provide appropriate safeguards for the purposes of transferring Personal Information and the data of legal entities, the following amendments shall apply in relation to Swiss transfers: (i) the Parties adopt the GDPR standard for all data transfers; (ii) in relation to Clause 13a, the EU Supervisory Authority shall be competent insofar as the data transfer is governed by the GDPR and the Swiss Supervisory Authority (FDPIC) shall conduct parallel supervision as applicable; and (iii) in relation to Clause 18 c, the term ’member state’ shall be interpreted in such a way as to allow data subjects in Switzerland with the possibility of suing for their rights in their place of habitual residence (Switzerland).
4. **Transfers from the United Kingdom.** To the extent that the UK Supervisory Authority (the Information Commissioner) considers the SCCs to provide appropriate safeguards for the purposes of transferring Personal Information to a third country or an international organisation in reliance on Articles 46 of the UK GDPR and, with respect to data transfers from controllers to processors and/or processors to processors, the following amendments shall apply in relation to UK transfers:
    1. “The details of the transfers(s) and in particular the categories of Personal Information that are transferred and the purpose(s) for which they are transferred) are those specified in Annex I.B where UK Data Protection Laws apply to the data exporter’s processing when making that transfer.”
    2. References to “Regulation (EU) 2016/679” or “that Regulation” are replaced by “UK Data Protection Laws” and references to specific Article(s) of “Regulation (EU) 2016/679” are replaced with the equivalent Article or Section of UK Data Protection Laws. In particular:

1. References to Regulation (EU) 2018/1725 are removed;
2. References to the “Union”, “EU” and “EU Member State” are all replaced with the “UK”;
3. Clause 13(a) is not used and the “competent supervisory authority” is the Information Commissioner;
4. Clause 17 is replaced to state “These SCCs are governed by the laws of England and Wales”;
5. Clause 18 is replaced to state: “Any dispute arising from these SCCs shall be resolved by the courts of England and Wales. A data subject may also bring legal proceedings against the data exporter and/or data importer before the courts of any country in the UK. The Parties agree to submit themselves to the jurisdiction of such courts.”; and
6. The footnotes to the SCCs do not apply to UK transfers.

16. **Miscellaneous.** Data Controller shall not unreasonably withhold or delay agreement to any consequential variations to this DPA proposed by Data Processor to protect the Data Processor against additional risks associated. If Data Controller proposes any other variations to this DPA which Data Controller reasonably considers to be necessary to address the requirements of Applicable laws, the Parties shall promptly discuss the proposed variations and negotiate in good faith with a view to agreeing and implementing those or alternative variations as soon as is reasonably practicable. Notwithstanding the foregoing, upon notice to the Client, Certn may revise this Addendum so as to incorporate any mandatory SCCs or other terms that are required by any competent data protection authority in the EU or the UK  

ANNEX I  

Annex I.A - PARTIES

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| **The Data Exporter** | The data exporter is identified as the Client or the “Controller” in the DPA. |
| **The Data Importer** | The data importer is Certn, a provider of data verification and background screening services. |

Annex I.B - PROCESSING INFORMATION

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| **Data Subjects** | Those individuals and applicants subject to the background verification services for the purposes of employment, tenancy or any other lawful and permissible purpose as instructed by the Controller. |
| **Categories of Personal Data Transferred** | **Client data:** business related contact details (email, phone, email address, names, job titles, business address).<br><br>**Consumer data:** Email addresses, names, contact details, job titles, residential or business address; photograph; personal identification numbers (where applicable); academic title and qualifications; career history; driving license; attendance records; job title; gender; professional telephone number (including mobile telephone number) and fax number; personal email address; personal telephone number (including mobile telephone number); credit score or limit, risk, failure and delinquency score; payment information; criminal history; records for associated claims and judgments; public records such as directorships, insolvencies, bankruptcies, financial standing, IP address; cookie data; login credentials (username and password); traffic data; images and sounds; Biometric data. |
| **The Frequency of Transfers** | Transfers will be processed on an on-demand basis. |
| **Nature of the Processing** | The nature and purpose of processing means any operation such as collection, recording, organization, structuring, storage, retrieval, consultation, use, disclosure by transmission, dissemination or otherwise making available, restriction, erasure or destruction of data (whether or not by automated means) |
| **Purpose(s) of the Data Transfer and Further Processing** | Providing the Services to the Client as set out with the Agreement; performing the Agreement, this DPA and/or other contracts executed by the Parties; providing support and technical maintenance, if agreed in the Agreement; preventing, mitigating and investigating the risks of data security incidents, fraud, error or any illegal or prohibited activity; complying with applicable laws and regulations; all tasks related with any of the above. |
| **The Period for Which the Personal Data Will Be Retained, or, If That Is Not Possible, the Criteria Used to Determine that Period** | The Parties agree to erase Personal Data from any computers, storage devices and storage media as soon as practicable after it has ceased to be necessary for such Party to retain the Personal Data under applicable Data Protection Legislation or as otherwise required by the Agreement. Notwithstanding the foregoing, unless otherwise agreed between the Parties, or required under applicable Data Protection Legislation, the Parties agree that (i) Client records will be retained by Certn in accordance with Certn’s Retention Policy which may be updated from time to time. |

Annex I.C - COMPETENT SUPERVISORY AUTHORITY

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| **Competent Supervisory Authority** | Data Protection Commission, the Republic of Ireland. |

ANNEX II

**TECHNICAL AND ORGANISATIONAL MEASURES INCLUDING TECHNICAL AND ORGANISATIONAL MEASURES TO ENSURE THE SECURITY OF THE DATA**

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| **The Technical and Organizational Measures Implemented by the Data Importer  <br>** | SOC2 compliance report is available upon request. SOC 3 compliance report is publicly available. |
| **Measures of Pseudonymization and Encryption of Personal Data  <br>** | The employed level of encryption is AES 256. |
| **Measures For Ensuring Ongoing Confidentiality, Integrity, Availability and Resilience of Processing Systems and Services  <br>** | Certn is SOC2 and SOC3 certified on a continuous basis. |
| **Measures For Ensuring the Ability to Restore the Availability and Access to Personal Data in a Timely Manner in the Event of a Physical or Technical Incident  <br>** | Backup and data restore procedures are defined and documented as Certn policies, available upon request. Execution of backups is monitored to ensure completeness. Certn stores data on AWS cloud which has automatic backups configured and encrypted. In addition, there are multiple zones for redundancy and recovery purposes. |
| **Processes for Regularly Testing, Assessing and Evaluating the Effectiveness of Technical and Organizational Measures in Order to Ensure the Security of the Processing  <br>** | Certn is compliant to and certified under SOC2 and SOC3. Some of the processes and measures ensuring security of processing include, but are not limited to, vulnerability management, risk evaluation, asset management, IDS and IPS, patch management, endpoint monitoring, SIEM tools vendor management. |
| **Measures for User Identification and Authorization  <br>** | An access control system applicable to all users accessing the IT system has been implemented. The system allows Certn to create, approve, review, and delete user accounts.<br><br>Certn implements multi-factor authentication for all accounts that have access to Personal Data. Where authentication mechanisms are based on passwords, the data processor requires the password to be at least eight characters long and conform to very strong password control parameters including length, character complexity, and non-repeatability.<br><br>Role- based authorizations in alignment to an established Authorization Control Policy. When granting access or assigning user roles, the “need-to-know principle” is observed in order to limit the number of users having access to Personal Information only to those who require it for achieving the Processor’s Processing Purposes. |
| **Measures for the Protection of Data During Transmission  <br>** | The Supplier maintains access controls to ensure role based access, logging mechanisms to show events of users which can be ported to a SIEM, encryption of data at rest and in transit using AES 256 encryption and ≥TLS v1.2 respectively. |
| **Measures for the Protection of Data During Storage  <br>** | Certn maintains a Data Encryption Policy, Data Backup Policy and a Data Retention Policy which govern access, availability and duration of stored categories data. |
| **Measures for Ensuring Physical Security of Locations at which Personal Data is Processed  <br>** | Certn maintains a Physical Security Policy which covers provisions for physical office access with key fobs, security alarms, security surveillance, visitor limited access. The physical perimeter of the IT system infrastructure is not accessible by non-authorized personnel. Appropriate technical measures and organizational measures are set in place to protect security areas and their access points against entry by unauthorized persons. Certn stores its data on AWS cloud following the best practices and requirements. Data is segmented, encrypted and backed up with the inclusion of multi zonal availability. |
| **Measures for Ensuring Events Logging  <br>** | SIEM collects events and policies and alerts are created for analysis and investigations. Endpoint protections and monitoring, intrusion detection and prevention with monitoring and evaluation. |
| **Measures for Ensuring System Configuration, Including Default Configuration  <br>** | Certn maintains an Asset Management Policy which defines the Configuration standards and any applicable variables. A system access control policy has been defined, documented and implemented to allow for evaluation of controls and access to Certn’s assets. |
| **Measures for Internal IT and IT Security Governance and Management  <br>** | Certn maintains an Information Security Policy and conducts employee security internal security training during the onboarding phase and annually thereafter. |
| **Measures for Certification/assurance of Processes and Products  <br>** | SOC2 compliance report is available upon request. SOC 3 compliance report is publicly available. |
| **Measures for Ensuring Data Minimization  <br>** | Any processed Personal Information is limited to the strictly necessary matching identifiers defined by the data sources we operate with. |
| **Measures for Ensuring Data Quality  <br>** | To ensure that Personal Information Is accurate, relevant, complete and up-to-date, Certn processes data verifications in real time, with the consent of the Data Subject and only within the limits of the defined Permissible Purpose. Any potentially incomplete data is reconfirmed with the Data Subject and/or the relative data source. |
| **Measures for Ensuring Limited Data Retention  <br>** | Certn has an established policy for Data Retention which defines different purging schedules for separate categories of data. |
| **Measures for Ensuring Accountability  <br>** | Certn maintains a “privacy by design approach” and is regularly and independently audited for the purposes of maintaining the highest industry standards for internal controls for security, availability, processing integrity and confidentiality and privacy. |
| **Measures for Allowing Data Portability and Ensuring Erasure  <br>** | Data Subjects can log Data Subject Access requests which are reviewed by a privacy officer. |
| **Subprocessors** | Sub Processors are required to meet the same standards as set out in the current Annex II. |

FCRA Disclosure
---------------

### Version 16.2

##### Effective March 12th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**DISCLOSURE**

CONSUMER REPORT

**{{{company\_name}}}** ("the **Company**") has requested a "consumer report" on you for the purpose of evaluating your current or potential employment through Certn (a consumer reporting agency). A "**consumer report**" is a background screening report that may contain information regarding your domestic and international background history, including but not limited to, your social security number and identification documents, criminal history, sex offender registry status, credit history, employment history, education history, driving history, professional licenses, drug testing results and other information about you.  

\[END OF DOCUMENT\]

Additional Information Disclosure Regarding Your Rights
-------------------------------------------------------

### Version 15.0

##### Effective February 14th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

ADDITIONAL NOTICE REGARDING

INVESTIGATIVE CONSUMER REPORTS ON YOU

**{{{company\_name}}}** ("the Company") may also request an "investigative consumer report" on you from a consumer reporting agency.

An "investigative consumer report" is a background screening report generated through personal interviews with sources such as your neighbors, friends, or associates.

The consumer reporting agency that may prepare an "investigative consumer report" on you for the Company is Certn (USA) Inc., 3820 Central Avenue #220, Cheyenne, WY 82001, 844-987-0690. The information contained in an "investigative consumer report" may bear upon your character, general reputation, personal characteristics, and/or mode of living.

Please be advised that the nature and scope of the most common form of "investigative consumer report" that may be ordered by the Company is an investigation into your employment history. During such an investigation, Certn may ask questions about your employment history to certain knowledgeable individuals and provide response information to the Company.

Note: You have the right to request additional information regarding the nature and scope of any "investigative consumer report" ordered by the Company on you. You may do so by contacting the Company.

\[END OF DOCUMENT\]

FCRA Summary of Rights
----------------------

### Version 19.0

##### Effective May 5th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

Para información en español, visite [www.consumerfinance.gov/learnmore](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/www.consumerfinance.gov/learnmore) o escribe a la Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, 1700 G Street N.W., Washington, DC 20552.

A Summary of Your Rights Under the Fair Credit Reporting Act

The federal Fair Credit Reporting Act (FCRA) promotes the accuracy, fairness, and privacy of information in the files of consumer reporting agencies. There are many types of consumer reporting agencies, including credit bureaus and specialty agencies (such as agencies that sell information about check writing histories, medical records, and rental history records). Here is a summary of your major rights under FCRA. For more information, including information about additional rights, go to [www.consumerfinance.gov/learnmore](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/www.consumerfinance.gov/learnmore) or write to: Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, 1700 G Street N.W., Washington, DC 20552.

∙ You must be told if information in your file has been used against you. Anyone who uses a credit report or another type of consumer report to deny your application for credit, insurance, or employment – or to take another adverse action against you – must tell you, and must give you the name, address, and phone number of the agency that provided the information.

∙ You have the right to know what is in your file. You may request and obtain all the information about you in the files of a consumer reporting agency (your “file disclosure”). You will be required to provide proper identification, which may include your Social Security number. In many cases, the disclosure will be free. You are entitled to a free file disclosure if:

o a person has taken adverse action against you because of information in your credit report;

o you are the victim of identity theft and place a fraud alert in your file;

o your file contains inaccurate information as a result of fraud;

o you are on public assistance;

o you are unemployed but expect to apply for employment within 60 days.

In addition, all consumers are entitled to one free disclosure every 12 months upon request from each nationwide credit bureau and from nationwide specialty consumer reporting agencies. See [www.consumerfinance.gov/learnmore](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/www.consumerfinance.gov/learnmore) for additional information.

∙ You have the right to ask for a credit score. Credit scores are numerical summaries of your credit-worthiness based on information from credit bureaus. You may request a credit score from consumer reporting agencies that create scores or distribute scores used in residential real property loans, but you will have to pay for it. In some mortgage transactions, you will receive credit score information for free from the mortgage lender.

∙ You have the right to dispute incomplete or inaccurate information. If you identify information in your file that is incomplete or inaccurate, and report it to the consumer reporting agency, the agency must investigate unless your dispute is frivolous. See [www.consumerfinance.gov/learnmore](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/www.consumerfinance.gov/learnmore) for an explanation of dispute procedures.

∙ Consumer reporting agencies must correct or delete inaccurate, incomplete, or unverifiable information. Inaccurate, incomplete, or unverifiable information must be removed or corrected, usually within 30 days. However, a consumer reporting agency may continue to report information it has verified as accurate.

∙ Consumer reporting agencies may not report outdated negative information. In most cases, a consumer reporting agency may not report negative information that is more than seven years old, or bankruptcies that are more than 10 years old.

∙ Access to your file is limited. A consumer reporting agency may provide information about you only to people with a valid need – usually to consider an application with a creditor, insurer, employer, landlord, or other business. The FCRA specifies those with a valid need for access.

∙ You must give your consent for reports to be provided to employers. A consumer reporting agency may not give out information about you to your employer, or a potential employer, without your written consent given to the employer. Written consent generally is not required in the trucking industry. For more information, go to [www.consumerfinance.gov/learnmore](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/www.consumerfinance.gov/learnmore)

∙ You may limit “prescreened” offers of credit and insurance you get based on information in your credit report. Unsolicited “prescreened” offers for credit and insurance must include a toll-free phone number you can call if you choose to remove your name and address form the lists these offers are based on. You may opt out with the nationwide credit bureaus at 1-888-5-OPTOUT (1-888-567-8688).

∙ The following FCRA right applies with respect to nationwide consumer reporting agencies :

CONSUMERS HAVE THE RIGHT TO OBTAIN A SECURITY FREEZE

You have a right to place a “security freeze” on your credit report, which will prohibit a consumer reporting agency from releasing information in your credit report without your express authorization. The security freeze is designed to prevent credit, loans, and services from being approved in your name without your consent. However, you should be aware that using a security freeze to take control over who gets access to the personal and financial information in your credit report may delay, interfere with, or prohibit the timely approval of any subsequent request or application you make regarding a new loan, credit, mortgage, or any other account involving the extension of credit.

As an alternative to a security freeze, you have the right to place an initial or extended fraud alert on your credit file at no cost. An initial fraud alert is a 1-year alert that is placed on a consumer’s credit file. Upon seeing a fraud alert display on a consumer’s credit file, a business is required to take steps to verify the consumer’s identity before extending new credit. If you are a victim of identity theft, you are entitled to an extended fraud alert, which is a fraud alert lasting 7 years.

A security freeze does not apply to a person or entity, or its affiliates, or collection agencies acting on behalf of the person or entity, with which you have an existing account that requests information in your credit report for the purposes of reviewing or collecting the account. Reviewing the account includes activities related to account maintenance, monitoring, credit line increases, and account upgrades and enhancements.

∙ You may seek damages from violators. If a consumer reporting agency, or, in some cases, a user of consumer reports or a furnisher of information to a consumer reporting agency violates the FCRA, you may be able to sue in state or federal court.

∙ Identity theft victims and active duty military personnel have additional rights. For more information, visit [www.consumerfinance.gov/learnmore](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/www.consumerfinance.gov/learnmore)

States may enforce the FCRA, and many states have their own consumer reporting laws. In some cases, you may have more rights under state law. For more information, contact your state or local consumer protection agency or your state Attorney General. For information about your federal rights, contact:

|     |     |
| --- | --- | 
| **TYPE OF BUSINESS:** | **CONTACT:** |
| 1.a. Banks, savings associations, and credit unions with total assets of over $10 billion and their affiliates<br><br>b. Such affiliates that are not banks, savings associations, or credit unions also should list, in addition to the CFPB: | a. Consumer Financial Protection Bureau<br><br>1700 G Street, N.W.<br><br>Washington, DC 20552<br><br>  <br><br>b. Federal Trade Commission<br><br>Consumer Response Center<br><br>600 Pennsylvania Avenue, N.W.<br><br>Washington, DC 20580<br><br>(877) 382-4357 |
| 2\. To the extent not included in item 1 above:<br><br>a. National banks, federal savings associations, and federal branches and federal agencies of foreign banks<br><br>b. State member banks, branches and agencies of foreign banks (other than federal branches, federal agencies, and Insured State Branches of Foreign Banks), commercial lending companies owned or controlled by foreign banks, and organizations operating under section 25 or 25A of the Federal Reserve Act.<br><br>c. Nonmember Insured Banks, Insured State Branches of Foreign Banks, and insured state savings associations<br><br>d. Federal Credit Unions | a. Office of the Comptroller of the Currency<br><br>Customer Assistance Group<br><br>P.O. Box 53570<br><br>Houston, TX 77052-9050<br><br>  <br><br>b. Federal Reserve Consumer Help Center<br><br>P.O. Box 1200<br><br>Minneapolis, MN 55480<br><br>  <br><br>c. Division of Depositor and Consumer Protection<br><br>National Center for Consumer and Depositor Assistance<br><br>Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation<br><br>1100 Walnut Street, Box #11<br><br>Kansas City, MO 64106<br><br>  <br><br>d. National Credit Union Administration<br><br>Office of Consumer Financial Protection<br><br>1775 Duke Street<br><br>Alexandria, VA 22314 |
| 3\. Air carriers | Asst. General Counsel for Aviation Protection<br><br>Department of Transportation<br><br>1200 New Jersey Avenue, S.E.<br><br>Washington, DC 20590 |
| 4\. Creditors Subject to the Surface Transportation Board | Office of Public Assistance, Governmental Affairs, and Compliance Surface Transportation Board<br><br>395 E Street, S.W.<br><br>Washington, DC 20423 |
| 5\. Creditors Subject to the Packers and Stockyards Act, 1921 | Nearest Packers and Stockyards Divsion Regional Office |
| 6\. Small Business Investment Companies | Associate Administrator, Office of Capital Access<br><br>United States Small Business Administration<br><br>409 Third Street, S.W., Suite 8200<br><br>Washington, DC 20416 |
| 7\. Brokers and Dealers | Securities and Exchange Commission<br><br>100 F Street, N.E.<br><br>Washington, DC 20549 |
| 8\. Federal Land Banks, Federal Land Bank Associations, Federal Intermediate Credit Banks, and Production Credit Associations | Farm Credit Administration<br><br>1501 Farm Credit Drive<br><br>McLean, VA 22102-5090 |
| 9\. Retailers, Finance Companies, and All Other Creditors Not Listed Above | Federal Trade Commission<br><br>Consumer Response Center<br><br>600 Pennsylvania Avenue, N.W.<br><br>Washington, DC 20580<br><br>(877) 382-4357 |

FCRA Authorization
------------------

### Version 20.0

##### Effective August 1st 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**AUTHORIZATION REGARDING BACKGROUND INVESTIGATION**

By signing below, I acknowledge receipt of the following separate documents (and certify that I have read and understood them):

* DISCLOSURE REGARDING BACKGROUND INVESTIGATION ON YOU;
* A SUMMARY OF YOUR RIGHTS UNDER THE FAIR CREDIT REPORTING ACT;
* ADDITIONAL NOTICE REGARDING INVESTIGATIVE CONSUMER REPORTS ON YOU;
* ADDITIONAL STATE LAW NOTICES.

By signing below, I also authorize domestic and international law enforcement agencies, learning institutions (including public and private schools, colleges and universities), information service bureaus, credit bureaus, data repositories, courts (federal, state and local), motor vehicle records agencies, my past or present employers, the military, and other public or private individuals and institutions to furnish any and all information on me that is requested by Certn, the consumer reporting agency preparing reports about me for **{{{company\_name}}}** . I agree that where my personal history requires verifications to be carried out in countries where I have worked and/or resided, my data may be sent and processed in those relevant countries for the delivery of the requested verifications. The information that can be disclosed to Certn includes, but is not limited to, criminal history, sex offender registry status, credit history, employment history, education history, driving history, and information regarding my professional licenses, social security number, identification documents, and drug testing results.

By signing below, I also authorize **{{{company\_name}}}** to obtain "**consumer reports**" and "**investigative consumer reports**" about me for employment purposes at any time during the hiring process and throughout my employment, if applicable.

Name: {{{first\_name}}} {{{last\_name}}}

You can withdraw your consent, dispute the accuracy of a Report, or ask for a correction, deletion or copy of your Report at any time by contacting Certn’s Privacy Officer at 1-844-987-0690 or [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co). Further information regarding the collection, use, disclosure, or storage of your Personal Information can be found [here](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/).  

\[END OF DOCUMENT\]

California Disclosure Form and California State Rights
------------------------------------------------------

### Version 3.0

##### Effective February 15th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**NOTICE REGARDING BACKGROUND INVESTIGATION**

**PURSUANT TO CALIFORNIA LAW**

**(For California Applicants and Employees Only)**

**{{{company\_name}}}** ("the Company") intends to obtain information about you from an investigative consumer reporting agency for employment purposes. Thus, you can expect to be the subject of "investigative consumer reports" obtained for employment purposes. Such reports may include information about your character, general reputation, personal characteristics, and mode of living. With respect to any investigative consumer report from an investigative consumer reporting agency ("ICRA"), the Company may investigate the information contained in your employment application and other background information about you, including but not limited to: your social security number and identification documents, criminal history, sex offender registry status, credit history, employment history, education history, driving history, professional licenses, drug testing results. The Company may also obtain comments from individuals who are knowledgeable about you . These reports may be used as a factor in making employment decisions. The source of any investigative consumer report (as that term is defined under California law) will be Certn (USA) Inc., 3820 Central Avenue #220, Cheyenne, WY 82001, 844-987-0690. Information regarding Certn's privacy practices (including information about whether any consumer personal information will be sent outside the U.S. or its territories) may be found at https: // certn . co / .

Under California Civil Code section 1786.22, you are entitled to find out from an ICRA what is in the ICRA's file on you with proper identification, as follows:

In person, by visual inspection of your file during normal business hours and upon reasonable notice. You also may request a copy of the information in person. The ICRA may not charge you more than the actual copying costs for providing you with a copy of your file.

* By requesting a copy be sent to a specified addressee by certified mail. ICRAs complying with requests for certified mailings shall not be liable for disclosures to third parties caused by mishandling of mail after such mailings leave the ICRAs.

A summary of all information contained in the ICRA's file on you (which is required to be provided

by the California Civil Code) will be provided to you via telephone, if you have made a written request for telephone disclosure and the toll charge, if any, for the telephone call is prepaid by or charged directly to you.

"Proper Identification" includes documents such as a valid driver's license, social security account number, military identification card, and credit cards. Only if you cannot identify yourself with such information may the ICRA require additional information concerning your employment and personal or family history in order to verify your identity.

The ICRA will provide trained personnel to explain any information furnished to you and will provide a written explanation of any coded information contained in files maintained on you. This written explanation will be provided whenever a file is provided to you for visual inspection.

You may be accompanied by one other person of your choosing, who must furnish reasonable identification. An ICRA may require you to furnish a written statement granting permission to the ICRA to discuss your file in such person's presence.

\[END OF DOCUMENT\]

**For California Residents Only**

**California Consumer Rights**

The following information may be obtained from Certn (Canada), Inc. and Certn (USA), Inc, 1006 Fort Street, Unit 300, Victoria, BC, Canada V8V 3K4. Our office hours are 9:00am to 5:00pm PTZ. Our telephone number is 844-987-0690. For complete information about Certn’s privacy practices, including whether your personal information will be sent outside of the U.S. or its territories, Certn’s privacy policy can be viewed at [https://certn.co/privacy-policy/](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/)

**CALIFORNIA CONSUMER RIGHTS**

You have rights when an investigative consumer report is obtained on you. The following are some of your rights:

1\. You have the right to contact the agency that made the report. You can do this in one of the following ways:

(a) You can go to the agency in person during the normal business hours and on reasonable notice. You can bring someone with you. You and that person may be required to present identification. You may be required to sign a paper allowing the agency to discuss your file with or to show your file to this person.

(b) You may receive your file by certified mail, if you have given written notice to the agency that you want information mailed to you or to another person you want to receive the file. You will be required to provide identification when you write for your file.

(c) You may be able to discuss your file over the telephone if you have given written instructions to the agency and have provided identification.

2\. You have the right to receive a copy of your file or your investigative consumer report at the agency. You may be charged up to $8.00 to obtain a copy of your report or file. However, you may receive a free copy if:

(a) Once during a twelve month period if you are unemployed and intend to seek employment within sixty (60) days or you receive public welfare assistance or you believe your file contains inaccurate information because of fraud.

(b) If you are receiving a copy from the agency relating to an investigation into the accuracy of information you have disputed or if information is put back into your file.

3\. You have the right to know the following information:

(a) The names of the persons and companies who have received a report about you in the last three (3) years. You may request their addresses and telephone numbers.

(b) Explanations of any codes or abbreviations used in your report, so you can understand the report.

4\. You have the right to dispute any information in your file. You must contact the agency directly to do so. The person who ordered a report is required to give you the name and address of the agency.

(a) The agency has thirty (30) days from the day it receives your dispute to complete the investigation.

(b) When the agency is done with the investigation, it must tell you of any changes made in the report as a result of the investigation.

(c) If the investigation does not remove the information disputed by you, you have the right to place your statement of the facts in your file. The agency has people to help you write the statement. The agency may limit your statement to five hundred (500) words.

(d) If information is removed or you add a statement to your file, you can request the agency to send the report, as changed or with your statement, to anyone who received the information in the last two (2) years.

(e) If information that is removed from your files is placed back in your file, you are entitled to receive written notice of that fact and you have the right to dispute the information added.

5\. You also have rights under federal law in regard to your report. A copy of those rights is given to you with this California statement of consumer rights. Many of these rights are also included within California law.

**Solo Para Residentes De California  
**

**Derechos del Consumidor de California**

**DERECHOS DEL CONSUMIDOR EN CALIFORNIA**

Usted tiene derechos cuando un reporte de investigación del consumidor es obtenido respecto a usted. Los siguientes son algunos de sus derechos:

1\. Usted tiene derecho de contactar la agencia que hizo el reporte y puede hacer èsto de las maneras siguientes:

(a) Puede ir a la agencia en persona durante horas normales de trabajo y en la nota razonable. Puede traer a un acompañante. Usted y esa persona debe traer una identificación. Es posible que tenga que firmar un documento en el que usted dará derecho a la agencia de discutir lo que está en su archivo o de mostrar el archivo a la persona que lo acompaña.

(b) Usted puede recibir su archivo por correspondencia certificada si es que avisó a la agencia por escrito que desea información por carta o desea que otra persona reciba su archivo. Por lo tanto, usted deberá proveer una identificación cuando solicite la información.

(c) Usted podrá platicar respecto a su archivo por telèfono si es que dió instrucciones por escrito a la agencia y presentó una identificación.

2\. Usted tiene derecho de recibir una copia de su archivo o de su reporte de investigación del consumidor en la agencia y se le puede cobrar hasta 8.00 dólares para obtener una copia de su reporte o archivo. De cualquier manera, usted podrá recibir una copia gratis en las siguientes circunstancias:

(a) Si es que durante doce meses usted está desempleado o tiene intenciones de buscar empleo durante 60 días o si usted recibe asistencia pública o cree que su archivo contiene información incorrecta debido a fraude.

(b) Si usted recibe una copia de la agencia relacionada con la nvestigación para verificar la exactitud de la información que usted reportó o si es que la información fuè regresada a su archivo.

3\. Usted tiene derecho de saber la siguiente información:

(a) Los nombres de personas y de compañías quienes han recibido un reporte respecto a usted en los últimos 3 años y puede solicitar sus domicilios y números de telèfono.

(b) Usted puede solicitar que se le explique códigos o abreviasiones utilizadas en su reporte para que usted lo pueda comprender con más claridad.

4\. Usted tiene derecho de reclamar cualquier información que estè en su archivo pero deberá contactar a la agencia directamente. La persona que ordenó el reporte deberá darle a usted el nombre y domicilio de la agencia.

(a) La agencia tiene 30 días para completar la investigación.

(b) Una vez terminada la investigación, la agencia debe informarle a usted de cualquier cambio que se haya hecho al reporte como resultado de la investigación.

(c) Si es que la investigación no elimina información reportada por usted, entonces tiene derecho de agregar su declaración en el archivo. La agencia tiene personal que le puede ayudar a escribir su declaración siempre y cuando no exceda quinientas (500) palabras.

(d) Si usted elimina o agrega información a su archivo puede pedirle a la agencia que mande el reporte como “Cambiado” o con su declaración a cualquierea que haya recibido la información en los últimos dos años.

(e) Si hay información que fuè eliminada de su archivo y despuès vuelta a poner, usted tiene derecho a recibir por escrito lo sucedido y tiene derecho a reclamar la información agregada.

5\. Tambièn tiene derechos bajo la ley federal respecto a su reporte. Se le dará una copia de esos derechos con èsta declaración de derechos del consumidor de California.

Oregon Credit Check Disclosure
------------------------------

### Version 2.0

##### Effective January 3rd 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

New York Disclosure and Article 23-A
------------------------------------

### Version 4.0

##### Effective February 15th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

You have the right, upon written request, to be informed of whether or not an investigative consumer report (as defined by state law) was requested from a consumer reporting agency. If a report was requested, you will be provided with the name and address of the consumer reporting agency to whom the request was made. You may also inspect and receive a copy of the report by contacting Certn (USA) Inc., 3820 Central Avenue #220, Cheyenne, WY 82001, 844-987-0690. You are also now receiving a copy of Article 23-A of the NY Correction Law.

Washington State Disclosure and Washington State Rights
-------------------------------------------------------

### Version 2.0

##### Effective January 5th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

If the Company requests an investigative consumer report (as defined by state law) from a consumer reporting agency, you have the right to receive a complete and accurate disclosure of the nature and scope of the investigation requested by the Company. You also have the right to request a written summary of your rights and remedies under the Washington Fair Credit Reporting Act.

Massachusetts Disclosure
------------------------

### Version 1.0

##### Effective January 5th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

If the Company requests an investigative consumer report (as defined by state law) from a consumer reporting agency, you have the right to have a copy of the report upon request.

New Jersey Disclosure
---------------------

### Version 1.0

##### Effective January 5th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

If the Company requests an investigative consumer report (as defined by state law) from a consumer reporting agency, you have the right to have a copy of the report upon request.

Minnesota Disclosure
--------------------

### Version 1.0

##### Effective January 5th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

You have the right, upon written request, to receive a complete and accurate disclosure of the nature and scope of any consumer report ordered about you. A consumer reporting agency must make this disclosure within five (5) days of receipt of your request or of the Company's request for the report, whichever is later.

New Jersey Consumer Rights
--------------------------

### Version 1.0

##### Effective January 5th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**A SUMMARY OF YOUR RIGHTS UNDER THE NEW JERSEY FAIR CREDIT REPORTING ACT**

The state of New Jersey Fair Credit Reporting Act (NJFCRA) is designed to promote accuracy, fairness, consumer confidentiality and the proper use of credit data by each consumer reporting agency (“CRA”) in accordance with the requirements of the NJFCRA.

Under the NJFCRA an employer, before taking adverse employment action, is required to provide the applicant or employee with a summary of their rights under the NJFCRA with respect to consumer reports or investigative consumer reports obtained for employment purposes from a consumer reporting agency (CRA).

You can find the complete text of the NJCRA, N.J. Stat. §§56:11‐29‐ 56:11‐41, at the New Jersey State Legislature's web site ([http://www.njleg.state.nj.us/](http://www.njleg.state.nj.us/)). You may have additional rights under the federal Fair Credit Reporting Act, 15 U.S.C. 1681‐1681u, which is available on the Internet at the Federal Trade Commission’s website ([http://www.ftc.gov](http://www.ftc.gov/)).

* You must consent to the procurement for employment purposes of a report about you. Before an employer can obtain a report about you from a CRA, the employer must provide you with notice that it will request the report and obtain your consent to that request. A CRA may not give out information about you to your employer, or prospective employer, without your written consent.
* You must be told if information in your file has been used against you for employment purposes. An employer who uses information from a consumer or investigative consumer report to take action against you – such as denying an application for employment or terminating employment – must tell you that its decision is based in whole or in part on the report. The employer also must provide you with a description of your rights under the NJCRA and a reasonable opportunity to dispute with the CRA any information on which the employer relied.
* You can find out what is in your file. At your request, a CRA must give you the information in your file and a list of everyone who has recently requested your file. These disclosures may be made in person, over the telephone or by any other reasonable method available to the CRA.
* You can dispute inaccurate information with the CRA. If you tell a CRA that your file contains inaccurate information, the CRA must reinvestigate the disputed items, free of charge, within 30 days, unless the CRA determines that the dispute is frivolous or irrelevant. The CRA must give you a written report of the investigation. If the CRA's investigation does not resolve the dispute, you may add a brief statement to your file. If an item is deleted or a dispute statement is filed, you may ask that anyone who has recently received your report be notified of the change.
* Inaccurate information must be corrected or deleted. A CRA must remove or correct inaccurate or unverified information from its files within 30 days after you dispute it. If your dispute results in any change to your report, the CRA cannot reinsert into your file a disputed item unless the information source verifies its accuracy and completeness. In addition, the CRA must give you a written notice telling you it has reinserted the item. The notice must include the business name and address.
* You may seek damages from violators. If a CRA, a user or (in some cases) a provider of CRA data violates the NJFCRA, you may sue them in state court.

**For questions or concerns regarding the NJFCRA, please contact:**

Division of Consumer Affairs

Department of Law and Public Safety

124 Halsey Street

Newark, NJ 07102

Phone: 973‐504‐620

California Consumer Rights
--------------------------

### Version 1.0

##### Effective January 5th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**For California Residents Only**

**California Consumer Rights**

The following information may be obtained from Certn (Canada), Inc. and Certn (USA), Inc, 1006 Fort Street, Unit 300, Victoria, BC, Canada V8V 3K4. Our office hours are 9:00am to 5:00pm PTZ. Our telephone number is 844-987-0690. For complete information about Certn’s privacy practices, including whether your personal information will be sent outside of the U.S. or its territories, Certn’s privacy policy can be viewed at [https://certn.co/privacy-policy/](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/)

**CALIFORNIA CONSUMER RIGHTS**

You have rights when an investigative consumer report is obtained on you. The following are some of your rights:

1\. You have the right to contact the agency that made the report. You can do this in one of the following ways:

(a) You can go to the agency in person during the normal business hours and on reasonable notice. You can bring someone with you. You and that person may be required to present identification. You may be required to sign a paper allowing the agency to discuss your file with or to show your file to this person.

(b) You may receive your file by certified mail, if you have given written notice to the agency that you want information mailed to you or to another person you want to receive the file. You will be required to provide identification when you write for your file.

(c) You may be able to discuss your file over the telephone if you have given written instructions to the agency and have provided identification.

2\. You have the right to receive a copy of your file or your investigative consumer report at the agency. You may be charged up to $8.00 to obtain a copy of your report or file. However, you may receive a free copy if:

(a) Once during a twelve month period if you are unemployed and intend to seek employment within sixty (60) days or you receive public welfare assistance or you believe your file contains inaccurate information because of fraud.

(b) If you are receiving a copy from the agency relating to an investigation into the accuracy of information you have disputed or if information is put back into your file.

3\. You have the right to know the following information:

(a) The names of the persons and companies who have received a report about you in the last three (3) years. You may request their addresses and telephone numbers.

(b) Explanations of any codes or abbreviations used in your report, so you can understand the report.

4\. You have the right to dispute any information in your file. You must contact the agency directly to do so. The person who ordered a report is required to give you the name and address of the agency.

(a) The agency has thirty (30) days from the day it receives your dispute to complete the investigation.

(b) When the agency is done with the investigation, it must tell you of any changes made in the report as a result of the investigation.

(c) If the investigation does not remove the information disputed by you, you have the right to place your statement of the facts in your file. The agency has people to help you write the statement. The agency may limit your statement to five hundred (500) words.

(d) If information is removed or you add a statement to your file, you can request the agency to send the report, as changed or with your statement, to anyone who received the information in the last two (2) years.

(e) If information that is removed from your files is placed back in your file, you are entitled to receive written notice of that fact and you have the right to dispute the information added.

5\. You also have rights under federal law in regard to your report. A copy of those rights is given to you with this California statement of consumer rights. Many of these rights are also included within California law.

**Solo Para Residentes De California**

**Derechos del Consumidor de California**

**DERECHOS DEL CONSUMIDOR EN CALIFORNIA**

Usted tiene derechos cuando un reporte de investigación del consumidor es obtenido respecto a usted. Los siguientes son algunos de sus derechos:

1\. Usted tiene derecho de contactar la agencia que hizo el reporte y puede hacer èsto de las maneras siguientes:

(a) Puede ir a la agencia en persona durante horas normales de trabajo y en la nota razonable. Puede traer a un acompañante. Usted y esa persona debe traer una identificación. Es posible que tenga que firmar un documento en el que usted dará derecho a la agencia de discutir lo que está en su archivo o de mostrar el archivo a la persona que lo acompaña.

(b) Usted puede recibir su archivo por correspondencia certificada si es que avisó a la agencia por escrito que desea información por carta o desea que otra persona reciba su archivo. Por lo tanto, usted deberá proveer una identificación cuando solicite la información.

(c) Usted podrá platicar respecto a su archivo por telèfono si es que dió instrucciones por escrito a la agencia y presentó una identificación.

2\. Usted tiene derecho de recibir una copia de su archivo o de su reporte de investigación del consumidor en la agencia y se le puede cobrar hasta 8.00 dólares para obtener una copia de su reporte o archivo. De cualquier manera, usted podrá recibir una copia gratis en las siguientes circunstancias:

(a) Si es que durante doce meses usted está desempleado o tiene intenciones de buscar empleo durante 60 días o si usted recibe asistencia pública o cree que su archivo contiene información incorrecta debido a fraude.

(b) Si usted recibe una copia de la agencia relacionada con la nvestigación para verificar la exactitud de la información que usted reportó o si es que la información fuè regresada a su archivo.

3\. Usted tiene derecho de saber la siguiente información:

(a) Los nombres de personas y de compañías quienes han recibido un reporte respecto a usted en los últimos 3 años y puede solicitar sus domicilios y números de telèfono.

(b) Usted puede solicitar que se le explique códigos o abreviasiones utilizadas en su reporte para que usted lo pueda comprender con más claridad.

4\. Usted tiene derecho de reclamar cualquier información que estè en su archivo pero deberá contactar a la agencia directamente. La persona que ordenó el reporte deberá darle a usted el nombre y domicilio de la agencia.

(a) La agencia tiene 30 días para completar la investigación.

(b) Una vez terminada la investigación, la agencia debe informarle a usted de cualquier cambio que se haya hecho al reporte como resultado de la investigación.

(c) Si es que la investigación no elimina información reportada por usted, entonces tiene derecho de agregar su declaración en el archivo. La agencia tiene personal que le puede ayudar a escribir su declaración siempre y cuando no exceda quinientas (500) palabras.

(d) Si usted elimina o agrega información a su archivo puede pedirle a la agencia que mande el reporte como “Cambiado” o con su declaración a cualquierea que haya recibido la información en los últimos dos años.

(e) Si hay información que fuè eliminada de su archivo y despuès vuelta a poner, usted tiene derecho a recibir por escrito lo sucedido y tiene derecho a reclamar la información agregada.

5\. Tambièn tiene derechos bajo la ley federal respecto a su reporte. Se le dará una copia de esos derechos con èsta declaración de derechos del consumidor de California.

Maryland Credit Report Disclosure
---------------------------------

### Version 2.0

##### Effective January 5th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**NOTICE REGARDING CREDIT REPORT PURSUANT TO MARYLAND LAW**

{{{company\_name}}} (“the Company”) intends to obtain credit information about you from a consumer reporting agency for employment purposes. Thus, you can expect to be the subject of “credit reports” for employment purposes. Such reports may include information about your character, general reputation, personal characteristics, and mode of living. The reports obtained by the Company may be used as a factor in making employment decisions. The source of any credit report will be Certn (USA) Inc., 3820 Central Avenue #220, Cheyenne, WY 82001, 844-987-0690.

The Company intends to obtain a credit report on you for the bona fide purpose under Maryland law specified below:

* The job for which you are applying (or if current employee, already occupy) is managerial and involves setting the direction or control of a business or a department, division, unit or agency.
* The job for which you are applying (or if current employee, already occupy) involves access to personal information, as defined in § 14-3501 of the Maryland Commercial Law Article, of a customer, employee or employer, except for personal information customarily provided in a retail transaction.
* The job for which you are applying (or if current employee, already occupy) involves a fiduciary responsibility to the employer, including the authority to issue payments, collect debts, transfer money or enter into contracts.
* The job for which you are applying (or if current employee, already occupy) would entitle you to an expense account or a corporate debit or credit card.
* The job for which you are applying (or if current employee, already occupy) involves access to trade secrets or other confidential business information. Trade secrets include information about a formula, pattern, compilation, program, device, method, technique or process that: (1) derives independent economic value, actual or potential, from not being generally known to, and not being readily ascertainable by proper means by, other persons who can obtain economic value from the disclosure or use of the information; and (2) is the subject of efforts that are reasonable under the circumstances to maintain its secrecy.

Please acknowledge that you received and understood it and provide consent for the Company to obtain credit reports about you from a consumer reporting agency.

Connecticut Credit Report Disclosure
------------------------------------

### Version 1.0

##### Effective January 5th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**NOTICE REGARDING CREDIT REPORT PURSUANT TO CONNECTICUT LAW**

{{{company\_name}}} (“the Company”) intends to obtain credit information about you from a consumer reporting agency for employment purposes. Thus, you can expect to be the subject of “credit reports” for employment purposes. Such reports may include information about your character, general reputation, personal characteristics, and mode of living. The reports obtained by the Company may be used as a factor in making employment decisions. The source of any credit report will be Certn (USA) Inc., 3820 Central Avenue #220, Cheyenne, WY 82001, 844-987-0690.

The Company intends to obtain a credit report on you for the substantially job-related reason checked by the Company below:

* The job for which you are applying (or if current employee, already occupy) is a managerial position which involves setting the direction or control of a business, division, unit or an agency of a business.
* The job for which you are applying (or if current employee, already occupy) involves access to customers, employees or the employer's personal or financial information other than information customarily provided in a retail transaction.
* The job for which you are applying (or if current employee, already occupy) involves a fiduciary responsibility to the employer, including but not limited to, the authority to issue payments, collect debts, transfer money or enter into contracts.
* The job for which you are applying (or if current employee, already occupy) entitles you to receive an expense account or corporate debit or credit card.
* The job for which you are applying (or if current employee, already occupy) entails access to: (i) confidential or proprietary business information, or (ii) information, including a formula, pattern, compilation, program, device, method, technique, process or trade secret that: (a) derives independent economic value, actual or potential, from not being generally known to, and not being readily ascertainable by proper means by, other persons who can obtain economic value from the disclosure or use of the information; and (b) is the subject of efforts that are reasonable under the circumstances to maintain its secrecy.
* The job for which you are applying (or if current employee, already occupy) entails access to the employer's nonfinancial assets valued at two-thousand five hundred ($2,500) dollars or more, including but not limited to, museum and library collections, prescription drugs, and other pharmaceuticals. Applicant/Employee: Please sign and date this form below to acknowledge that you received and understood it and to provide consent for the Company to obtain credit reports about you from a consumer reporting agency.

Please acknowledge that you received and understood it and provide consent for the Company to obtain credit reports about you from a consumer reporting agency.

Colorado Credit Report Request
------------------------------

### Version 1.0

##### Effective January 5th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**NOTICE REGARDING CREDIT REPORT PURSUANT TO COLORADO LAW**

{{{company\_name}}} (“the Company”) intends to obtain credit information about you from a consumer reporting agency for employment purposes. Thus, you can expect to be the subject of “credit reports” for employment purposes. Such reports may include information about your character, general reputation, personal characteristics, and mode of living. The reports obtained by the Company may be used as a factor in making employment decisions. The source of any credit report will be Certn (USA) Inc., 3820 Central Avenue #220, Cheyenne, WY 82001, 844-987-0690.

The Company intends to obtain a credit report on you because such a report is substantially job-related, as specified below (see check marks):

* The job for which you are applying (or if current employee, already occupy) is an executive, management, or officer position, or qualifies as professional staff to executive and management personnel, and the position involves one or more of the following:
    * Setting the direction or control of a business or a department, division, unit or agency; or
    * A fiduciary responsibility to the employer; or
    * Access to customers’, employees’, or the employer's personal or financial information other than information customarily provided in a retail transaction; or
    * Authority to issue payments, collect debts, or enter into contracts  
        
* The job for which you are applying (or if current employee, already occupy) involves contracts with defense, intelligence, national security or space agencies of the federal government.
* The job for which you are applying (or if current employee, already occupy) is with a bank or financial institution.

Please acknowledge that you received and understood it and provide consent for the Company to obtain credit reports about you from a consumer reporting agency.

Social Media US Consent - HR - English
--------------------------------------

### Version 8.0

##### Effective February 6th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**SOCIAL MEDIA BACKGROUND CHECK AUTHORIZATION**

{{{company\_name}}} has elected to perform social media background checks on candidates using a third-party provider. This background check will perform a review of your public posts on social media as well as publicly available articles in which you are referenced from the web and news sources. This information is provided to us as a consumer report as defined under the Fair Credit Reporting Act (FCRA).  

By clicking the button below, I authorize {{{company\_name}}} and its designated agents and representatives to conduct a comprehensive review of any publicly available information (including written posts, photos, and any other information) on my social media profiles (including, for example, platforms such as LinkedIn, Facebook, Instagram, X and any other publicly available social media accounts) to generate a consumer report and/or an investigative consumer report which will be used for employment, promotion, reassignment or retention as an employee. I expressly consent to the collection and display of extracts of my public social media profiles, including written posts and photographs, as well as any publicly available articles, on my consumer report. I understand that I am not being asked or required to disclose my username(s) or password(s) for any social media accounts, grant access to any personal social media accounts, divulge any personal social media content, invite anyone or accept an invitation from anyone on social media, access any personal social media in the presence of an employer, use social media as a condition of employment, or change any privacy settings related to any of my social media accounts. I understand that, pursuant to the federal Fair Credit Reporting Act, if any adverse action is to be taken based upon the consumer report, a copy of the report and a summary of the consumer’s rights will be provided to me.  
.

This Agreement takes effect when I click the “Continue” button or checkbox presented with these terms. I represent to Certn that I am lawfully able to enter into this agreement.

By clicking the “Continue” button or checkbox, I also certify the information I provided on and in connection with this form is true, accurate and complete. I agree that this form in original, faxed, photocopied or electronic (including electronically signed) form, will be valid for any background reports that may be requested by or on behalf of {{{company\_name}}}.

Social Media US Consent - HR - French
-------------------------------------

### Version 4.0

##### Effective February 6th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**AUTHORISATION DE PROCEDER AVEC UNE VERIFICATION DES ANTÉCÉDENTS SUR LES RÉSEAUX SOCIAUX**

{{{company\_name}}} a élu de vérifier les antécédents de tous les candidats sur les réseaux sociaux en sollicitant l’usage d’un fournisseur tiers. Cette vérification des antécédents permettra à la compagnie de réviser et d’examiner vos annonce/publications publiques sur les réseaux sociaux ainsi que que les articles accessibles au public provenant du Web et de sources de nouvelles.Ces renseignements nous sont fournis à titre de rapport aux consommateurs au sens de la la Loi sur les rapports équitables en matière de crédit.

En cliquant sur le bouton ci-dessous, j'autorise et ses agents et représentants désignés à procéder à un examen complet de toute information publiquement disponible (y compris les messages écrits, les photos et toute autre information) sur mes profils de médias sociaux (y compris, par exemple, des plateformes telles que LinkedIn, Facebook, Instagram, X et tout autre compte de médias sociaux publiquement disponible) afin de générer un rapport de consommateur et/ou un rapport d'enquête sur le consommateur qui sera utilisé pour l'emploi, la promotion, la réaffectation ou le maintien en poste en tant qu'employé. Je consens expressément à la collecte et à l'affichage d'extraits de mes profils de médias sociaux publics, y compris les messages écrits et des photos, ainsi que tout article accessible au public, dans mon rapport sur le consommateur. Je comprends qu'il ne m'est pas demandé ni exigé de divulguer mon (mes) nom(s) d'utilisateur ou mot(s) de passe pour tout compte de média social, d'accorder l'accès à tout compte de média social personnel, de divulguer tout contenu de média social personnel, d'inviter ou d'accepter une invitation de sur les médias sociaux, d'accéder à tout média social personnel en présence d'un employeur, d'utiliser les médias sociaux comme condition d'emploi, ou de modifier tout paramètre de confidentialité lié à l'un de mes comptes de média social. Je comprends que, conformément à la loi fédérale Fair Credit Reporting Act, si une mesure défavorable doit être prise sur la base du rapport du consommateur, une copie du rapport et un résumé des droits du consommateur me seront fournis.

Le présent contrat entre en vigueur quand je clique sur le bouton continuer ou quand je coche la case avec ces termes. Je déclare à Certn que je peux légalement conclure cette entente. En cliquant sur le bouton ou la case à cocher « Continuer », je certifie également que les renseignements que j’ai fournis sur ce formulaire sont véridiques, exacts et complets. Je conviens que ce formulaire original, télécopié, photocopié ou électronique (y compris signé électriquement t) sera valide pour tous les rapports d’information qui peuvent être demandés par ou au nom de {{{company\_name}}}.

Washington Credit Report Disclosure
-----------------------------------

### Version 1.0

##### Effective January 13th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

Washington State Consumer Rights
--------------------------------

### Version 7.0

##### Effective February 14th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**STATE OF WASHINGTON**

**CONSUMER CREDIT REPORTING ACT**

**SUMMARY OF CONSUMER RIGHTS**

The State of Washington Fair Credit Reporting Act (WFCRA) promotes the accuracy, fairness, and privacy of information in the files of consumer reporting agencies. There are many types of consumer reporting agencies, including credit bureaus and specialty agencies (such as agencies that sell information about check writing histories, medical records, and rental history records).

Here is a summary of your major rights under the WFCRA. The WFCRA is modeled after the Federal Fair Credit Reporting Act. The same rights are provided under the Federal Fair Credit Reporting Act and you have received A Summary of Your Rights Under the Federal Fair Credit Reporting Act. You can get the complete text of WFCRA RCW 19.182, from the Washington Code Revisers Office, P.O. Box 40551, Olympia, WA, 98504, or online at [http://apps.leg.wa.gov/rcw/default.aspx?cite=19.182&full=true#19.182.070](http://apps.leg.wa.gov/rcw/default.aspx?cite=19.182&full=true#19.182.070).

* Under Washington law, we must convey your dispute to the source of the information within five business days after receiving your request for investigation. If we determine that the request is frivolous or irrelevant as defined by the Fair Credit Reporting Act, we will notify you within five business days of the reasons for our decision. The results of our investigation will be sent to you within five business days after the investigation is complete. If you request, we will provide you with the company name, address and telephone number of any person contacted during the investigation. If you believe that a law regulating consumer credit reporting has been violated, you may file a complaint with the Washington State Attorney General’s Office. Contact details are below.
* You must be told if information in your file has been used against you. If a person takes an adverse action against you that is based, in whole or in part, on information contained in a consumer report, that person must tell you, and must give you the name, address, and telephone number of the consumer reporting agency that provided the information.
* You have a right to know what is in your file. You may request and obtain all the information about you in the files of a consumer reporting agency, although medical information may be withheld and given directly to your medical provider. You will be required to provide proper identification, which may include your Social Security number. In many cases, the disclosure will be free. You will not be charged for:
    * a consumer report if a person has taken adverse action against you because of information in your credit report;
    * the reinvestigation of information you dispute; or
    * corrected reports resulting from the deletion of inaccurate or unverifiable information.

In addition, you are entitled to one free consumer report every 12 months, upon request.

* You may be charged a limited fee for a second or subsequent report requested by you during a 12 month period. You have a right to dispute incomplete or inaccurate information. If you identify information in your file that is incomplete or inaccurate, and you notify the consumer reporting agency directly of the dispute, the consumer reporting agency will reinvestigate without charge and record the current status of the disputed information before the end of thirty business days, unless your dispute is frivolous.
* Consumer reporting agencies must correct or delete inaccurate, incomplete, or unverifiable information. Upon completion of the reinvestigation, if the information you disputed is found to be inaccurate or cannot be verified, the consumer reporting agency will delete the information and notify you of the correction. If the reinvestigation does not resolve your dispute, you may file with the consumer reporting agency a brief statement setting forth the nature of your dispute. The statement will be placed in your consumer file and in any subsequent report containing the information you disputed.
* Consumer reporting agencies may not report outdated negative information. In most cases, a consumer reporting agency may not report negative information that is more than seven years old, or bankruptcies that are more than ten years old.
* Access to your file is limited. A consumer reporting agency may provide information about you only to people with a valid need – usually to consider an application with a creditor, insurer, employer, landlord, or other business. The WFCRA specifies those with a valid need for access.
* You must be notified if reports are provided to employers. A consumer reporting agency may not give out information about you to employers without your knowledge. A potential employer must make a clear and conspicuous disclosure in writing to you or obtain your consent before obtaining a report. A current employer may not receive a report unless it has given you written notice that consumer reports may be used for employment purposes.
* You may limit “prescreened” offers of credit and insurance you get based on information in your credit report. You may elect not to receive unsolicited “prescreened” offers for credit and insurance by using the consumer reporting agency’s notification system to remove your name and address from the lists these offers are based on. You may opt-out with the nationwide credit bureaus at 1-888-5-OPTOUT (1-888-567-8688).
* You may place a security freeze on your credit report. A security freeze prevents your credit file from being shared with potential creditors or insurance companies. You may request a security freeze by contacting MicroBilt Corporation at, Attn: Compliance Department, PO Box 440693, Kennesaw, GA 30160, or call the following number: 888-222-7621, or 800-884-4747 option# 5, or fax: 404-393-9512. We may charge a fee for providing this service.
* You may be able to block information resulting from identity theft from appearing on your credit report. If you are a victim of identity theft, a consumer reporting agency must permanently block misinformation resulting from that theft from appearing on your credit report. You must provide the consumer reporting agency with a copy of a police report as evidence of your claim before it can place the block on your report.
* You may seek damages from violators. If a consumer reporting agency, or in some cases, a user of consumer reports or a furnisher of information to a consumer reporting agency violates the WFCRA, you may be able to sue in state or federal co

**COMPLAINTS**

Any complaints by consumers under state law may be directed to:

Office of the Attorney General

Consumer Protection Division

800 5th Avenue, Suite 2000

Seattle, Washington 98104-3188

Phone 1-800-551-4636 or (206) 464-6684

Fax (206) 389-2801

Statewide Toll-Free TDD: 800 276-9883

Complaints May Be Made Via U.S. Mail or E-Mail

Complaints: [http://www.atg.wa.gov/FileAComplaint.aspx](http://www.atg.wa.gov/FileAComplaint.aspx)

(Include your U.S. Mail address with any complaint.)

Website & Forms: [http://www.atg.wa.gov/](http://www.atg.wa.gov/)

Combined Tenant Screening Disclosure and Authorization
------------------------------------------------------

### Version 15.0

##### Effective May 29th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**DISCLOSURE REGARDING BACKGROUND INVESTIGATION ON YOU**

**{{{company\_name}}}** (“the Company”) may obtain “consumer reports” about you from a consumer reporting agency for tenant screening purposes. A “consumer report” is a background screening report that may contain information regarding your social security number and identification documents, criminal history, sex offender registry status, credit history, employment history, education history, driving history, professional licenses, social media, drug testing results and other information about you. It may bear upon your character, general reputation, personal characteristics, and/or mode of living.

\[END OF DOCUMENT\]

**NOTICE REGARDING INVESTIGATIVE CONSUMER REPORTS**

**{{{company\_name}}}** (“the Company”) may also request an “investigative consumer report” on you from a consumer reporting agency.

An “investigative consumer report” is a background screening report generated through personal interviews with sources such as your neighbors, friends or associates.

The consumer reporting agency that may prepare an “investigative consumer report” on you for the Company is Certn (USA) Inc., 3820 Central Avenue #220, Cheyenne, WY 82001, 844-987-0690. The information contained in an “investigative consumer report” may bear upon your character, general reputation, personal characteristics, and/or mode of living.

Please be advised that the nature and scope of the most common form of investigative consumer report that may be ordered by the Company is an investigation into your tenant/rental history. During such an investigation, Certn may ask questions about your tenant/rental history to certain knowledgeable individuals and provide response information to the Company.

**Note: You have the right to request additional information regarding the nature and scope of any “investigative consumer report” ordered by the Company on you. You may do so by contacting the Company.**

\[END OF DOCUMENT\]

**ACKNOWLEDGMENT AND AUTHORIZATION REGARDING  
BACKGROUND INVESTIGATION**

By signing below, I acknowledge receipt of the following separate documents (and certify that I have read and understood them):

* DISCLOSURE REGARDING BACKGROUND INVESTIGATION ON YOU;
* A SUMMARY OF YOUR RIGHTS UNDER THE FAIR CREDIT REPORTING ACT;
* NOTICE REGARDING INVESTIGATIVE CONSUMER REPORTS; and
* ADDITIONAL STATE LAW NOTICES;

By signing below, I also authorize **{{{company\_name}}}** (“the Company”) to obtain “consumer reports” and “investigative consumer reports” about me for tenant screening purposes.

By signing below, I also authorize law enforcement agencies, learning institutions (including public and private schools, colleges and universities), information service bureaus, credit bureaus, data repositories, courts (federal, state and local), motor vehicle records agencies, my past or present employers, the military, and other public or private individuals and institutions to furnish any and all information on me that is requested by Certn, the consumer reporting agency preparing reports about me for **{{{company\_name}}}** . The information that can be disclosed to Certn includes, but is not limited to, criminal history, sex offender registry status, credit history, employment history, education history, driving history, and information regarding my professional licenses, social media, social security number, identification documents, and drug testing results.

\[END OF DOCUMENT\]

California Credit Report Disclosure
-----------------------------------

### Version 4.0

##### Effective January 17th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

NOTICE REGARDING CONSUMER CREDIT REPORT PURSUANT TO CALIFORNIA LAW

{{{company\_name}}} (“the Company”) intends to obtain credit information about you from a consumer credit reporting agency for employment purposes. Thus, you can expect to be the subject of “consumer credit reports” for employment purposes. Such reports may include information about your character, general reputation, personal characteristics, and mode of living. With respect to any consumer credit report from a consumer credit reporting agency, the Company may investigate your credit history. The reports obtained by the Company may be used as a factor in making employment decisions. The source of any “consumer credit report” (as that term is defined under California Law) will be Certn (USA) Inc., 3820 Central Avenue #220, Cheyenne, WY 82001, 844-987-0690. Information regarding Certn’s privacy practices (including information about whether any consumer personal information will be sent outside the U.S. or its territories) may be found at: [https://certn.co](https://certn.co/).

The Company intends to obtain a consumer credit report on you for the permissible purpose under California Labor Code 1024.5 checked by the Company below:

• The job for which you are applying (or if current employee, already occupy) is a managerial position.

• The job for which you are applying (or if current employee, already occupy) is with the state Department of Justice.

• The job for which you are applying (or if current employee, already occupy) is a sworn peace officer or other law enforcement position.

• The job for which you are applying (or if current employee, already occupy) is a position for which the information contained in the report is required by law to be disclosed or obtained.

• The job for which you are applying (or if current employee, already occupy) is a position that involves regular access, for any purpose other than the routine solicitation and processing of credit card applications in a retail establishment, to all of the following types of information of any one person:

(A) Bank or credit card account information;

(B) Social security number; and

(C) Date of birth.

• The job for which you are applying (or if current employee, already occupy) is a position in which you would be (any of the following):

(A) A named signatory on the bank or credit card account of the employer;

(B) Authorized to transfer money on behalf of the employer; and

(C) Authorized to enter into financial contracts on behalf of the employer.

• The job for which you are applying (or if current employee, already occupy) is a position that involves access to confidential or proprietary information, including a formula, pattern, compilation, program, device, method, technique, process or trade secret that: (i) derives independent economic value, actual or potential, from not being generally known to, and not being readily ascertainable by proper means by, other persons who may obtain economic value from the disclosure or use of the information, and (ii) is the subject of an effort that is reasonable under the circumstances to maintain secrecy of the information.

• The job for which you are applying (or if current employee, already occupy) is a position that involves regular access during the workday to cash totalling Ten Thousand ($10,000) Dollars or more and which belongs to the employer, a customer or client.

Applicant: Please acknowledge that you received and understood it and to provide consent for the Company to obtain consumer credit reports about you from a consumer credit reporting agency.

New Hampshire Disclosure Form (MVR)
-----------------------------------

### Version 3.1

##### Effective January 24th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**FOR NEW HAMPSHIRE CANDIDATES AND RESIDENTS ONLY STATE NOTICE REGARDING CONSUMER REPORTS FOR EMPLOYMENT**

For New Hampshire registered drivers: The authorization for motor vehicle driving records is valid for only two (2) years and is revocable at any time.

City and County of San Francisco Fair Chance Ordinance
------------------------------------------------------

### Version 13.0

##### Effective February 15th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

City of Los Angeles Fair Chance Initiative Disclosure
-----------------------------------------------------

### Version 8.0

##### Effective November 11th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

Non Criminal Consent - HR English
---------------------------------

### Version 4.0

##### Effective February 14th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

I understand and acknowledge that I am agreeing to this consent electronically and by doing so, to the extent permitted by applicable law:

(1) I hereby authorize Certn (and its designated representatives, as applicable) to collect, use, disclose and independently verify my Personal Information which may include, but is not limited to, my name, address, email address, date of birth, my education, employment history, earnings history, credit history, motor vehicle history, public criminal history and professional credentials (collectively, "Personal Information") for the purposes of delivering a background screening report in relation to my application for employment with the Employer.

(2) I acknowledge and agree that the Employer may collect, use and disclose the Personal Information for the purposes of evaluating my suitability for employment with the Employer;

(3) I also authorize Certn to (i) contact the relevant law enforcement agencies, educational institutions, information service bureaus, credit bureaus, public websites, data repositories, motor vehicle records agencies, as well as all other accessible private and public sector archives (including any other person, organization, or agency) and (ii) receive copies of verified results on me through any reasonable means including in writing, electronic transmission or over the phone;

(4) I understand and agree that, where my personal history requires background verifications to be carried out in countries where I have worked, studied, or resided, my Personal Information may be sent and verified in those relevant countries.

(5) I agree that an electronic copy of this consent is equally effective as an original signature for the purposes of validity, enforceability, and admissibility and authorize Certn to export this Background Screening Consent in a PDF document and present it to any of my referees which may request a proof of my consent for the purposes set out above;

(6) I acknowledge that I have read and understood Certn’s [Privacy Policy](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/) and hereby confirm that my consent is fully informed and freely given and I am aware that I can withdraw it at any time.

(7) I acknowledge that if I do not consent to Certn’s and/or the Employer’s collection, use and disclosure of the information, this may result in my conditional offer being void. Without a conditional offer, I will not have a relationship with the Employer for any purposes; and

(8) I acknowledge that if I am denied employment wholly or partly because of information received from a consumer reporting agency or credit information obtained from a person other than a consumer reporting agency, if required by law, the Employer and/or Certn will notify me of that fact and, upon request by me within the time limits required by the applicable legislation, shall inform me of the nature and source of the information where the information is furnished by a person other than a consumer reporting agency; or of the name and address of the consumer reporting agency, where the information is furnished by a consumer reporting agency, and any other information required by law.

If you have any questions about the collection, use, disclosure, or storage of your Personal Information or if you would like to request more information about Certn’s privacy policies and procedures, please contact Certn’s Privacy Officer at 1-844-987-0690 or [privacy@certn.co.](mailto:privacy@certn.co.)

Non Criminal Consent - HR French
--------------------------------

### Version 3.0

##### Effective January 24th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

Je comprends et reconnais que j’accepte ce consentement par voie électronique et, ce faisant, dans la mesure permise par la loi applicable:

(1) Par la présente, j’autorise Certn (et ses représentants désignés, le cas échéant) à recueillir, utiliser, divulguer et vérifier de manière indépendante mes renseignements personnels, qui peuvent comprendre, sans s’y limiter, mon nom, mon adresse, mon adresse électronique, ma date de naissance, mon parcours d’étude, mon historique professionnel, mes antécédents en matière de rémunération, mes antécédents en matière de crédit, mes antécédents en matière de véhicules à moteur, mes antécédents publics en matière de criminalité, mes informations accessibles au public sur les médias sociaux, et mes compétences professionnelles (collectivement, les « renseignements personnels ») dans le but de fournir un rapport de vérification des antécédents relativement à ma candidature auprès de l'Employeur.

(2) Je reconnais et j’accepte que l'Employeur puisse recueillir, utiliser et divulguer les renseignements personnels dans le but d’évaluer mon aptitude à travailler pour l'employeur;

(3) J’autorise également le Certn à (i) contacter les organismes d’application de la loi, les établissements d’enseignement, les bureaux de services d’information, les agences d’évaluation du crédit, les sites Web publics, les dépôts de données, les agences d’enregistrement des véhicules à moteur, ainsi que toutes les autres archives accessibles des secteurs privé et public (y compris toute autre personne, organisation ou agence) et (ii) à recevoir des copies des résultats vérifiés me concernant par tout moyen raisonnable, y compris par écrit, par transmission électronique ou par téléphone;

(4) Je comprends et j’accepte que, lorsque mes antécédents personnels nécessitent des vérifications dans des pays où j’ai travaillé, étudié ou résidé, mes renseignements personnels peuvent être envoyés et vérifiés dans ces pays pertinents.

(5) Je conviens du fait qu’une copie électronique du présent consentement a la même valeur qu’une signature originale aux fins de validité, d’applicabilité et d’admissibilité et j’autorise le Certn à exporter le présent consentement à la vérification des antécédents dans un document PDF et à le présenter à toute personne de référence qui pourrait demander une preuve de mon consentement aux fins énoncées ci-dessous;

(6) Je reconnais avoir lu et compris la Politique de confidentialité de Certn et confirme que mon consentement est pleinement informé et donné librement et je suis conscient(e) que je peux le retirer à tout moment.

(7) Je reconnais que le fait de ne pas consentir à la collecte, à l’utilisation et à la divulgation des renseignements personnels par le Certn et l'employeur peut entraîner l’annulation de mon offre conditionnelle d’emploi et dans ce cas, je n’aurai pas de relation d’emploi avec l'Employeur à quelque fin que ce soit; et,

(8) Je reconnais que si un emploi m’est refusé en tout ou en partie en raison d’information reçues d’une agence d’évaluation du crédit ou d’informations de crédit obtenues d’une personne autre qu’une agence d’évaluation du crédit, si la loi l’exige, l'Employeur et/ou Certn m’avertiront de ce fait et, sur demande de ma part dans les délais requis par la législation applicable, m’informeront de la nature et de la source des informations lorsque celles-ci sont fournies par une personne autre qu’une agence d’évaluation du crédit; ou du nom et de l’adresse de l’agence d’évaluation du crédit, lorsque l’information est fournie par une agence d’évaluation du crédit, et de toute autre information requise par la loi.

Pour toutes questions au sujet de la collecte, de l’utilisation, de la divulgation ou du stockage de vos renseignements personnels ou si vous souhaitez obtenir de plus amples informations sur les politiques et les procédures de Certn ou de l'employeur en matière de protection de la vie privée, veuillez communiquer avec le responsable de la protection des renseignements personnels de Certn en téléphonant au 1-844-987-0690 ou par courriel à [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co).  

Biometric Consent
-----------------

### Version 1.0

##### Effective February 1st 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**BIOMETRIC CONSENT**

I understand and consent freely that my picture will be collected and processed on behalf of Certn via a biometric system based on facial recognition technology to identify me in the photographs for the purpose of verifying my identity as part of my application.

Applicant/Employee: Please acknowledge that you received and understood it and provide consent.

Social Media US Consent - PM - English
--------------------------------------

### Version 3.0

##### Effective February 6th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**SOCIAL MEDIA BACKGROUND CHECK AUTHORIZATION**

{{{company\_name}}} has elected to perform social media background checks on candidates using a third-party provider. This background check will perform a review of your public posts on social media as well as publicly available articles in which you are referenced from the web and news sources. This information is provided to us as a consumer report as defined under the Fair Credit Reporting Act (FCRA).

By clicking the button below, I authorize {{{company\_name}}} and its designated agents and representatives to conduct a comprehensive review of any publicly available information (including written posts, photos and any other information) on my social media profiles (including, for example, platforms such as LinkedIn, Facebook, Instagram, X and any other publicly available social media accounts) to generate a consumer report and/or an investigative consumer report which will be used for tenant screening purposes. I expressly consent to the collection and display of extracts of my public social media profiles, including written posts and photographs, as well as any publicly available articles, on my consumer report. I understand that I am not being asked or required to disclose my username(s) or password(s) for any social media accounts, grant access to any personal social media accounts, divulge any personal social media content, invite anyone or accept an invitation from anyone on social media, access any personal social media in the presence of a landlord, or change any privacy settings related to any of my social media accounts. I understand that, pursuant to the federal Fair Credit Reporting Act, if any adverse action is to be taken based upon the consumer report, a copy of the report and a summary of the consumer’s rights will be provided to me.

This Agreement takes effect when I click the “Continue” button or checkbox presented with these terms. I represent to Certn that I am lawfully able to enter into this agreement.

By clicking the “Continue” button or checkbox, I also certify the information I provided on and in connection with this form is true, accurate and complete. I agree that this form in original, faxed, photocopied or electronic (including electronically signed) form, will be valid for any background reports that may be requested by or on behalf of {{{company\_name}}}.

\[END OF DOCUMENT\]

Social Media US Consent - PM - French
-------------------------------------

### Version 3.0

##### Effective February 6th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**AUTORISATION DE PROCÉDER AVEC UNE VÉRIFICATION DES ANTÉCÉDENTS SUR LES RÉSEAUX SOCIAUX**

{{{company\_name}}} a élu de vérifier les antécédents de tous les candidats sur les réseaux sociaux en sollicitant l’usage d’un fournisseur tiers. Cette vérification des antécédents permettra à la compagnie de réviser et d’examiner vos annonce/publications publiques sur les réseaux sociaux ainsi que que les articles accessibles au public provenant du Web et de sources de nouvelles.Ces renseignements nous sont fournis à titre de rapport aux consommateurs au sens de la la Loi sur les rapports équitables en matière de crédit

En cliquant sur le bouton ci-dessous, j'autorise et ses agents et représentants désignés à procéder à un examen complet de toute information publiquement disponible (y compris les messages écrits, les photos et toute autre information) sur mes profils de médias sociaux (y compris, par exemple, des plateformes telles que LinkedIn, Facebook, Instagram, X et tout autre compte de médias sociaux publiquement disponible) afin de générer un rapport de consommateur et/ou un rapport de consommateur d'enquête qui sera utilisé à des fins de sélection des locataires. Je consens expressément à la collecte et à l'affichage d'extraits de mes profils de médias sociaux publics, y compris les messages écrits et des photos, ainsi que tout article accessible au public, dans mon rapport sur le consommateur. Je comprends qu'il ne m'est pas demandé ni exigé de divulguer mon (mes) nom(s) d'utilisateur ou mot(s) de passe pour tout compte de média social, d'accorder l'accès à tout compte de média social personnel, de divulguer tout contenu de média social personnel, d'inviter ou d'accepter une invitation de sur les médias sociaux, d'accéder à tout média social personnel en présence d'un propriétaire, ou de modifier tout paramètre de confidentialité lié à l'un de mes comptes de média social. Je comprends que, conformément à la loi fédérale Fair Credit Reporting Act, si une mesure défavorable doit être prise sur la base du rapport du consommateur, une copie du rapport et un résumé des droits du consommateur me seront fournis.

Le présent contrat entre en vigueur quand je clique sur le bouton continuer ou quand je coche la case avec ces termes. Je déclare à Certn que je peux légalement conclure cette entente. En cliquant sur le bouton ou la case à cocher « Continuer », je certifie également que les renseignements que j’ai fournis sur ce formulaire sont véridiques, exacts et complets. Je conviens que ce formulaire original, télécopié, photocopié ou électronique (y compris signé électriquement t) sera valide pour tous les rapports d’information qui peuvent être demandés par ou au nom de {{{company\_name}}}

Background Screening Consent - HR - English
-------------------------------------------

### Version 3.0

##### Effective February 6th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

Background screening consent

Human Resources

I understand and acknowledge that I am agreeing to this consent electronically and by doing so, to the extent permitted by applicable law:

(1) I hereby authorize Certn (and its designated representatives, as applicable) to collect, use, disclose and independently verify my Personal Information which may include, but is not limited to, my name, address, email address, date of birth, my education, employment history, earnings history, credit history, motor vehicle history, public criminal history, publicly available social media information, and professional credentials (collectively, "Personal Information") for the purposes of delivering a background screening report in relation to my application for employment with the Employer.

(2) I acknowledge and agree that the Employer may collect, use and disclose the Personal Information for the purposes of evaluating my suitability for employment with the Employer;

(3) I also authorize Certn to (i) contact the relevant law enforcement agencies, educational institutions, information service bureaus, credit bureaus, public websites, data repositories, motor vehicle records agencies, as well as all other accessible private and public sector archives (including any other person, organization, or agency) and (ii) receive copies of verified results on me through any reasonable means including in writing, electronic transmission or over the phone;

(4) I understand and agree that, where my personal history requires background verifications to be carried out in countries where I have worked, studied, or resided, my Personal Information may be sent and verified in those relevant countries.

(5) I agree that an electronic copy of this consent is equally effective as an original signature for the purposes of validity, enforceability, and admissibility and authorize Certn to export this Background Screening Consent in a PDF document and present it to any of my referees which may request a proof of my consent for the purposes set out above;

(6) I acknowledge that I have read and understood Certn’s [Privacy Policy](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/) and hereby confirm that my consent is fully informed and freely given and I am aware that I can withdraw it at any time.

(7) I acknowledge that if I do not consent to Certn’s and/or the Employer collection, use and disclosure of the information, this may result in my conditional offer being void. Without a conditional offer, I will not have a relationship with the Employer for any purposes; and

(8) I acknowledge that if I am denied employment wholly or partly because of information received from a consumer reporting agency or credit information obtained from a person other than a consumer reporting agency, if required by law, the Employer and/or Certn will notify me of that fact and, upon request by me within the time limits required by the applicable legislation, shall inform me of the nature and source of the information where the information is furnished by a person other than a consumer reporting agency; or of the name and address of the consumer reporting agency, where the information is furnished by a consumer reporting agency, and any other information required by law.

If you have any questions about the collection, use, disclosure, or storage of your Personal Information or if you would like to request more information about Certn's privacy policies and procedures, please contact Certn’s Privacy Officer at 1-844-987-0690 or privacy@certn.co.

Background Screening Consent - HR - French
------------------------------------------

### Version 3.0

##### Effective February 6th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

CONSENTEMENT POUR LA Vérification des antécédents

Ressources Humaines

Je comprends et reconnais que j’accepte ce consentement par voie électronique et, ce faisant, dans la mesure permise par la loi applicable:

(1) Par la présente, j’autorise Certn (et ses représentants désignés, le cas échéant) à recueillir, utiliser, divulguer et vérifier de manière indépendante mes renseignements personnels, qui peuvent comprendre, sans s’y limiter, mon nom, mon adresse, mon adresse électronique, ma date de naissance, mon parcours d’étude, mon historique professionnel, mes antécédents en matière de rémunération, mes antécédents en matière de crédit, mes antécédents en matière de véhicules à moteur, mes antécédents publics en matière de criminalité, mes informations accessibles au public sur les médias sociaux, et mes compétences professionnelles (collectivement, les « renseignements personnels ») dans le but de fournir un rapport de vérification des antécédents relativement à ma candidature auprès de l'Employeur.

(2) Je reconnais et j’accepte que l'Employeur puisse recueillir, utiliser et divulguer les renseignements personnels dans le but d’évaluer mon aptitude à travailler pour l'employeur;

(3) J’autorise également le Certn à (i) contacter les organismes d’application de la loi, les établissements d’enseignement, les bureaux de services d’information, les agences d’évaluation du crédit, les sites Web publics, les dépôts de données, les agences d’enregistrement des véhicules à moteur, ainsi que toutes les autres archives accessibles des secteurs privé et public (y compris toute autre personne, organisation ou agence) et (ii) à recevoir des copies des résultats vérifiés me concernant par tout moyen raisonnable, y compris par écrit, par transmission électronique ou par téléphone;

(4) Je comprends et j’accepte que, lorsque mes antécédents personnels nécessitent des vérifications dans des pays où j’ai travaillé, étudié ou résidé, mes renseignements personnels peuvent être envoyés et vérifiés dans ces pays pertinents.

(5) Je conviens du fait qu’une copie électronique du présent consentement a la même valeur qu’une signature originale aux fins de validité, d’applicabilité et d’admissibilité et j’autorise le Certn à exporter le présent consentement à la vérification des antécédents dans un document PDF et à le présenter à toute personne de référence qui pourrait demander une preuve de mon consentement aux fins énoncées ci-dessous;

(6) Je reconnais avoir lu et compris la Politique de confidentialité de Certn et confirme que mon consentement est pleinement informé et donné librement et je suis conscient(e) que je peux le retirer à tout moment.

(7) Je reconnais que le fait de ne pas consentir à la collecte, à l’utilisation et à la divulgation des renseignements personnels par le Certn et l'employeur peut entraîner l’annulation de mon offre conditionnelle d’emploi et dans ce cas, je n’aurai pas de relation d’emploi avec l'Employeur à quelque fin que ce soit; et,

(8) Je reconnais que si un emploi m’est refusé en tout ou en partie en raison d’information reçues d’une agence d’évaluation du crédit ou d’informations de crédit obtenues d’une personne autre qu’une agence d’évaluation du crédit, si la loi l’exige, l'Employeur et/ou Certn m’avertiront de ce fait et, sur demande de ma part dans les délais requis par la législation applicable, m’informeront de la nature et de la source des informations lorsque celles-ci sont fournies par une personne autre qu’une agence d’évaluation du crédit; ou du nom et de l’adresse de l’agence d’évaluation du crédit, lorsque l’information est fournie par une agence d’évaluation du crédit, et de toute autre information requise par la loi.

Pour toutes questions au sujet de la collecte, de l’utilisation, de la divulgation ou du stockage de vos renseignements personnels ou si vous souhaitez obtenir de plus amples informations sur les politiques et les procédures de Certn ou de l'employeur en matière de protection de la vie privée, veuillez communiquer avec le responsable de la protection des renseignements personnels de Certn en téléphonant au 1-844-987-0690 ou par courriel à privacy@certn.co.

Background Screening Consent - PM - English
-------------------------------------------

### Version 7.0

##### Effective February 12th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

Background screening consent

Property Management

I understand and acknowledge that I am agreeing to this consent electronically and by doing so, to the extent permitted by applicable law:

(1) I hereby authorize Certn (and its designated representatives, as applicable) to collect and independently verify my Personal Information which may include, but is not limited to, my name, address, email address, date of birth, my references, earnings history, credit history, public criminal history, publicly available social media information, and professional credentials (collectively, “Personal Information”) for the purposes of delivering a background screening report in relation to my tenancy;

(2) I also authorize Certn to (i) contact the relevant law enforcement agencies, information service bureaus, credit bureaus, public websites, data repositories, as well as all other accessible private and public sector archives (including any other person, organization, or agency) and (ii) receive copies of verified results on me through any reasonable means including in writing, electronic transmission or over the phone;

(3) I understand and agree that, where my personal history requires background verifications to be carried out in countries where I have worked and/or resided, my Personal Information may be sent and verified in those relevant countries;

(4) I agree that an electronic copy of this consent is equally effective as an original signature for the purposes of validity, enforceability, and admissibility and authorize Certn to export this Background Screening Consent in a PDF document and present it to any of my referees which may request a proof of my consent for the purposes set out above;

(5) I acknowledge that I have read and understood Certn’s Privacy Policy and hereby confirm that my consent is fully informed and freely given and I am aware that I can withdraw it at any time.

Background Screening Consent - PM - French
------------------------------------------

### Version 1.0

##### Effective February 3rd 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

CONSENTEMENT POUR LA Vérification des antécédents

Gestion Immobilière

Je comprends et reconnais que j'accepte ce consentement par voie électronique et, ce faisant, dans la mesure permise par la loi applicable:

(1) J'autorise par la présente Certn (et ses représentants désignés, le cas échéant) à recueillir et à vérifier de manière indépendante mes renseignements personnels qui peuvent inclure, sans s'y limiter, mon nom, mon adresse, mon adresse électronique, ma date de naissance, mes références, mes antécédents de revenus, mon historique de crédit, mes antécédents publics en matière de criminalité, mes informations accessibles au public sur les médias sociaux, et mes compétences professionnelles (collectivement dénommés, les «renseignements personnels») dans le but de délivrer un rapport de vérification des antécédents en rapport avec ma location;

(2) J'autorise également Certn à (i) contacter les organismes d'application de la loi, les bureaux de service d'information, les bureaux de crédit, les sites Web publics, les entrepôts de données, ainsi que toutes les autres archives accessibles des secteurs privé et public (y compris toute autre personne, organisation ou agence) et (ii) recevoir des copies des résultats vérifiés sur moi par tout moyen raisonnable, y compris par écrit, par transmission électronique ou par téléphone;

(3) Je comprends et j'accepte que, lorsque mon histoire personnelle nécessite des vérifications d'antécédents dans les pays où j'ai travaillé et/ou résidé, mes informations personnelles peuvent être envoyées et vérifiées dans les pays concernés;

(4) J'accepte qu'une copie électronique du présent consentement a la même valeur qu'une signature originale aux fins de validité, d'applicabilité et de recevabilité et j'autorise Certn à exporter le présent consentement à la vérification des antécédents dans un document PDF et à le présenter à l'une de mes références qui pourrait demander une preuve de mon consentement aux fins énoncées ci-dessus;

(5) Je reconnais avoir lu et compris la Politique de confidentialité de Certn et confirme par la présente que mon consentement est pleinement éclairé et donné librement, et je suis conscient que je peux le révoquer à tout moment.

Disclosure Scotland specific Consent - HR - English
---------------------------------------------------

### Version 7.0

##### Effective December 11th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

Please review all statements below to allow us to apply for your criminal record check from Disclosure Scotland:

1. I have read the [Disclosure Scotland Privacy Policy for Applicants](https://www.mygov.scot/privacy/?via=http://www.disclosurescotland.co.uk/about/PrivacyPolicyandDisclaimer.htm) and I understand how Disclosure Scotland will process my personal data.
2. I consent to Certn, submitting an application to Disclosure Scotland on my behalf for a basic disclosure certificate.
3. I also consent to Certn, receiving and viewing my basic disclosure certificate prior to me seeing it.  

Questions, queries and comments in relation to how Disclosure Scotland process personal information are welcome and should be addressed to their Data Protection Officer at [DSDPO@gov.scot](mailto://DSDPO@gov.scot).

DBS Consent - HR - English
--------------------------

### Version 6.0

##### Effective March 13th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

Please review all statements below to allow us to apply for your criminal record check from the DBS:

1. I have read the basic [DBS Check Processing Privacy Policy](https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/basic-dbs-check-privacy-policy) for Applicants and I understand how the DBS will process my personal data.
2. I have provided complete and true information in support of the application and I understand that knowingly making a false statement for this purpose is a criminal offence.
3. I consent to Certn, submitting an application to DBS on my behalf for a basic DBS certificate.
4. I also consent to Certn receiving and viewing my basic disclosure certificate prior to me seeing it, and to the DBS providing an electronic result directly to the Responsible Organisation (i.e Certn) that submits my application. I understand that an electronic result contains a message that indicates either the certificate does not contain criminal record information or to await certificate which will indicate that my certificate contains criminal record information. In some cases the Responsible Organisation may provide this information directly to my employer prior to me receiving my certificate. I understand that if I do not consent to Certn receiving an electronic result, I must not proceed with this application and I should apply directly to the DBS.

To withdraw your consent whilst the application is in progress you can contact the DBS helpline 03000 200 190. You can also contact Certn [uk-support@certn.co](mailto:uk-support@certn.co). If your certificate has not yet been issued, your application will then be withdrawn.

Consent (collect, process and report) - EN
------------------------------------------

### Version 25.2

##### Effective November 24th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**AUTHORIZATION**

To evaluate your suitability for {{purpose}} , {{company\_name}} (the "**Company**") has asked [Certn](https://certn.co/) to assemble and return a consumer report (your "**Report**") consisting of: {{services\_list}} .

Certn will collect the following personal information for the purpose of completing the Report: {{personal\_information\_list}} . {{#if data\_providers\_list}}Certn may collect Personal Information directly from you, the Company or third parties such as {{data\_providers\_list}} {{else}} Certn may collect Personal Information directly from you or the Company{{/if}}. Certn will compare information received from different sources for consistency.

It may be necessary for Certn to transfer and process Personal Information in multiple jurisdictions, specifically if you have lived, worked or attended school outside of the jurisdiction in which the Company has ordered the Report. Your Personal Information may be handled by our employees and contractors in Canada, Australia, the U.S., the U.K., South Africa, and the Philippines. Regardless of where Personal Information is processed, it will be handled in accordance with our privacy and security policies.

You can withdraw your consent, dispute the accuracy of a Report, or ask for a correction, deletion or copy of your Report at any time by contacting Certn’s Privacy at 1-844-987-0690 or [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co). Further information regarding the collection, use, disclosure, or storage of your Personal Information can be found [here](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/).

International Criminal Consent
------------------------------

### Version 2.0

##### Effective March 22nd 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**BACKGROUND SCREENING CONSENT**

International

I understand and acknowledge that I am agreeing to this consent electronically in connection with the written screening request provided to me on behalf of my current or prospective employer, as identified therein (“Employer”) and by doing so, to the extent permitted by applicable law:

(1) I hereby authorize Certn (and its designated representatives, as applicable) to collect and independently verify only the necessary Personal Information which may include, but is not limited to, my name, address, email address, date of birth, my criminal history, my public criminal history and professional credentials (collectively, “Personal Information”) for the purposes of delivering a background screening report to my Employer in relation to my current or prospective employment.

(2) I also authorize Certn to (i) contact the relevant government departments, law enforcement agencies, data repositories, public websites, as well as all other accessible private and public sector archives on my behalf to perform a criminal records check on me; and (ii) receive copies of verified results through any reasonable means including in writing, electronic transmission, over the phone or at their postal address, and communicate the results to my prospective employer.

(3) I understand my background check may include the processing of sensitive Personal Information and acknowledge and agree that where my personal history requires verifications to be carried out in countries where I have worked and/or resided, my data may be sent and processed in those relevant countries for the delivery of the requested verification/s.

(4) I agree that an electronic copy of this consent is equally effective as an original signature for the purposes of validity, enforceability, and admissibility and authorize Certn to export this Background Screening Consent in a PDF document and present it to any of my referees which may request a proof of my consent for the purposes set out above.

(5) I acknowledge that I have read and understood Certn’s [Privacy Policy](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/) and hereby confirm that my consent is fully informed and freely given and I am aware that I can withdraw it at any time.

Canadian Criminal Consent - Generic
-----------------------------------

### Version 4.0

##### Effective March 21st 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

To the extent permitted by applicable law, I hereby consent to a search of all records and information available at the time the search is conducted, including non-conviction information, charges before the courts, findings of guilt or convictions and court orders registered in my name in the National Repository of Criminal Records, the Canadian Police Information Centre (“CPIC”) database and local records available to the police service for the purposes of delivering a background screening report in relation to my application for employment with the Employer (“the Employer”). The query may also include a search of court records and a query of records management systems in other police agencies' jurisdictions through the Police Information Portal (PIP) or other data sharing systems.

I understand that this criminal record check is based on my identity verification including, but not limited to the name(s), date of birth and where used, the declared criminal record history provided by myself.

I acknowledge that for the completion of the criminal record check, reported criminal records may require me to provide fingerprints.

I acknowledge and agree that the Employer may collect, use and disclose the information collected for the purposes of evaluating my suitability for employment with the Employer.

I acknowledge that I have read and understood Certn’s [Privacy Policy](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/) and hereby confirm that my consent is fully informed and freely given and I am aware that I can withdraw it at any time.

I acknowledge that if I do not consent to Certn’s and/or the Employer collection, use and disclosure of the information, this may result in my conditional offer of employment being void. Without a conditional offer of employment, I will not have an employment relationship with the Employer for any purposes.

You may request more information about the nature and scope of any criminal record checks to be conducted by contacting Certn’s Privacy Officer at 1-844-987-0690 or [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co).

Canadian Criminal Consent - Generic (FR)
----------------------------------------

### Version 3.0

##### Effective March 22nd 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

Dans la mesure où la loi applicable le permet, je consens par la présente à une recherche de tous les dossiers et renseignements disponibles me concernant au moment où la recherche est effectuée, y compris les renseignements sur les non-condamnations, les accusations portées devant les tribunaux, les déclarations de culpabilité ou les condamnations et les ordonnances judiciaires enregistrées à mon nom dans le Répertoire national des casiers judiciaires, la base de données du Centre d’information de la police canadienne (CIPC) et les dossiers locaux dont dispose le service de police dans le but de fournir un rapport de vérification des antécédents relativement à ma demande d’emploi auprès de l'Employeur (« l’Employeur »). La requête peut également comprendre une recherche dans les dossiers judiciaires et une interrogation des systèmes de gestion des dossiers dans les juridictions d’autres services de police par le biais du Portail d’informations policières (PIP) ou d’autres systèmes de partage de données.

Je comprends que cette vérification du casier judiciaire est basée sur la vérification de mon identité, y compris, mais sans s’y limiter, le(s) nom(s), la date de naissance et, le cas échéant, les antécédents judiciaires que j’aurais déclarés moi-même.

Je reconnais que pour compléter la vérification du casier judiciaire, les antécédents criminels déclarés peuvent exiger que je fournisse des empreintes digitales.

Je reconnais et accepte que l'Employeur puisse collecter, utiliser et divulguer les informations recueillies dans le but d’évaluer mon aptitude à l’emploi chez l'Employeur.

Je reconnais avoir lu et compris la [Politique de confidentialité](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/) de Certn et confirme que mon consentement est pleinement informé et donné librement et je suis conscient(e) que je peux le retirer à tout moment.

Je reconnais que le fait de ne pas consentir à la collecte, à l’utilisation et à la divulgation de ces renseignements par Certn et/ou l'Employeur pourrait entraîner l’annulation de mon offre d’emploi conditionnelle. Dans ce cas, je n’aurai pas de relation d’emploi avec l'Employeur à quelque fin que ce soit.

Vous pouvez demander de plus amples informations sur la nature et la portée des vérifications du casier judiciaire qui seront effectuées en téléphonant au responsable de la protection des renseignements personnels de Certn au 1 844 987-0690 ou par courriel à [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co).

International Criminal Consent (FRENCH)
---------------------------------------

### Version 2.0

##### Effective March 21st 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

Je comprends et reconnais que j'accepte ce consentement par voie électronique dans le cadre de la demande de présélection écrite qui m'a été fournie au nom de mon employeur actuel ou potentiel, tel qu'identifié dans celle-ci ("Employeur") et, ce faisant, dans la mesure permise par la loi:

(1) J'autorise par la présente Certn (et ses représentants désignés, le cas échéant) à collecter et à vérifier de manière indépendante uniquement les informations personnelles nécessaires qui peuvent inclure, mais sans s'y limiter, mon nom, mon adresse, mon adresse e-mail, ma date de naissance, mon nom d'utilisateur historique, mes antécédents criminels publics et mes références professionnelles (collectivement, les «informations personnelles») aux fins de fournir un rapport de vérification des antécédents à mon employeur en relation avec mon emploi actuel ou potentiel.

(2) J'autorise également le Certn à (i) contacter en mon nom les services gouvernementaux concernés, les organismes chargés de l'application des lois, les référentiels de données, les sites Web publics, ainsi que toutes les autres archives accessibles des secteurs privé et public pour effectuer une vérification de mon casier judiciaire ; et (ii) recevoir des copies des résultats vérifiés par tout moyen raisonnable, y compris par écrit, par transmission électronique, par téléphone ou à leur adresse postale, et communiquer les résultats à mon futur employeur.

(3) Je comprends que la vérification de mes antécédents peut inclure le traitement d'informations personnelles sensibles et je reconnais et accepte que lorsque mes antécédents personnels nécessitent des vérifications dans les pays où j'ai travaillé et/ou résidé, mes données peuvent être envoyées et traitées dans ces pays pertinents pour la fourniture de la ou des vérifications demandées.

(4) J'accepte qu'une copie électronique du présent consentement a la même valeur qu'une signature originale aux fins de validité, d'applicabilité et de recevabilité et j'autorise Certn à exporter le présent consentement à la vérification des antécédents dans un document PDF et à le présenter à l'une de mes références qui pourrait demander une preuve de mon consentement aux fins énoncées ci-dessus.

(5) Je reconnais avoir lu et compris la Politique de confidentialité de Certn et confirme par la présente que mon consentement est pleinement éclairé et donné librement, et je suis conscient que je peux le révoquer à tout moment.

UBER Background Screening Consent - HR - English
------------------------------------------------

### Version 3.0

##### Effective April 11th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

I understand and acknowledge that I am agreeing to this consent electronically and by doing so, to the extent permitted by applicable law:

(1) I hereby authorize Certn (and its designated representatives, as applicable) to collect, use, disclose and independently verify my Personal Information which may include, but is not limited to, my name, address, email address, date of birth, motor vehicle history, public criminal history, and my right to work (collectively, "Personal Information") for the purposes of delivering a background screening report in relation to my signing up to use Uber’s software platform as a driver, delivery person, and/or shopper.

(2) I acknowledge and agree that Uber may collect, use and disclose the Personal Information for the purposes of evaluating whether I meet the applicable safety requirements to provide services using Uber’s platform;

(3) I also authorize Certn to (i) contact the relevant law enforcement agencies, information service bureaus, credit bureaus, public websites, data repositories, motor vehicle records agencies, as well as all other necessary private and public sector archives and (ii) receive copies of verified results on me through any reasonable means including in writing, electronic transmission or over the phone;  

(4) I understand and agree that, where my personal history requires background verifications to be carried out in countries where I have worked, studied, or resided, my Personal Information may be sent and verified in those relevant countries.

(5) I agree that an electronic copy of this consent is equally effective as an original signature for the purposes of validity, enforceability, and admissibility and authorize Certn to export this Background Screening Consent in a PDF document and present it to any of the agencies which may request a proof of my consent for the purposes set out above;

(6) I acknowledge that I have read and understood Certn’s [Privacy Policy](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/) and hereby confirm that my consent is fully informed and freely given and I am aware that I can withdraw it at any time;

; and

(7) I acknowledge that if I am denied access to Uber’s platform wholly or partly because of information received from a consumer reporting agency or credit information obtained from a person other than a consumer reporting agency, if required by law, the Uber and/or Certn will notify me of that fact and, upon request by me within the time limits required by the applicable legislation, shall inform me of the nature and source of the information where the information is furnished by a person other than a consumer reporting agency; or of the name and address of the consumer reporting agency, where the information is furnished by a consumer reporting agency, and any other information required by law.

If you have any questions about the collection, use, disclosure, or storage of your Personal Information or if you would like to request more information about Certn's privacy policies and procedures, please contact Certn’s Privacy Officer at 1-844-987-0690 or privacy@certn.co.

Aritzia - FCRA Authorization
----------------------------

### Version 1.0

##### Effective March 23rd 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**AUTHORIZATION REGARDING BACKGROUND INVESTIGATION**

By signing below, I acknowledge receipt of the following separate documents (and certify that I have read and understood them):

* DISCLOSURE REGARDING BACKGROUND INVESTIGATION ON YOU;
* A SUMMARY OF YOUR RIGHTS UNDER THE FAIR CREDIT REPORTING ACT;
* ADDITIONAL NOTICE REGARDING INVESTIGATIVE CONSUMER REPORTS ON YOU;
* ADDITIONAL STATE LAW NOTICES.

By signing below, I also authorize domestic and international law enforcement agencies, learning institutions (including public and private schools, colleges and universities), information service bureaus, credit bureaus, data repositories, courts (federal, state and local), motor vehicle records agencies, my past or present employers, the military, and other public or private individuals and institutions to furnish any and all information on me that is requested by Certn, the consumer reporting agency preparing reports about me for **{{{company\_name}}}** . I agree that where my personal history requires verifications to be carried out in countries where I have worked and/or resided, my data may be sent and processed in those relevant countries for the delivery of the requested verifications. The information that can be disclosed to Certn includes, but is not limited to, criminal history, sex offender registry status, credit history, employment history, education history, driving history, and information regarding my professional licenses, social security number, identification documents, and drug testing results.

By signing below, I also authorize **{{{company\_name}}}** to obtain "**consumer reports**" and "**investigative consumer reports**" about me for employment purposes at any time during the hiring process and throughout my employment, if applicable.

\[END OF DOCUMENT\]

Aritzia - FCRA Disclosure
-------------------------

### Version 1.0

##### Effective March 23rd 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**DISCLOSURE REGARDING BACKGROUND**

INVESTIGATION ON YOU

**{{{company\_name}}}** ("the Company") may obtain "consumer reports" about you from a consumer reporting agency for employment purposes. A "consumer report" is a background screening report that may contain information regarding your domestic and international background history, including but not limited to, your social security number and identification documents, criminal history, sex offender registry status, credit history, employment history, education history, driving history, professional licenses, drug testing results and other information about you. It may bear upon your character, general reputation, personal characteristics, and/or mode of living.  

\[END OF DOCUMENT\]

Aritzia - California Disclosure Form and California State Rights
----------------------------------------------------------------

### Version 1.0

##### Effective March 23rd 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**NOTICE REGARDING BACKGROUND INVESTIGATION**

**PURSUANT TO CALIFORNIA LAW**

**(For California Applicants and Employees Only)**

**{{{company\_name}}}** ("the Company") intends to obtain information about you from an investigative consumer reporting agency for employment purposes. Thus, you can expect to be the subject of "investigative consumer reports" obtained for employment purposes. Such reports may include information about your character, general reputation, personal characteristics, and mode of living. With respect to any investigative consumer report from an investigative consumer reporting agency ("ICRA"), the Company may investigate the information contained in your employment application and other background information about you, including but not limited to: your social security number and identification documents, criminal history, sex offender registry status, credit history, employment history, education history, driving history, professional licenses, drug testing results. The Company may also obtain comments from individuals who are knowledgeable about you . These reports may be used as a factor in making employment decisions. The source of any investigative consumer report (as that term is defined under California law) will be Certn (USA) Inc., 3820 Central Avenue #220, Cheyenne, WY 82001, 844-987-0690. Information regarding Certn's privacy practices (including information about whether any consumer personal information will be sent outside the U.S. or its territories) may be found at https: // certn . co / .

Under California Civil Code section 1786.22, you are entitled to find out from an ICRA what is in the ICRA's file on you with proper identification, as follows:

In person, by visual inspection of your file during normal business hours and upon reasonable notice. You also may request a copy of the information in person. The ICRA may not charge you more than the actual copying costs for providing you with a copy of your file.

* By requesting a copy be sent to a specified addressee by certified mail. ICRAs complying with requests for certified mailings shall not be liable for disclosures to third parties caused by mishandling of mail after such mailings leave the ICRAs.

A summary of all information contained in the ICRA's file on you (which is required to be provided

by the California Civil Code) will be provided to you via telephone, if you have made a written request for telephone disclosure and the toll charge, if any, for the telephone call is prepaid by or charged directly to you.

"Proper Identification" includes documents such as a valid driver's license, social security account number, military identification card, and credit cards. Only if you cannot identify yourself with such information may the ICRA require additional information concerning your employment and personal or family history in order to verify your identity.

The ICRA will provide trained personnel to explain any information furnished to you and will provide a written explanation of any coded information contained in files maintained on you. This written explanation will be provided whenever a file is provided to you for visual inspection.

You may be accompanied by one other person of your choosing, who must furnish reasonable identification. An ICRA may require you to furnish a written statement granting permission to the ICRA to discuss your file in such person's presence.

\[END OF DOCUMENT\]

**For California Residents Only**

**California Consumer Rights**

The following information may be obtained from Certn (Canada), Inc. and Certn (USA), Inc, 1006 Fort Street, Unit 300, Victoria, BC, Canada V8V 3K4. Our office hours are 9:00am to 5:00pm PTZ. Our telephone number is 844-987-0690. For complete information about Certn’s privacy practices, including whether your personal information will be sent outside of the U.S. or its territories, Certn’s privacy policy can be viewed at [https://certn.co/privacy-policy/](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/)

**CALIFORNIA CONSUMER RIGHTS**

You have rights when an investigative consumer report is obtained on you. The following are some of your rights:

1\. You have the right to contact the agency that made the report. You can do this in one of the following ways:

(a) You can go to the agency in person during the normal business hours and on reasonable notice. You can bring someone with you. You and that person may be required to present identification. You may be required to sign a paper allowing the agency to discuss your file with or to show your file to this person.

(b) You may receive your file by certified mail, if you have given written notice to the agency that you want information mailed to you or to another person you want to receive the file. You will be required to provide identification when you write for your file.

(c) You may be able to discuss your file over the telephone if you have given written instructions to the agency and have provided identification.

2\. You have the right to receive a copy of your file or your investigative consumer report at the agency. You may be charged up to $8.00 to obtain a copy of your report or file. However, you may receive a free copy if:

(a) Once during a twelve month period if you are unemployed and intend to seek employment within sixty (60) days or you receive public welfare assistance or you believe your file contains inaccurate information because of fraud.

(b) If you are receiving a copy from the agency relating to an investigation into the accuracy of information you have disputed or if information is put back into your file.

3\. You have the right to know the following information:

(a) The names of the persons and companies who have received a report about you in the last three (3) years. You may request their addresses and telephone numbers.

(b) Explanations of any codes or abbreviations used in your report, so you can understand the report.

4\. You have the right to dispute any information in your file. You must contact the agency directly to do so. The person who ordered a report is required to give you the name and address of the agency.

(a) The agency has thirty (30) days from the day it receives your dispute to complete the investigation.

(b) When the agency is done with the investigation, it must tell you of any changes made in the report as a result of the investigation.

(c) If the investigation does not remove the information disputed by you, you have the right to place your statement of the facts in your file. The agency has people to help you write the statement. The agency may limit your statement to five hundred (500) words.

(d) If information is removed or you add a statement to your file, you can request the agency to send the report, as changed or with your statement, to anyone who received the information in the last two (2) years.

(e) If information that is removed from your files is placed back in your file, you are entitled to receive written notice of that fact and you have the right to dispute the information added.

5\. You also have rights under federal law in regard to your report. A copy of those rights is given to you with this California statement of consumer rights. Many of these rights are also included within California law.

**Solo Para Residentes De California  
**

**Derechos del Consumidor de California**

**DERECHOS DEL CONSUMIDOR EN CALIFORNIA**

Usted tiene derechos cuando un reporte de investigación del consumidor es obtenido respecto a usted. Los siguientes son algunos de sus derechos:

1\. Usted tiene derecho de contactar la agencia que hizo el reporte y puede hacer èsto de las maneras siguientes:

(a) Puede ir a la agencia en persona durante horas normales de trabajo y en la nota razonable. Puede traer a un acompañante. Usted y esa persona debe traer una identificación. Es posible que tenga que firmar un documento en el que usted dará derecho a la agencia de discutir lo que está en su archivo o de mostrar el archivo a la persona que lo acompaña.

(b) Usted puede recibir su archivo por correspondencia certificada si es que avisó a la agencia por escrito que desea información por carta o desea que otra persona reciba su archivo. Por lo tanto, usted deberá proveer una identificación cuando solicite la información.

(c) Usted podrá platicar respecto a su archivo por telèfono si es que dió instrucciones por escrito a la agencia y presentó una identificación.

2\. Usted tiene derecho de recibir una copia de su archivo o de su reporte de investigación del consumidor en la agencia y se le puede cobrar hasta 8.00 dólares para obtener una copia de su reporte o archivo. De cualquier manera, usted podrá recibir una copia gratis en las siguientes circunstancias:

(a) Si es que durante doce meses usted está desempleado o tiene intenciones de buscar empleo durante 60 días o si usted recibe asistencia pública o cree que su archivo contiene información incorrecta debido a fraude.

(b) Si usted recibe una copia de la agencia relacionada con la nvestigación para verificar la exactitud de la información que usted reportó o si es que la información fuè regresada a su archivo.

3\. Usted tiene derecho de saber la siguiente información:

(a) Los nombres de personas y de compañías quienes han recibido un reporte respecto a usted en los últimos 3 años y puede solicitar sus domicilios y números de telèfono.

(b) Usted puede solicitar que se le explique códigos o abreviasiones utilizadas en su reporte para que usted lo pueda comprender con más claridad.

4\. Usted tiene derecho de reclamar cualquier información que estè en su archivo pero deberá contactar a la agencia directamente. La persona que ordenó el reporte deberá darle a usted el nombre y domicilio de la agencia.

(a) La agencia tiene 30 días para completar la investigación.

(b) Una vez terminada la investigación, la agencia debe informarle a usted de cualquier cambio que se haya hecho al reporte como resultado de la investigación.

(c) Si es que la investigación no elimina información reportada por usted, entonces tiene derecho de agregar su declaración en el archivo. La agencia tiene personal que le puede ayudar a escribir su declaración siempre y cuando no exceda quinientas (500) palabras.

(d) Si usted elimina o agrega información a su archivo puede pedirle a la agencia que mande el reporte como “Cambiado” o con su declaración a cualquierea que haya recibido la información en los últimos dos años.

(e) Si hay información que fuè eliminada de su archivo y despuès vuelta a poner, usted tiene derecho a recibir por escrito lo sucedido y tiene derecho a reclamar la información agregada.

5\. Tambièn tiene derechos bajo la ley federal respecto a su reporte. Se le dará una copia de esos derechos con èsta declaración de derechos del consumidor de California.

UBER - Background Screening Consent - HR - French
-------------------------------------------------

### Version 3.0

##### Effective April 13th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

Je comprends et reconnais que j’accepte ce consentement par voie électronique et, ce faisant, dans la mesure permise par la loi applicable:  

(1) Par la présente, j’autorise Certn (et ses représentants désignés, le cas échéant) à recueillir, utiliser, divulguer et vérifier de manière indépendante mes renseignements personnels, qui peuvent comprendre, sans s’y limiter, mon nom, mon adresse, mon adresse électronique, ma date de naissance, mes antécédents en matière de véhicules à moteur, mes antécédents publics en matière de criminalité, et mon droit de travailler (collectivement, les « renseignements personnels ») dans le but de fournir un rapport de vérification des antécédents relativement à mon inscription pour utiliser la plateforme logicielle d'Uber en tant que chauffeur, livreur et/ou acheteur.

(2) Je reconnais et j’accepte que Uber puisse recueillir, utiliser et divulguer les renseignements personnels dans le but d’évaluer si je réponds aux exigences de sécurité applicables pour fournir des services à l'aide de la plateforme d'Uber;

(3) J’autorise également le Certn à (i) contacter les organismes d’application de la loi, les bureaux de services d’information, les agences d’évaluation du crédit, les sites Web publics, les dépôts de données, les agences d’enregistrement des véhicules à moteur, ainsi que toutes les autres archives nécessaires des secteurs privé et public et (ii) à recevoir des copies des résultats vérifiés me concernant par tout moyen raisonnable, y compris par écrit, par transmission électronique ou par téléphone;

(4) Je comprends et j’accepte que, lorsque mes antécédents personnels nécessitent des vérifications dans des pays où j’ai travaillé, étudié ou résidé, mes renseignements personnels peuvent être envoyés et vérifiés dans ces pays pertinents.

(5) Je conviens du fait qu’une copie électronique du présent consentement a la même valeur qu’une signature originale aux fins de validité, d’applicabilité et d’admissibilité et j’autorise le Certn à exporter le présent consentement à la vérification des antécédents dans un document PDF et à le présenter à toutes agences de référence qui pourrait demander une preuve de mon consentement aux fins énoncées ci-dessous;

(6) Je reconnais avoir lu et compris la Politique de confidentialité de Certn et confirme que mon consentement est pleinement informé et donné librement et je suis conscient(e) que je peux le retirer à tout moment;

(7) Je reconnais que si l’accès à la plate-forme Uber m’est refusé en tout ou en partie en raison d’information reçues d’une agence d’évaluation du crédit ou d’informations de crédit obtenues d’une personne autre qu’une agence d’évaluation du crédit, si la loi l’exige, Uber et/ou Certn m’avertiront de ce fait et, sur demande de ma part dans les délais requis par la législation applicable, m’informeront de la nature et de la source des informations lorsque celles-ci sont fournies par une personne autre qu’une agence d’évaluation du crédit; ou du nom et de l’adresse de l’agence d’évaluation du crédit, lorsque l’information est fournie par une agence d’évaluation du crédit, et de toute autre information requise par la loi.

Pour toutes questions au sujet de la collecte, de l’utilisation, de la divulgation ou du stockage de vos renseignements personnels ou si vous souhaitez obtenir de plus amples informations sur les politiques et les procédures de Certn ou de l'employeur en matière de protection de la vie privée, veuillez communiquer avec le responsable de la protection des renseignements personnels de Certn en téléphonant au 1-844-987-0690 ou par courriel à privacy@certn.co.

UBER - Canadian Criminal Consent
--------------------------------

### Version 2.0

##### Effective April 11th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

To the extent permitted by applicable law, I hereby consent to a search of all records and information available at the time the search is conducted, including non-conviction information, charges before the courts, findings of guilt or convictions and court orders registered in my name in the National Repository of Criminal Records, the Canadian Police Information Centre (“CPIC”) database and local records available to the police service for the purposes of delivering a background screening report in relation to my signing up to use Uber’s software platform as a driver, delivery person, and/or shopper. The query may also include a search of court records and a query of records management systems in other police agencies' jurisdictions through the Police Information Portal (PIP) or other data sharing systems.

I understand that this criminal record check is based on my identity verification including, but not limited to the name(s), date of birth and where used, the declared criminal record history provided by myself.

I acknowledge that for the completion of the criminal record check, reported criminal records may require me to provide fingerprints.

I acknowledge and agree that Uber may collect, use and disclose the information collected for the purposes of evaluating whether I meet the applicable safety requirements to provide services using Uber’s platform.

I acknowledge that I have read and understood Certn’s [Privacy Policy](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/) and hereby confirm that my consent is fully informed and freely given and I am aware that I can withdraw it at any time.

You may request more information about the nature and scope of any criminal record checks to be conducted by contacting Certn’s Privacy Officer at 1-844-987-0690 or [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co).

UBER - Canadian Criminal Consent - FR
-------------------------------------

### Version 2.0

##### Effective April 11th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

Dans la mesure où la loi applicable le permet, je consens par la présente à une recherche de tous les dossiers et renseignements disponibles me concernant au moment où la recherche est effectuée, y compris les renseignements sur les non-condamnations, les accusations portées devant les tribunaux, les déclarations de culpabilité ou les condamnations et les ordonnances judiciaires enregistrées à mon nom dans le Répertoire national des casiers judiciaires, la base de données du Centre d’information de la police canadienne (CIPC) et les dossiers locaux dont dispose le service de police dans le but de fournir un rapport de vérification des antécédents relativement à mon inscription pour utiliser la plateforme logicielle d'Uber en tant que chauffeur, livreur et/ou acheteur. La requête peut également comprendre une recherche dans les dossiers judiciaires et une interrogation des systèmes de gestion des dossiers dans les juridictions d’autres services de police par le biais du Portail d’informations policières (PIP) ou d’autres systèmes de partage de données.

Je comprends que cette vérification du casier judiciaire est basée sur la vérification de mon identité, y compris, mais sans s’y limiter, le(s) nom(s), la date de naissance et, le cas échéant, les antécédents judiciaires que j’aurais déclarés moi-même.

Je reconnais que pour compléter la vérification du casier judiciaire, les antécédents criminels déclarés peuvent exiger que je fournisse des empreintes digitales.

Je reconnais et accepte que Uber puisse collecter, utiliser et divulguer les informations recueillies dans le but d’évaluer si je réponds aux exigences de sécurité applicables pour fournir des services en utilisant la plateforme d'Uber.

Je reconnais avoir lu et compris la [Politique de confidentialité](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/) de Certn et confirme que mon consentement est pleinement informé et donné librement et je suis conscient(e) que je peux le retirer à tout moment.

Vous pouvez demander de plus amples informations sur la nature et la portée des vérifications du casier judiciaire qui seront effectuées en téléphonant au responsable de la protection des renseignements personnels de Certn au 1 844 987-0690 ou par courriel à [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co).

Wise Inc - FCRA Authorization
-----------------------------

### Version 10.0

##### Effective January 16th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**AUTHORIZATION REGARDING BACKGROUND INVESTIGATION**

By signing below, I acknowledge receipt of the following separate documents (and certify that I have read and understood them):

* DISCLOSURE REGARDING BACKGROUND INVESTIGATION ON YOU;
* A SUMMARY OF YOUR RIGHTS UNDER THE FAIR CREDIT REPORTING ACT;
* ADDITIONAL NOTICE REGARDING INVESTIGATIVE CONSUMER REPORTS ON YOU;
* ADDITIONAL STATE LAW NOTICES.

By signing below, I also authorize domestic and international law enforcement agencies, learning institutions (including public and private schools, colleges and universities), information service bureaus, credit bureaus, data repositories, courts (federal, state and local), motor vehicle records agencies, my past or present employers, the military, and other public or private individuals and institutions to furnish any and all information on me that is requested by Certn, the consumer reporting agency preparing reports about me for **{{{company\_name}}}** . I agree that where my personal history requires verifications to be carried out in countries where I have worked and/or resided, my data will be sent and processed in those relevant countries for the delivery of the requested verifications. The information that can be disclosed to Certn includes, but is not limited to, criminal history, sex offender registry status, credit history, employment history, education history, driving history, and information regarding my professional licenses, social security number, identification documents, and drug testing results.

By signing below, I also authorize **{{{company\_name}}}** to obtain "**consumer reports**" and "**investigative consumer reports**" about me for employment purposes at any time during the hiring process and throughout my employment, if applicable.

Name: {{{first\_name}}} {{{last\_name}}}

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| Name |     |
| Social Security Number: | {{{ssn}}} |
| Date of Birth: | {{{dob}}} |
| Full Address: | {{{full\_address}}} |
| Race: | U   |
| Gender: | U   |
| Purpose Code | E   |

\[END OF DOCUMENT\]

FCRA Authorization (Copy) -- Formatting Test
--------------------------------------------

### Version 12.0

##### Effective May 29th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**AUTHORIZATION REGARDING BACKGROUND INVESTIGATION**

By signing below, I acknowledge receipt of the following separate documents (and certify that I have read and understood them):

* DISCLOSURE REGARDING BACKGROUND INVESTIGATION ON YOU;
* A SUMMARY OF YOUR RIGHTS UNDER THE FAIR CREDIT REPORTING ACT;
* ADDITIONAL NOTICE REGARDING INVESTIGATIVE CONSUMER REPORTS ON YOU;
* ADDITIONAL STATE LAW NOTICES.

By signing below, I also authorize domestic and international law enforcement agencies, learning institutions (including public and private schools, colleges and universities), information service bureaus, credit bureaus, data repositories, courts (federal, state and local), motor vehicle records agencies, my past or present employers, the military, and other public or private individuals and institutions to furnish any and all information on me that is requested by Certn, the consumer reporting agency preparing reports about me for **{{{company\_name}}}** . I agree that where my personal history requires verifications to be carried out in countries where I have worked and/or resided, my data may be sent and processed in those relevant countries for the delivery of the requested verifications. The information that can be disclosed to Certn includes, but is not limited to, criminal history, sex offender registry status, credit history, employment history, education history, driving history, and information regarding my professional licenses, social security number, identification documents, and drug testing results.

By signing below, I also authorize **{{{company\_name}}}** to obtain "**consumer reports**" and "**investigative consumer reports**" about me for employment purposes at any time during the hiring process and throughout my employment, if applicable.

\[END OF DOCUMENT\]

ADDENDA SUR LE TRAITEMENT DES DONNÉES - FR
------------------------------------------

### Version 1.1

##### Effective June 9th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**ADDENDA SUR LE TRAITEMENT DES DONNÉES**

Le présent Addenda sur le Traitement des données (« **ATD** ») fait partie du Contrat de services signé par vous (le « **Client** ») lorsque vous avez créé votre compte (le « **Contrat** »).

1. **Définitions.** Les mots et les expressions figurant en caractères gras et utilisés, mais non définis dans les présentes, ont le sens qui leur est attribué dans le Contrat. En cas de conflit entre certaines dispositions du présent ATD et les dispositions du Contrat, les dispositions du présent ATD doivent avoir préséance sur les dispositions contradictoires du Contrat uniquement en ce qui a trait au Traitement des Renseignements personnels.
    1. « **CCPA** » désigne la loi de la Californie sur les droits de confidentialité des consommateurs (« California Consumer Privacy Act ») de 2018, Cal. Civ. Code §1798.100 et. séq., de même que ses réglementations de mise en œuvre.
    2. « **Clauses** **contractuelles** **types** » (« **CCT** ») désigne les Clauses contractuelles types telles qu’énoncées sur ce lien faisant partie de la présente, en ce qui concerne les transferts de responsable du Traitement à Sous-traitant, conformément à la Décision (UE) 2021/914 de la Commission européenne du 4 juin 2021 (telle que pouvant être mise à jour par la Commission européenne de temps à autre).
    3. « **CPA** » désigne la loi sur la protection des Renseignements personnels du Colorado (« Colorado Privacy Act ») de 2021.
    4. « **Demande d’accès par la Personne concernée** » désigne un formulaire permettant au consommateur (ou à la « **Personne concernée** » telle que définie dans le RGPD) de demander l’accès, la copie, la modification, la contestation, l’effacement ou toute action supplémentaire concernant ses Renseignements personnels sous réserve de la Législation applicable en matière de protection des données.
    5. « **Finalité** **du Traitement** » désigne l’une des finalités autorisées telles qu’elles sont décrites dans le Contrat.
    6. « **LGPD** désigne la Loi générale sur la protection des données « **LGPD** » du Brésil (Lei Geral de Proteção de Dados).
    7. « **Lois sur la protection des données du Royaume-Uni** » (« **UK Data Protection Laws** ») désigne toutes les lois relatives à la protection des données, au traitement des Renseignements personnels, à la confidentialité et/ou aux communications électroniques en vigueur de temps à autre au Royaume-Uni, y compris le RGPD du Royaume-Uni (« UK GDPR ») et la Loi sur la protection des données de 2018 (la « Data Protection Act 2018 »).
    8. « **LPD** » désigne la Loi sur la protection des données de la Suisse.
    9. « **Renseignements personnels** » et « **Données à caractère personnel** » désignent tout renseignement pouvant identifier ou décrire un consommateur identifié ou identifiable, être associé à ce dernier, ou pouvant raisonnablement être lié, directement ou indirectement, à ce dernier, et qui est traité par Certn uniquement pour le compte du Client, en vertu du présent ATD et du Contrat.
    10. « **Responsable du Traitement des données** » (ou le « **Responsable du Traitement** ») désigne une personne morale, une autorité publique, une agence ou un autre organisme qui, seul ou conjointement avec d’autres, détermine les finalités et les moyens du Traitement des Renseignements personnels et donne des instructions concernant les activités de traitement à Certn; aux fins du Contrat, le Client est le Responsable du Traitement des données.
    11. « **RGPD** » désigne le Règlement général sur la protection des données (UE) 2016/679 de l’Union européenne.
    12. « **RGPD du Royaume-Uni** » désigne le Règlement général sur la protection des données du Royaume-Uni, car il fait partie de la loi de l’Angleterre et du Pays de Galles, de l’Écosse et de l’Irlande du Nord en vertu de l’article 3 de la Loi sur le retrait de l’Union européenne de 2018 (la « European Union \[Withdrawal\] Act »).
    13. « **Sous-traitant** **chargé du Traitement des données** » (ou le « **Sous-traitant** ») désigne l’entité juridique qui traite les Renseignements personnels au nom du Responsable du Traitement des données; au sens du présent Contrat, Certn est le Sous-traitant chargé du Traitement des données.
    14. « **Sous-traitant ultérieur** » désigne un Sous-traitant ultérieur engagé, désigné et supervisé par Certn qui accepte de recevoir et de traiter les Renseignements personnels en vertu des Modalités du présent ATD et uniquement aux fins de traitement ou de livraison des données, sous réserve des Modalités du Contrat.
    15. « **Traitement** » (aussi « **traiter** » et « **traité** ») désigne toute opération ou tout ensemble d’opérations qui est effectué sur des Renseignements personnels ou sur un ensemble de Renseignements personnels, que ce soit par des moyens automatisés ou non comme la collecte, l’enregistrement, l’organisation, la structuration, le stockage, l’adaptation ou la modification, la récupération, la consultation, l’utilisation, la divulgation par transmission, la diffusion ou la mise à disposition, l’alignement ou la combinaison, la restriction, l’effacement ou la destruction.
    16. « **VCDPA** » désigne la Loi sur la protection des données des consommateurs de la Virginie (« Virginia Consumer Data Protection Act »).
2. **Rôles.** Les parties reconnaissent et conviennent que, en ce qui a trait au Traitement et au transfert des Renseignements personnels, sous réserve du champ d’application du RGPD, de la FADP, de la LGPD, de la CPA et de la VCDPA : i) le Client est le Responsable du Traitement des Renseignements personnels; ii) Certn est le Sous-traitant chargé du Traitement de ces Renseignements personnels et iii) aux fins de la CCPA (et dans la mesure applicable), le Client est l’« **entreprise** » et Certn est le « **fournisseur** **de services** » (tels que ces termes sont définis dans la CCPA). À titre d’agence de renseignements sur les consommateurs, (« **ARC** »), Certn n’est pas considéré comme un courtier en données et, par conséquent, est exonéré de l’application de la CCPA (voir les articles §1798.99.80 (d) (1)). Le Code civil de la Californie (« California Civil Code ») prévoit des exonérations pour les ARC (voir l’article §1798.145(d)(1) pour plus de détails).
3. **Généralités.**
    1. Chaque partie doit se conformer à toutes les lois applicables en ce qui concerne le traitement des Renseignements personnels et s’engage à faire tout ce qui est en son pouvoir pour aider l’autre partie à se conformer à ses obligations en vertu des lois applicables et ne doit pas exécuter ses obligations en vertu du présent ATD de manière à amener l’autre partie à violer l’une de ses obligations en vertu des lois applicables dans la mesure où elle sait, ou aurait dû raisonnablement savoir, que cela constituerait une violation de ces obligations.
    2. Certn ne doit traiter les Renseignements personnels que sur les instructions documentées du Client et conformément à la Finalité du Traitement, à moins d’exigence contraire en vertu des lois applicables. Des instructions subséquentes peuvent également être données par le Client pendant toute la durée du Traitement des Renseignements personnels. Ces instructions doivent toujours être documentées.
    3. Certn doit informer immédiatement le Client si Certn estime que les instructions données par le Client (ou le Responsable du Traitement) contreviennent aux lois applicables.
4. **Limitation de la finalité.** Certn traitera les Renseignements personnels uniquement selon de la Finalité du Traitement, dans la mesure et de la manière nécessaires à la prestation des Services. Certn ne traitera pas les Renseignements personnels à d’autres fins ou d’une manière qui ne serait pas conforme au Contrat (y compris au présent Addenda) ou aux lois applicables.
5. **Effacement ou restitution des Renseignements personnels.**
    1. Certn ne doit Traiter les Renseignements personnels fournis par le Client que pendant la durée du Contrat.
    2. Sauf accord contraire entre les Parties, les dispositions de l’Annexe I.B s’appliquent en ce qui concerne les calendriers de conservation et d’effacement des données.
6. **Sécurité du Traitement..**
    1. Certn doit appliquer des normes commercialement raisonnables pour assurer la sécurité des Renseignements personnels, y compris la protection contre la destruction accidentelle ou illégale, la perte, la modification, la divulgation ou l’accès non autorisé à ces données (atteinte à la vie privée). Une copie des mesures techniques et organisationnelles de Certn est énoncée dans l’ANNEXE II. Si le Traitement porte sur des Renseignements personnels révélant des données sensibles ou biométriques dans le but d’identifier de manière exceptionnelle une personne physique, ou des données relatives à des condamnations et à des infractions criminelles, Certn doit appliquer des restrictions précises et/ou des mesures de protection supplémentaires, tel que peut l’exiger raisonnablement le Client à l’occasion.
    2. Pour évaluer le niveau de sécurité approprié, les deux Parties doivent tenir compte des risques liés au Traitement, de la nature des Renseignements personnels et de la nature, de la portée, du contexte et des finalités du Traitement.
    3. En cas d’atteinte à la vie privée, l’une ou l’autre des Parties doit aviser l’autre Partie sans délai indu et au plus tard 24 heures après avoir pris connaissance de ladite atteinte. Cet avis doit contenir les coordonnées d’une personne-ressource qui peut fournir de plus amples renseignements sur l’atteinte à la vie privée, une description de la nature de l’atteinte(y compris, si possible, les catégories et le nombre approximatif de Personnes concernées et d’enregistrements de données concernés), les conséquences probables de l’atteinte et les mesures prises ou proposées pour atténuer ses éventuels effets négatifs. S’il n’est pas possible de fournir tous ces renseignements en même temps, l’avis initial doit contenir les renseignements disponibles à ce moment-là, et les renseignements complémentaires doivent être fournis au fur et à mesure qu’ils deviennent disponibles, sans retard excessif.
7. **Droits des consommateurs.** Certn doit aviser rapidement le Client s’il reçoit une Demande d’accès par la Personne concernée. Le Client est responsable de la réponse aux Demandes d’accès des Personnes concernées et, cependant, dans la mesure où le Client n’a pas la capacité de donner suite à une Demande d’accès de la Personne concernée, Certn doit déployer des efforts raisonnables, lorsque la loi l’exige ou à la demande du Client, pour aider le Client à répondre à cette demande d’accès de la Personne concernée sans frais supplémentaires pendant la période de validité de la Loi applicable.
8. **Sous-traitants ultérieurs.**
    1. Les Sous-traitants ultérieurs de Certn (tels qu’ils se trouvent ici) sont les entités mandatées par Certn qui acceptent de recevoir des Renseignements personnels de la part du Sous-traitant aux fins exclusives des activités de Traitement à effectuer selon les instructions du Client. Le Client reconnaît et convient que les sociétés affiliées de Certn : a) peuvent être mandatées à titre de Sous-traitants ultérieurs et b) peuvent, chacune, faire appel aux services de Sous-traitants tiers dans le cadre de la prestation des services. Certn peut écarter, remplacer ou désigner d’autres Sous-traitants ultérieurs adéquats et fiables, sur avis au Client et à sa propre discrétion.
    2. Nonobstant ce qui précède, le Client peut raisonnablement s’opposer à l’utilisation, par Certn, d’un nouveau Sous-traitant ultérieur pour des raisons liées à la protection des Renseignements personnels destinés à être Traités par ledit Sous-traitant ultérieur, en avisant rapidement par écrit Certn dans les trois (3) jours ouvrables suivant la réception de l’avis de Certn. Une telle objection écrite doit préciser les motifs pour lesquels le Client s’oppose au fait que le Sous-traitant fasse appel à ce Sous-traitant ultérieur. L’absence d’objection écrite à ce nouveau Sous-traitant ultérieur dans les trois (3) jours ouvrables suivant l’avis de Certn sera considérée comme une acceptation du nouveau Sous-traitant ultérieur. Dans le cas où le Client s’oppose raisonnablement à un nouveau Sous-traitant ultérieur, comme cela est autorisé ci-dessus, Certn peut :
        1. cesser d’utiliser le Sous-traitant ultérieur en ce qui concerne les Renseignements personnels soumis par le Client;
        2. prendre les mesures correctives demandées par le Client dans son objection;
        3. cesser de fournir (temporairement ou définitivement) l’élément du service qui nécessite l’utilisation de ce Sous-traitant ultérieur en ce qui concerne les Renseignements personnels soumis par le Client; et
        4. fournir au Client une description écrite de la ou des solutions de rechange commercialement raisonnables, le cas échéant, à cet engagement, y compris, sans s’y limiter, la modification des services
    3. Si Certn, à sa seule discrétion, ne peut fournir une ou plusieurs des solutions de rechange énumérées ci-dessus , ou si le Client n’accepte pas la ou les éventuelles solutions de rechange, alors Certn et le Client peuvent résilier le Contrat conformément aux Modalités de ce dernier. La résiliation ne dégage pas le Client de tous les frais dus à Certn en vertu du Contrat. Jusqu’à ce qu’une décision soit prise concernant le nouveau Sous-traitant ultérieur, Certn peut, au besoin, suspendre temporairement le Traitement des Renseignements personnels concernés et/ou suspendre l’accès au compte, et le Client n’aura aucune autre réclamation à l’encontre du Sous-traitant ultérieur en raison de la suspension temporaire ou de la résiliation du Contrat (y compris, sans limitation, relativement à une demande de remboursement).
    4. Certn doit assurer que tous les Sous-traitants ultérieurs autorisés ont signé des accords de confidentialité qui les empêchent de Traiter sans autorisation les Renseignements personnels du Client, tant pendant qu’après leur engagement auprès de Certn. En outre, Certn doit (par exemple, par voie de contrat ou d’un autre acte juridique) imposer au Sous-traitant ultérieur les mêmes obligations de protection des données que celles énoncées dans le présent ATD.
9. **Transferts internationaux de données.**
    1. **Les transferts internationaux de données sont assujettis aux CCT.** Lorsque le transfert des Renseignements personnels est effectué sous réserve des CCT, l’« importateur des données », en vertu des CCT, est soit le Sous-traitant, soit le Sous-traitant ultérieur, selon le cas et selon ce que détermine le Sous-traitant, et l’« exportateur des données » est le Responsable du Traitement de ces Données à caractère personnel. Le Sous-traitant doit s’assurer que le Sous-traitant ultérieur concerné, le cas échéant, se conforme aux obligations de l’importateur des données, et le Responsable du Traitement des données doit se conformer aux obligations de l’exportateur de données, dans chaque cas en vertu des CCT applicables.
    2. **Transferts internationaux de données depuis et vers des pays qui offrent un niveau adéquat de protection des données.** Les Renseignements personnels peuvent être transférés depuis les États membres de l’UE et les pays membres de l’EEE (Norvège, Liechtenstein et Islande) (collectivement, « EEE ») vers des pays qui offrent un niveau adéquat de protection des données (y compris le Canada) en vertu ou conformément aux décisions d’adéquation publiées par les autorités de protection des données de l’EEE ou de la Commission européenne (« décisions d’adéquation »), selon le cas, sans qu’aucune autre mesure de protection ne soit nécessaire.
    3. **Transferts depuis la Suisse.** Dans la mesure où le Préposé fédéral à la protection des données et à la transparence (PFPDT) de la Suisse considère que les CCT assurent des mesures de protection appropriées aux fins du transfert des Renseignements personnels et des données des entités juridiques, les modifications suivantes s’appliquent en ce qui concerne les transferts suisses :
        1. les Parties adoptent la norme RGPD pour tous les transferts de données;
        2. en ce qui concerne la clause 13a, l’autorité de surveillance de l’UE doit être compétente dans la mesure où le transfert de données est régi par le RGPD et le Préposé fédéral à la protection des données et à la transparence de la Suisse doit effectuer une supervision parallèle, le cas échéant; et
        3. en ce qui concerne la clause 18c, le terme « État membre » doit être interprété de manière à permettre aux Personnes concernées en Suisse d’entamer des poursuites pour assurer le respect de leurs droits dans leur lieu de résidence habituel (Suisse).
    4. **Transferts depuis le Royaume-Uni.** Dans la mesure où l’Autorité de surveillance du Royaume-Uni (le Commissaire à l’information) considère que les CCT assurent des mesures de protection appropriées aux fins de transfert des Renseignements personnels vers un pays tiers ou vers un organisme international en se fondant sur les articles 46 du RGPD du Royaume-Uni et, en ce qui concerne les transferts de données des Responsables du Traitement aux Sous-traitants et/ou des Sous-traitants aux Sous-traitants, les modifications suivantes s’appliquent en ce qui concerne les transferts depuis le Royaume-Uni :
        1. « Les détails du ou des transferts et en particulier les catégories de Renseignements personnels qui sont transférés et la ou les finalités pour lesquelles ils sont transférés) sont ceux spécifiés à l’annexe I.B lorsque les Lois britanniques sur la protection des données s’appliquent au traitement de l’exportateur de données lors de ce ou ces transferts. »
        2. Les références à « Règlement (UE) 2016/679 » ou « ce Règlement » sont remplacées par « Lois britanniques sur la protection des données » et les références à l’article ou aux articles spécifiques du « Règlement (UE) 2016/679 » sont remplacées par l’article ou la section équivalents des Lois britanniques sur la protection des données. En particulier :
            1. Les références au règlement (UE) 2018/1725 sont supprimées;
            2. Les références à l’« Union », à l’« UE » et à l’« État membre de l’UE » sont toutes remplacées par le « R.-U. »;
            3. La clause 13(a) n’est pas utilisée et l’« autorité de surveillance compétente » est le commissaire à l’information;
            4. La clause 17 est remplacée par la mention « Ces CCT sont régies par les lois de l’Angleterre et du Pays de Galles »;
            5. La clause 18 est remplacée par la mention suivante : « Tout différend découlant de ces CCT doit être résolu par les tribunaux d’Angleterre et du Pays de Galles. Une Personne concernée peut également intenter des procédures judiciaires contre l’exportateur de données et/ou l’importateur de données devant les tribunaux de tout pays du Royaume-Uni. Les Parties conviennent de se soumettre à la compétence de ces tribunaux »; et
            6. Les notes de bas de page relatives aux CCT ne s’appliquent pas aux transferts depuis le Royaume-Uni.
10. **Divers.** Le Responsable du Traitement des données ne doit pas refuser ou retarder de manière déraisonnable son approbation à une éventuelle modification du présent ATD proposée par le Sous-traitant dans le but de protéger ce dernier contre les risques additionnels connexes. Si le Responsable du Traitement propose d’autres variations au présent ATD qu’il estime raisonnablement nécessaires pour répondre aux exigences des lois applicables, les Parties doivent discuter promptement des variations proposées et négocier en toute bonne foi afin d’accepter et de mettre en œuvre ces variations ou d’autres variations dès que cela sera raisonnablement possible. Nonobstant ce qui précède, sur présentation d’un avis au Client, Certn peut réviser le présent Addenda afin d’y intégrer toute CCT obligatoire ou toute autre condition exigée par une autorité compétente en matière de protection des données dans l’UE ou au Royaume-Uni.

**ANNEXE I**

**Annexe I.A. – PARTIES**

| **Exportateur de données** | L’exportateur de données est identifié comme le Client ou le « Responsable du Traitement des données » dans l’ATD. |
| --- | --- |
| **Importateur de données** | L’importateur de données est Certn, un fournisseur de services de vérification des données et de vérification des antécédents. |
| --- | --- |

**Annexe I.B. – RENSEIGNEMENTS SUR LE TRAITEMENT**

| **Personnes concernées** | Les individus et les candidats assujettis aux services de vérification des antécédents à des fins d’emploi, de location ou de toute autre finalité légale et autorisée, selon les instructions du responsable du traitement. |
| --- | --- |
| **Catégories de Données à caractère personnel transférées** | **Données du Client****:** coordonnées professionnelles (courriel, numéro de téléphone, adresse courriel, noms, titres de poste, adresse professionnelle).**Données sur les consommateurs****:** adresses de courriel, noms, coordonnées, titres de poste, adresse résidentielle ou commerciale; photographie; numéros d’identification personnels (le cas échéant); titre et qualifications scolaires; antécédents professionnels; permis de conduire; dossiers de présence; titre du poste; sexe; numéro de téléphone professionnel (y compris le numéro de téléphone cellulaire) et numéro de télécopieur; adresse courriel personnelle; numéro de téléphone personnel (y compris le numéro de téléphone cellulaire); cote, pointage, risque, défaillance ou défaut de crédit; renseignements sur le paiement; antécédents criminels; dossiers concernant les réclamations et les jugements associés; dossiers publics comme les postes d’administrateur, insolvabilité, faillites, situation financière, adresse IP; données des témoins; identifiants de connexion (nom d’utilisateur et mot de passe); données de trafic; images et sons; données biométriques. |
| --- | --- |
| **Fréquence des transferts** | Les transferts seront traités sur demande. |
| --- | --- |
| **Nature du Traitement** | La nature et le but du traitement s’entendent de toute opération telle que la collecte, l’enregistrement, l’organisation, la structuration, le stockage, la récupération, la consultation, l’utilisation, la divulgation par transmission, la diffusion ou autre mise à disposition, la restriction, l’effacement ou la destruction des données (que ce soit ou non par des moyens automatisés). |
| --- | --- |
| **Finalité(s) du transfert de données et du Traitement ultérieur** | Fournir les services au Client, tels qu’ils sont décrits dans le Contrat; exécuter le Contrat, le présent ATD et/ou d’autres ententes signées par les Parties; fournir un soutien et un maintien technique, si prévu aux termes du Contrat; prévenir, atténuer les risques d’incidents de sécurité des données, de fraude, d’erreur ou de toute activité illégale ou interdite et faire enquête sur ces éléments; se conformer aux lois et aux règlements applicables; toutes les tâches liées à l’un ou l’autre des éléments ci-dessus. |
| --- | --- |
| **Période pendant laquelle les Données à caractère personnel seront conservées ou, si ce n’est pas possible, les critères utilisés pour déterminer cette période** | Les Parties conviennent d’effacer les Données à caractère personnel de tous les ordinateurs, dispositifs de stockage et supports de stockage dès que possible après que leur conservation n’est plus nécessaire en vertu de la législation applicable en matière de protection des données ou comme l’exige par ailleurs le Contrat. Nonobstant ce qui précède, sauf accord contraire entre les Parties, ou si requis en vertu de la législation applicable en matière de protection des données, les Parties conviennent que i) les dossiers du Client seront conservés par Certn conformément à la Politique de conservation de Certn, qui peut être mise à jour de temps à autre. |
| --- | --- |

**Annexe I.C. – AUTORITÉ DE CONTRÔLE COMPÉTENTE**

| **Autorité de contrôle compétente** | Commission de protection des données (« Data Protection Commission »), République d’Irlande. |
| --- | --- |

**ANNEXE II**

**MESURES TECHNIQUES ET ORGANISATIONNELLES, Y COMPRIS LES MESURES TECHNIQUES ET ORGANISATIONNELLES POUR ASSURER LA SÉCURITÉ DES DONNÉES**

| **Mesures techniques et organisationnelles mises en œuvre par l’importateur de données** | Le rapport de conformité SOC 2 est disponible sur demande. Le rapport de conformité SOC 3 est accessible au public. |
| --- | --- |
| **Mesures de la pseudonymisation et de chiffrement des Données à caractère personnel** | Le niveau de chiffrement utilisé est AES 256. |
| --- | --- |
| **Mesures pour assurer la confidentialité, l’intégrité, la disponibilité et la résilience continues des systèmes et des services de traitement** | Certn est certifié SOC 2 et SOC 3 de façon continue. |
| --- | --- |
| **Mesures pour assurer la capacité de restaurer la disponibilité et l’accès aux Données à caractère personnel en temps opportun en cas d’incident physique ou technique** | Des procédures de sauvegarde et de restauration des données sont définies et documentées dans les politiques de Certn, lesquelles sont disponibles sur demande. L’exécution des sauvegardes est surveillée pour en assurer l’exhaustivité. Certn stocke les données sur le nuage AWS, qui a des sauvegardes automatiques configurées et chiffrées. De plus, il existe plusieurs zones à des fins de redondance et de récupération. |
| --- | --- |
| **Processus d’essai et d’évaluation réguliers de l’efficacité des mesures techniques et organisationnelles dans le but d’assurer la sécurité du traitement** | Certn est conforme et certifié en vertu des normes SOC 2 et SOC 3. Parmi les processus et mesures garantissant la sécurité du traitement figurent, entre autres, la gestion des vulnérabilités, l’évaluation des risques, la gestion des actifs, les IDS et IPS, la gestion des correctifs, la surveillance des points de terminaison, la gestion des fournisseurs d’outils SIEM. |
| --- | --- |
| **Mesures d’identification et de l’utilisateur** | Un système de contrôle d’accès applicable à tous les utilisateurs accédant au système informatique a été mis en œuvre. Le système permet à Certn de créer, d’approuver, d’examiner et de supprimer des comptes d'utilisateurs.Certn met en œuvre l’authentification à facteurs multiples pour tous les comptes qui ont accès aux Données à caractère personnel. Lorsque les mécanismes d’authentification sont fondés sur des mots de passe, le Sous-traitant chargé du Traitement des données exige que le mot de passe soit d’au moins huit caractères et qu’il soit conforme aux paramètres de contrôle des mots de passe très forts, y compris la longueur, la complexité des caractères et la non-répétitivité. |
| --- | --- |
| **Mesures d’autorisations de l’utilisateur fondées sur les rôles** | Au moment d’octroyer un accès ou d’attribuer un rôle d’utilisateur, le principe du « besoin de savoir » est appliqué afin de limiter le nombre d’utilisateurs ayant accès aux Renseignements personnels uniquement à ceux qui en ont besoin pour atteindre les Finalités de Traitement du Responsable du Traitement des données. |
| --- | --- |
| **Mesures de protection des données pendant la transmission** | Le Fournisseur applique des contrôles d’accès pour garantir un accès fondé sur les rôles, des mécanismes de journalisation pour montrer les événements des utilisateurs qui peuvent être transférés à un SIEM, le chiffrement des données au repos et en transit en utilisant respectivement le chiffrement AES 256 et ≥TLS v1.2. |
| --- | --- |
| **Mesures de protection des données pendant le stockage** | Certn a adopté une Politique de chiffrement des données, une Politique de sauvegarde des données et une Politique de conservation des données, lesquelles régissent l’accès, la disponibilité et la durée de conservation des données des catégories stockées. |
| --- | --- |
| **Mesures pour assurer la sécurité physique des emplacements où les Données à caractère personnel sont traitées** | Certn s’est dotée d’une Politique de sécurité physique qui prévoit l’accès aux bureaux physiques au moyen d’une clé, l’utilisation d’alarmes de sécurité, la surveillance de sécurité, l’accès limité aux visiteurs. Le périmètre physique de l’infrastructure du système informatique n’est pas accessible par le personnel non autorisé. Des mesures techniques et organisationnelles appropriées ont été mises en œuvre pour protéger les zones de sécurité et protéger les points d’accès contre l’entrée par des personnes non autorisées. Certn stocke ses données sur le nuage AWS, en appliquant les exigences et pratiques exemplaires. Les données sont segmentées, chiffrées et sauvegardées avec l’inclusion d’une disponibilité multizone. |
| --- | --- |
| **Mesures pour assurer la journalisation des événements** | Le SIEM recueille des événements, et des politiques et des alertes sont créées aux fins d’analyse et d’enquête. Protection et surveillance des points d’extrémité, détection et prévention des intrusions grâce à la surveillance et à l’évaluation. |
| --- | --- |
| **Mesures pour assurer la configuration du système, y compris la configuration par défaut** | Certn a mis en œuvre une Politique de gestion des actifs dans laquelle sont décrites les normes de configuration et toute variable applicable. Une politique de contrôle d’accès au système a été définie, documentée et mise en œuvre pour permettre l’évaluation des contrôles et l’accès aux actifs de Certn. |
| --- | --- |
| **Mesures liées aux TI internes et à la gouvernance et à la gestion de la sécurité des TI** | Certn a mis en œuvre une Politique de sécurité de l’information et donne aux employés une formation sur la sécurité interne pendant la phase d’orientation, puis chaque année. |
| --- | --- |
| **Mesures de certification/assurance des processus et des produits** | Le rapport de conformité SOC 2 est disponible sur demande. Le rapport de conformité SOC 3 est accessible au public. |
| --- | --- |
| **Mesures visant à assurer la minimisation des données** | Tout renseignement personnel traité est limité aux seuls identifiants correspondants strictement nécessaires, lesquels sont définis en fonction des sources de données avec lesquelles nous exerçons nos activités. |
| --- | --- |
| **Mesures visant à assurer la qualité des données** | Pour garantir l’exactitude, la pertinence, l’exhaustivité et la mise à jour des Renseignements personnels, Certn procède à des vérifications de données en temps réel, avec le consentement de la Personne concernée et uniquement dans les limites de la finalité autorisée définie. Toutes les données potentiellement incomplètes font l’objet d’une nouvelle confirmation auprès de la Personne concernée et/ou de la source de données relative. |
| --- | --- |
| **Mesures visant à assurer une conservation limitée des données** | Certn s’est dotée d’une politique sur la conservation des données qui définit différents calendriers de purge pour des catégories de données distinctes. |
| --- | --- |
| **Mesures visant à assurer la responsabilisation** | Certn a adopté une « approche de la protection de la vie privée dès la conception » et fait l’objet de vérifications indépendantes à intervalles réguliers dans le but d’assurer le respect aux normes les plus élevées du secteur d’industrie en matière de contrôles internes de sécurité, de disponibilité, d’intégrité, de confidentialité et de protection de la vie privée. |
| --- | --- |
| **Mesures pour permettre la portabilité des données et assurer l’effacement des données** | Les Personnes concernées peuvent enregistrer leurs demandes d’accès, lesquelles sont passées en revue par un agent de la protection de la vie privée. |
| --- | --- |
| **Sous-traitants ultérieurs** | Les Sous-traitants ultérieurs doivent respecter les mêmes normes que celles énoncées dans l’Annexe II dans sa version actuelle. |
| --- | --- |

CONDITIONS DE SERVICE - FR
--------------------------

### Version 1.5

##### Effective November 14th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**CONDITIONS DE SERVICE**

Les présentes conditions de service (les « **Conditions** ») énoncent les dispositions générales qui régissent votre accès et votre utilisation de la plateforme et les portails de vérification des antécédents proposés par Certn (la « **Plateforme** ») et constituent une entente entre Certn et vous ou l’entité que vous êtes autorisé à représenter (**« vous », « votre » ou « vos »**). Les Conditions entrent en vigueur lorsque vous signez un bon de commande, le cas échéant (le « **Bon de commande** »), cliquez sur le bouton « **Continue** » (Continuer) ou cochez la case figurant dans ces conditions ou, dès lors que vous utilisez l’une des offres de services de Certn si vous effectuez cette démarche plus tôt (la « **Date d’entrée en vigueur** »). Vous déclarez à Certn que vous êtes légalement en mesure d’accepter les Conditions.

Si vous acceptez les Conditions et créez un Compte au nom d’une entité, telle que la société pour laquelle vous travaillez, vous déclarez à Certn que vous avez l’autorité légale de lier ladite entité. Si vous n’avez pas cette autorité ou si vous n’acceptez pas les Conditions, vous ne devez pas cliquer sur « Continue » (Continuer) et vous ne pouvez pas utiliser les offres de services de Certn. Si vous acceptez les Conditions et créez un Compte pour un Utilisateur final, vous déclarez à Certn, en votre qualité d’Utilisateur initial, que vous avez l’autorité légale de lier l’Utilisateur final. L’Utilisateur final sera responsable des actions de l’Utilisateur initial et de tout Utilisateur supplémentaire. Pour éviter toute ambiguïté, il est précisé que, si l’Utilisateur final a conclu un Bon de commande ou un contrat-cadre de services distinct avec Certn (un « **CCS** »), les présentes Conditions seront subordonnées à toute disposition convenue dans ledit document.

Certn peut réviser les Conditions à tout moment, sans préavis. Les Conditions révisées entreront en vigueur lorsqu’elles seront publiées sur le site Web applicable appartenant à Certn, y compris certn.co (le ou les « **Site(s) Web** »). Nonobstant ce qui précède, Certn vous avertira de toute révision qui pourrait avoir une incidence sur votre utilisation du Site Web et/ou des Services ou la restreindre.

1. **DÉFINITIONS.**
    1. « **Compte** » désigne le compte de l’Utilisateur final ouvert auprès de Certn et associé à l’adresse courriel de l’Utilisateur initial et à l’adresse courriel de tout éventuel Utilisateur supplémentaire, sous réserve de sa validation par Certn.
    2. « **Utilisateur** **supplémentaire** » désigne toute société affiliée ou filiale de l’Utilisateur initial ou de l’Utilisateur final dont Certn a validé et approuvé par écrit la capacité à accéder à la Plateforme conformément aux Conditions.
    3. « **API** » désigne la ou les interfaces de programmation de l’application, dont (i) le flux d’invitation; ou (ii) le flux d’écran dynamique servant à donner accès à la Plateforme.
    4. « **Certn** » désigne Certn Holdings Inc. et ses filiales et sociétés affiliées, notamment, mais sans s'y limiter: Certn (Canada) Inc., Certn (USA) Inc., Certn (UK) Ltd. et InterCheck Global Pty Ltd.
    5. « **Formulaires** **de** **Certn** » désigne les formulaires standard de consentement, de divulgation, d’autorisation, de décision défavorable et de notification que Certn peut vous transmettre à votre demande pour que vous puissiez le consulter.
    6. « **Consommateur** » désigne tout candidat individuel qui est soumis aux Services dans le cadre de sa demande d’emploi ou d’engagement en tant que prestataire indépendant par vous, ou à tout autre Objectif autorisé par Certn pendant le processus d’accréditation.
    7. « **Agence** **d’évaluation du crédit** » désigne, selon le cas, TransUnion International UK Ltd., Equifax Canada Co, Equifax Information Services LLC ou Equifax Workforce Solutions LLC, prestataire de services de vérification d’Equifax, ou tout autre bureau de crédit approuvé.
    8. « **Objectifs** **professionnels** » désigne l’Objectif autorisé spécifique à un Rapport concernant l’évaluation des personnes en matière d’emploi, de promotion, de réaffectation ou de rétention en tant qu’employé ou prestataire indépendant.
    9. « **Utilisateur** **final** » désigne l’entité professionnelle qui utilise le Rapport conformément à la législation relative aux renseignements sur les consommateurs, dont la Fair Credit Reporting Act, ses articles 15 U.S.C. § 1681 et suivants (« FCRA »).
    10. « **Utilisateur** **initial** » désigne le représentant initial de l’Utilisateur final qui est pleinement habilité en tant qu’entreprise à lier l’Utilisateur final d’un compte.
    11. « **Objectif** **autorisé** » désigne (i) les Objectifs professionnels, si le Consommateur a donné son autorisation écrite préalable; (ii) toute autre fin autorisée en vertu de la loi (dont l’article 8 de la Loi sur les renseignements concernant le consommateur \[Ontario\] et l’article 604\[a\] de la FCRA, le cas échéant); ou (iii) conformément au RGPD, tout objectif pour lequel l’Utilisateur final a précisé le fondement légal du traitement des données personnelles (si l’Utilisateur final est le responsable du traitement) ou a obtenu confirmation par le responsable du traitement que le fondement légal a été précisé (si l’Utilisateur final demande les services au nom du responsable du traitement), selon le cas, en fonction de ce que l’Utilisateur final déclare avant la commande.
    12. « **Rapport** » désigne un rapport sur le consommateur ou un autre produit de sélection applicable offert sur la Plateforme, dont les rapports contenant des renseignements sur la solvabilité et les Rapports d’enquête sur le consommateur (le cas échéant), comme défini à la Section 603\[d\] de la FCRA.
    13. « **Services** » désigne les services de vérification et de vérification des antécédents, dont la transmission et la gestion des Rapports et de la documentation connexe, et la communication de renseignements sur l’état d’avancement de la collecte de ces renseignements.
    14. « **Utilisateur** » renvoie à vous, à l’Utilisateur initial, à l’Utilisateur final et aux Utilisateurs supplémentaires, selon le cas.
2. **SERVICES.**
    1. Les Services sont fournis conformément aux descriptions mentionnées sur la Plateforme, les documents API ou le Bon de commande, selon le cas. Il vous incombe de lire attentivement la description des Services avant de commander un Rapport.
    2. Vous acceptez d’utiliser les Rapports et la Plateforme conformément aux lois, règles et réglementations en vigueur, qu’elles soient fédérales, provinciales, d’État, locales ou internationales, et notamment la législation sur les rapports de consommation et la protection des données. (« **Lois** »).
3. **CONDITIONS INTERNATIONALES DE TRAITEMENT DES DONNÉES.**  
      
    Les parties conviennent de respecter les conditions énoncées dans l’[Addenda sur le traitement des données](https://vault.pactsafe.io/s/5d800911-f26c-4e3a-884d-85117a81799b/legal.html?g=37964&contract-ryclhyapj) [(](https://docs.google.com/document/d/1B-0ULFJiOsb8M0ZEIXes9ImOgKuM4LlV/edit)l’« **ATD** ») et toute législation applicable en matière de protection des données en ce qui concerne le traitement des Renseignements personnels (au sens de l’ATD), dont l’ensemble des renseignements, données et autres contenus, quelle qu’en soit la forme, transmis, saisis ou téléchargés sur la Plateforme dans le cadre des Services.
4. **CERTIFICATIONS**.
    1. En acceptant les Conditions et/ou en créant un Compte, et chaque fois que vous demandez un Rapport ou y accédez, vous certifiez, en votre qualité d’Utilisateur final ou d’Utilisateur agissant en tant que mandataire de l’Utilisateur final, que vous avez une connaissance directe des faits, et vous attestez et convenez que :
        1. vous aurez un besoin légitime et un Objectif autorisé pour commander ledit Rapport et utiliser les Services;
        2. si le Rapport concerne un résident des États-Unis, votre objectif sera conforme à l’article 604(a) de la FCRA et à toute autre réglementation d’État comparable en matière d’objectif spécifique;
        3. si les Services sont soumis à l’application du RGPD du R.-U. ou du RGPD de l’UE ou que le Rapport concerne des personnes résidant au Royaume-Uni ou dans l’Union européenne, vous aurez un fondement légal explicite correspondant à l’Objectif autorisé permettant le traitement légal des Renseignements personnels, conformément aux Lois sur la protection des données applicable;
        4. vous ne demanderez et n’utiliserez les Rapports qu’au titre des Objectifs autorisés;
        5. vous agirez conformément à toute autre réglementation provinciale, d’État ou locale lorsque vous demanderez, recevrez et utiliserez les Rapports (dont les renseignements en matière de crédit ou les antécédents criminels, le cas échéant); et
        6. le Consommateur peut avoir le droit, en vertu des règlements applicables, d’obtenir une copie de son Rapport; par conséquent, si la demande vous est faite directement, vous acceptez de fournir une copie du Rapport au Consommateur ou de demander immédiatement à Certn de fournir une copie du Rapport au Consommateur en votre nom.
    2. Si vous demandez des Rapports aux États-Unis ou si le Consommateur est un résident des États-Unis :
        1. vous accusez réception des avis légaux suivants et certifiez que vous les avez lus et parfaitement compris :
            * [le résumé de vos droits en vertu de la FCRA](https://files.consumerfinance.gov/f/201504_cfpb_summary_your-rights-under-fcra.pdf);[](https://files.consumerfinance.gov/f/201410_cfpb_summary_remedying-the-effects-of-id-theft-fcra.pdf)
            * [le document intitulé « Remédier aux effets du vol d’identité »](https://files.consumerfinance.gov/f/201410_cfpb_summary_remedying-the-effects-of-id-theft-fcra.pdf)[](https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/CFR-2012-title12-vol8/pdf/CFR-2012-title12-vol8-part1022-appN.pdf)
            * [l’Avis aux utilisateurs de Rapports sur les consommateurs – Obligations des utilisateurs en vertu de la FCRA](https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/CFR-2012-title12-vol8/pdf/CFR-2012-title12-vol8-part1022-appN.pdf).
        2. Si vous utilisez une API à écran dynamique et que Certn ne recueille pas le consentement des Consommateurs ou ne transmet pas de déclaration aux Consommateurs par l’intermédiaire de la Plateforme en votre nom, vous certifiez qu’avant qu’un quelconque Rapport ne vous soit transmis au titre d’un Objectif autorisé : (i) une déclaration claire et bien visible sera transmise par écrit au Consommateur dans un document qui satisfait à toutes les exigences de la FCRA ainsi qu’à toute Loi d’État ou locale applicable, (ii) le Consommateur aura autorisé par écrit la transmission du Rapport par l’Utilisateur final, et aura notamment donné tous les consentements nécessaires requis en vertu des Lois sur la protection des renseignements personnels et des données applicables; et (iii) vous divulguerez clairement et précisément au Consommateur le fait qu’un Rapport d’enquête sur le Consommateur peut inclure des renseignements sur le caractère du Consommateur, sur sa réputation générale, sur ses caractéristiques personnelles et/ou sur son mode de vie.
        3. Avant de prendre une quelconque décision défavorable fondée en tout ou en partie sur un Rapport, vous devrez respecter certaines obligations et, si Certn permet à l’Utilisateur final d’accéder à un outil de décision défavorable, l’Utilisateur final devra confirmer qu’il a étudié et utilisé les actions/lettres défavorables en fonction de la résidence et du lieu de travail du Consommateur conformément aux règles régissant les décisions défavorables, et vous acceptez également ce qui suit :
            1. avant d’émettre des lettres indiquant une décision défavorable ou préalables à une décision défavorable, l’Utilisateur final devra demander l’avis d’un conseiller juridique indépendant pour garantir leur conformité avec les Lois et règlements applicables. Certn décline expressément toute responsabilité eu égard aux démarches que vous effectuerez en vous fondant sur les renseignements figurant dans cette section.
            2. L’Utilisateur final ne lancera aucun processus d’avis de décision défavorable ou préalable à une décision défavorable avant que : (i) Certn ait accompli l’ensemble des étapes de la recherche relativement au Rapport et/ou au Rapport d’enquête sur le Consommateur, (ii) Certn ait remis son Rapport complet et/ou Rapport d’enquête sur le Consommateur complet à l’Utilisateur final, et (iii) l’Utilisateur final ait étudié le contenu du Rapport et/ou du Rapport d’enquête sur le Consommateur.
            3. Si vous utilisez un Rapport relativement à des Objectifs professionnels, avant de prendre toute décision défavorable fondée en tout ou en partie sur le Rapport, vous devrez au moins transmettre au Consommateur que le Rapport concerne : (a) un avis ou une lettre préalable à une décision défavorable indiquant que l’Utilisateur final envisage de prendre une décision défavorable; (b) une copie du Rapport complet incluant les coordonnées de Certn; (c) une copie de l’avis intitulé « Résumé de vos droits en vertu du Fair Credit Reporting Act » et de tout résumé des droits accordés par l’État qui sont applicables; et (d) donner au Consommateur la possibilité raisonnable de corriger tout renseignement erroné figurant dans le Rapport.
            4. Si vous prenez par la suite une décision défavorable en ce qui concerne un emploi, si le Consommateur se voit refuser une location ou si une autre décision défavorable est prise en lien avec un autre Objectif autorisé énoncé à l’article 604(a) de la FCRA, vous devrez donner un avis final de décision défavorable au Consommateur faisant l’objet du Rapport conformément au FCRA et à toute loi d’État applicable.
            5. Vous reconnaissez qu’avant de prendre des décisions défavorables fondées sur un casier judiciaire, le [Conseil sur les antécédents criminels de l’EEOC](https://www.eeoc.gov/laws/guidance/enforcement-guidance-consideration-arrest-and-conviction-records-employment-decisions) recommande que vous effectuiez une évaluation personnalisée et/ou preniez en compte d’autres critères.
            6. Si vous prenez des décisions défavorables en Californie, vous devrez vous conformer aux articles 1785.20 et 1786.40 du Code civil de Californie et transmettre au Consommateur un avis écrit précisant ses droits en vertu de l’ICRA et du CCRAA, définis ci-dessous.
        4. Vous comprenez et certifiez que l’Utilisateur final (ou vous-même en votre qualité de mandataire de l’Utilisateur final) est tenu de se conformer aux exigences, restrictions et lois réglementaires fédérales, provinciales, d’État et/ou locales, et notamment à la législation sur la protection des données, à la FCRA, aux évaluations individualisées prescrites par la Commission de l’égalité d’accès à l’emploi, aux lois locales Ban the Box, aux lois sur l’équité en matière d’emploi et d’embauche, aux lignes directrices HUD et aux lois sur l’équité en matière de logement.
    3. Autres certifications. Vous acceptez ce qui suit :
        1. de ne pas utiliser ou tenter d’utiliser la Plateforme à des fins non autorisées ou au profit d’un tiers non autorisé;
        2. d’utiliser chaque Rapport une seule fois et dans un délai raisonnable;
        3. de respecter la stricte confidentialité des Rapports et ne pas les divulguer d’une manière incompatible avec les Lois applicables en matière de protection des données;
        4. si Certn ne recueille pas de consentements ou d’autorisations et ne fait pas de déclarations au nom de l’Utilisateur final, que l’Utilisateur final doive recueillir et conserver des copies de toutes les autorisations et déclarations écrites pendant une période de trois (3) ans et tenir ces documents à la disposition de Certn;
        5. que Certn puisse examiner les registres de l’Utilisateur final lorsque cela est légitimement requis pour démontrer son respect des Conditions, à tout moment moyennant un préavis raisonnable pendant la Durée de validité et pendant trois (3) ans après son expiration.
5. **EXIGENCES SPÉCIFIQUES À UN PAYS/UNE RÉGION.**
    1. **États-Unis (fédéral)** : VOUS RECONNAISSEZ QUE LA FCRA PRÉVOIT QUE TOUTE PERSONNE QUI OBTIENT SCIEMMENT ET VOLONTAIREMENT DES RENSEIGNEMENTS SUR UN CONSOMMATEUR AUPRÈS D’UNE AGENCE DE RENSEIGNEMENTS SUR LE CONSOMMATEUR SOUS UN PRÉTEXTE FALLACIEUX SERA CONDAMNÉE À UNE AMENDE EN VERTU DU TITRE 18 DU CODE DES ÉTATS-UNIS ET/OU À UNE PEINE D’EMPRISONNEMENT DE DEUX ANS MAXIMUM.
    2. **Californie** : Vous confirmez avoir lu et compris vos obligations en vertu de la Loi sur les agences d’évaluation du crédit à la consommation (Investigative Consumer Reporting Agencies Act ou « ICRAA »), des articles 1786 et suivants du Code civil de Californie, de la Loi sur les agences d’évaluation du crédit à la consommation (Consumer Credit Reporting Agencies Act ou « CCRAA ») et des articles 1785.1 et suivants du Code civil de Californie lorsque vous commandez un Rapport en Californie. En outre, le cas échéant, vous demanderez et utiliserez les Rapports uniquement aux objectifs autorisés énoncés dans les articles 1785.11 et 1786.12 du Code civil de Californie.
    3. **Vermont** : Vous confirmez que vous avez lu et compris les restrictions en matière de rapport sur les consommateurs énoncées à l’[Article 2480e](https://legislature.vermont.gov/statutes/section/09/063/02480e) lorsque vous commandez des Rapports au Vermont.
    4. **New York (État de New York)** : En votre qualité d’Utilisateur final ou de mandataire agissant au nom de l’Utilisateur final, vous devez vous conformer à toutes les exigences applicables en vertu de la Loi de New York sur les droits de la personne (« New York City Humans Rights Law » ou « NYCHRL »). Vous attestez de ce qui suit au titre du NYCHRL : (A) l’Utilisateur final ne saurait obtenir ou évaluer des renseignements sur les antécédents criminels d’un candidat ou d’un employé avant qu’une offre d’emploi conditionnelle, une promotion ou une mutation lui ait été proposée; (B) l’Utilisateur final ne saurait se renseigner sur des antécédents criminels que le NYCHRL interdit de consulter ni en tenir compte; (C) l’Utilisateur final doit s’engager dans tout processus d’évaluation individualisé requis avant de prendre des décisions défavorables envers un Consommateur; et (D) l’Utilisateur final doit suivre toutes les procédures préalables et postérieures aux décisions défavorables requises par la Loi, et il doit notamment s’assurer que toutes les communications préalables et postérieures aux décisions défavorables comprennent tous les renseignements requis par la loi et sont transmises en temps opportun. Nonobstant toute limitation de responsabilité prévue par les Conditions, l’Utilisateur final garantira Certn, ses sociétés affiliées et ses filiales, ainsi que leurs dirigeants, administrateurs, employés, mandataires et assureurs respectifs, contre tous les dommages, pénalités, pertes, responsabilités, jugements, règlements, sentences, coûts et dépenses (ce qui inclut les honoraires et dépenses raisonnables d’avocat) découlant de ou relatifs à des réclamations, allégations, demandes, causes d’action, procès, procédures ou autres actions de tiers, que ce soit en droit ou en equité, qui seraient liés de quelque manière que ce soit au non-respect du NYCHRL par l’Utilisateur final.
6. **EXIGENCES SPÉCIFIQUES AU SERVICE.**
    1. **Registres d’immatriculation des véhicules des É.-U.** : Si vous demandez une vérification des registres d’immatriculation des véhicules et/ou des dossiers de conduite, vous vous engagez à le faire dans le strict respect de la Loi américaine sur la protection de la vie privée des conducteurs (US Driver’s Privacy Protection Act ou « DPPA », articles 18 U.S.C. § 2721 et suivants) et de toute loi d’État applicable; vous vous engagez notamment à n’utiliser ces renseignements que dans le cours normal de vos activités professionnelles (i) pour obtenir des renseignements légaux concernant le titulaire d’un permis de conduire commercial, ou (ii) pour vérifier les renseignements fournis par le Consommateur.
    2. **Trace des numéros de sécurité sociale américains** : Si les Rapports comprennent la trace de numéros de sécurité sociale (une « **Trace** **NSS** »), vous vous engagez à ne pas utiliser les résultats de la Trace NSS de quelque manière que ce soit, directement ou indirectement, dans le cadre des Objectifs professionnels. Vous vous engagez par ailleurs à ne pas utiliser les renseignements figurant dans la Trace NSS d’une manière qui violerait les obligations de confidentialité, toute autre condition et disposition de la loi Gramm-Leach-Bliley (Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act – 15 U.S.C. 6801 et suivants.) ou du DPPA (18.U.S.C. Articles 2721 et suivants) ou une quelconque autre loi, règle ou réglementation d’État ou locale américaine similaire.
    3. **Antécédents criminels** **aux États-Unis** : Certn propose des recherches au niveau du palais de justice du comté, au niveau fédéral et au niveau des bases de données inter-États et nationales, que vous pouvez commander à votre discrétion. Vous reconnaissez que Certn ne sera pas responsable au titre des renseignements figurant dans les bases de données qui n’auront pas été explorées. Veuillez noter que Certn ne signalera que les affaires judiciaires en cours et les antécédents en matière de condamnation; Certn transmettra des renseignements en matière de condamnation sur au moins sept (7) ans lorsque cela est autorisé par une loi applicable en matière d’évaluation du crédit équitable, à moins que l’Utilisateur final ne donne des consignes supplémentaires dans un document distinct signé par l’Utilisateur final et le Consommateur. Il incombe uniquement a l'Utilisateur final de déterminer si les renseignements signalés peuvent être utilisés là où le Consommateur vit, travaille ou postule un emploi, selon le cas.
    4. **Antécédents criminels au Royaume-Uni** : Si vous demandez un extrait de casier judiciaire pour un Consommateur résidant au Royaume-Uni, vous acceptez de vous conformer rigoureusement aux articles des codes relatifs aux employeurs ou aux clients des organismes encadrant le service de divulgation et d’interdiction (Disclosure & Barring Service – « **DBS** »), de Disclosure Scotland (« **DS** ») et/ou d’AccessNI (« **ANI** »), ou aux procédures pertinentes (chacun de ces éléments constituant un « Code »), en particulier pour : (i) vous assurer que les Consommateurs connaissent et reçoivent une copie du Code applicable, au début du processus de recrutement; (ii) mettre en œuvre une politique écrite précisant le processus et les critères utilisés par l’Utilisateur final s’agissant de prendre des décisions en matière d’emploi, de recrutement et/ou d’embauche concernant les Consommateurs ayant des antécédents criminels; (iii) mentionner à Certn les personnes qui, au sein de votre organisation, ont le droit de recevoir les renseignements divulgués et aviser rapidement Certn de tout changement à cet égard; et (iv) à moins que la vérification des antécédents puisse être traitée par le biais d’une vérification d’identification numérique par Certn en votre nom et que vous l’ayez demandé, vous devrez respecter le processus de vérification de l’identité du Consommateur conformément aux directives pertinentes publiées par DBS, DS ou ANI, le cas échéant.
    5. **Cifas au Royaume-Uni** : Si vous demandez une vérification Cifas dans les bases de données Cifas (au sens du guide Cifas Insider Threat Database Handbook), vous : (i) garantissez à Certn que vous êtes membre de Cifas et que vous cesserez de demander ce type de vérification si, pour une raison quelconque, vous cessez d’être membre de Cifas; (ii) reconnaissez que Certn est spécialisé dans le domaine du contrôle (au sens du Cifas Insider Threat Database Handbook), que vous êtes un membre de Cifas déposant un dossier complet, et, qu’à ce titre, ce sera vous, et non Certn, qui devrez assumer la majorité des responsabilités, exigences et démarches énoncées dans le guide Cifas Insider Threat Database Handbook. Pour éviter toute ambiguïté, précisons que Certn effectuera une recherche dans la base de données et vous fournira des données (au sens du Cifas Insider Threat Database Handbook) et, s’il existe une correspondance (au sens du Cifas Insider Threat Database Handbook), vous devrez enquêter sur ladite correspondance et, le cas échéant, déposer une demande conformément au Principe 1 : réciprocité du Cifas Insider Threat Database Handbook; (iii) par les présentes, vous indemnisez et acceptez de dégager Certn (et ses sociétés affiliées) de toute responsabilité (ci-après la clause d’Indemnisation) eu égard à : (A) l’ensemble des réclamations, actions, dommages, dépenses et frais juridiques que Certn (ou ses Sociétés affiliées) pourrait subir ou engager en lien avec ou suite à votre non-respect des conditions de la présente section; (B) l’ensemble des demandes d’indemnisation et frais juridiques que Certn (ou ses Sociétés affiliées) pourrait subir ou engager à la suite de votre violation de l’une quelconque des dispositions de la Loi sur la protection des données ou de toutes les Lois en vigueur, reposant sur des allégations de dommages ou de préjudices moraux suite à votre utilisation du Cifas Insider Threat Database Handbook; (C) l’ensemble des réclamations, actions, dommages, pertes, dépenses et frais juridiques (sur la base d’une indemnisation complète) que Certn (ou ses sociétés affiliées) subirait ou engagerait en lien avec ou suite à toute réclamation selon laquelle vous avez enfreint le Cifas Insider Threat Database Handbook, avez enfreint une Loi ou avez omis de vous conformer aux Lois (ce qui inclut les lois, textes réglementaires et la common law), même si vous avez respecté le Cifas Insider Threat Database Handbook; et (iv) cette clause d’indemnisation s’ajoute, sans la limiter, à toute autre clause d’indemnisation acceptée par vous en vertu du Cifas Insider Threat Database Handbook ou des Conditions sans aucunement en restreindre l’effet ou la force.
    6. **Vérification d’identité numérique au Royaume-Uni** : Lorsque vous faites appel à un prestataire de services d’identité certifiés (Identity Service Providers ou « **IDSP** ») pour effectuer des vérifications d’identité à l’aide de la technologie de validation des documents d’identification (Identification Document Validation Technology ou « **IDVT** ») afin d’obtenir des extraits de casiers judiciaires et de confirmer le droit d’occuper un emploi Royaume-Uni, vous devez être certain que la photo et les détails biographiques enregistrés sont cohérents avec la personne se présentant au travail. Cela fait partie du processus d’établissement d’une excuse légale contre une sanction civile si la personne est ultérieurement reconnue comme travaillant illégalement. Vous devez conserver une copie lisible des résultats de la vérification d’identité numérique pendant la durée de l’emploi et pendant deux (2) ans après la fin de l’emploi. Certn (A) vérifie l’identité de chaque Consommateur à hauteur du coefficient de confiance moyen d’IDVT (au sens du guide publié par le gouvernement du Royaume-Uni pour l’IDVT, tel que modifié le cas échéant); et (B) reconnaît que la prestation des services de Vérification d’identité numérique dépend du fait que Certn et/ou son sous-traitant soient certifiés en tant qu’IDSP.
    7. **Rapports de solvabilité et Renseignements sur la solvabilité** : Si vous demandez des Renseignements sur la solvabilité, vous acceptez de vous conformer à toutes les exigences d’État, provinciales et fédérales en vigueur. Plus précisément, vous comprenez et acceptez que :
        1. **Processus de validation** : Avant toute commande de renseignements fournis par une Agence d’évaluation de crédit (« **Renseignements** **sur la solvabilité** ») auprès de Certn, l’Agence d’évaluation du crédit peut exiger que l’Utilisateur final satisfasse à une inspection virtuelle de ses locaux
        2. **Autres certifications de solvabilité.** Si des Renseignements sur la solvabilité sont demandés :
            1. Certn pourra, à la demande de l’Agence d’évaluation du crédit, vérifier périodiquement que l’Utilisateur final respecte les Conditions, en particulier en matière d’accès et de traitement des Renseignements sur la solvabilité. Tout manquement à coopérer pleinement et rapidement à une vérification légitime constituera un motif de suspension immédiate du service ou de résiliation des Conditions.
            2. L’Utilisateur final indemnisera et dégagera Certn et l’Agence d’évaluation du crédit de toute responsabilité, de quelque nature qu’elle soit, qui pourrait découler de ou se rapporter à (i) la résiliation de l’accès aux Renseignements sur la solvabilité suite à la découverte d’informations dans le cadre d’une inspection demandée par l’Agence d’évaluation du crédit; (ii) la diffusion ou la divulgation des Renseignements sur la solvabilité par l’Utilisateur final, ses employés ou mandataires, en violation des dispositions des Conditions ou des Lois applicables; ou (iii) l’inconduite volontaire de l’Utilisateur final, ou une fraude, une négligence grave ou une violation des Conditions perpétrée par l’Utilisateur final, nonobstant toute limitation de responsabilité énoncée ailleurs dans les Conditions.
            3. L’Utilisateur final sécurisera toutes les copies papier et électroniques des Renseignements sur la solvabilité dans ses bureaux et sur ses sites, le cas échéant, afin que les personnes non autorisées ne puissent pas y accéder facilement;
            4. L’Utilisateur final déchiquettera ou détruira toutes les copies papier des Renseignements sur la solvabilité et supprimera ou rendra illisibles les fichiers électroniques contenant des Renseignements sur la solvabilité lorsqu’ils ne seront plus nécessaires et si les lois le permettent;
            5. L’Utilisateur final sécurisera tous les appareils utilisés pour accéder aux Renseignements sur la solvabilité dans un endroit physiquement sécurisé, accessible aux seuls Utilisateurs, et mettra en œuvre des mesures de sécurité raisonnables lorsque les appareils ne seront pas utilisés;
            6. L’Utilisateur final coopérera pleinement avec l’Agence d’évaluation du crédit en cas de violation impliquant l’accès de l’Utilisateur final aux Renseignements sur la solvabilité par l’intermédiaire de la Plateforme.
            7. Si l’Utilisateur final est un propriétaire foncier ou une société de gestion immobilière, il atteste que s’il demande des Renseignements sur la solvabilité à des fins d’enquête préalable à la location, il a reçu une demande de location en bonne et due forme du Demandeur qui comprend les renseignements nécessaires permettant d’identifier le Demandeur de manière satisfaisante et qu’il a dûment étudié lesdits renseignements.
        3. **Catégories restreintes** : L’Utilisateur final certifie qu’il n’est pas un(e) : détective privé, agence privée de détectives, société d’enquête privée, garant(e) d’une personne mise en liberté sous caution, avocat, cabinet d’avocat, cabinet de conseil en crédit, cabinet de conseil financier, agence de redressement du crédit, bureau de prêteur sur gages, agence d’encaissement de chèques, cabinet de recherche généalogique ou d’héritiers, service de rencontre, service de massage ou de tatouage, entreprises opérant dans des appartements ou des emplacements résidentiels non soumis à des restrictions, personne recherchant des renseignements à des fins personnelles, service quelconque de divertissement pour adultes, entreprise recherchant les enfants disparus, entreprise tierce de reprise de possession, entreprise facturant des frais préalables pour l’allègement d’une dette ou une assistance hypothécaire (à l’exclusion du refinancement des prêts immobiliers ou des services offerts par les avocats), entreprise proposant ou vendant des abonnements ou travaillant par le biais d’abonnements (magazines, clubs de lecture, clubs de disques, etc.), entreprise ou personne prodiguant des conseils spirituels, entité autre qu’un utilisateur final ou un décideur, à moins qu’Equifax ne l’approuve par écrit. Pour plus de clarté, précisons que si l’Utilisateur final réside au Royaume-Uni et que la vérification de solvabilité concerne des résidents britanniques actuels ou d’anciens résidents du Royaume-Uni, cette disposition ne s’applique pas.
        4. **Discrétion de l’Agence d’évaluation du crédit** : L’Agence d’évaluation du crédit se réserve le droit, à sa seule discrétion, de refuser l’accès aux Renseignements sur la solvabilité à certains Utilisateurs, même s’ils répondent aux critères énoncés dans les présentes.
        5. **Cotes de crédit aux États-Unis** : Si l’Utilisateur final utilise une cote de crédit américaine, il certifie qu’il se conformera à la loi Dodd-Frank et à tous les règlements applicables relativement à l’utilisation d’une cote de crédit.
        6. **Solvabilité au Royaume-Uni** : Certn et l’Agence d’évaluation du crédit auront le droit d’appliquer les modalités et conditions mentionnées dans la présente conformément à la Loi de 1999 du United Kingdom Contracts (Rights of Third Parties) Act de 1999.
        7. **Utilisation exclusive et confidentialité** : Tout Renseignement sur la solvabilité devra être conservé dans la plus grande confidentialité à moins que sa divulgation à des tiers ne soit autorisée par le Consommateur ou permise par les Lois en vigueur. Il est strictement interdit aux Utilisateurs de se procurer des Renseignements sur la solvabilité les concernant personnellement, ou concernant leurs associés ou toute autre personne, en dehors du cadre de leurs fonctions officielles et de l’Objectif autorisé. L’Utilisateur final ne saurait vendre, transférer, distribuer ou mettre par ailleurs à disposition des Renseignements sur la solvabilité transmis à un Utilisateur ni utiliser des Renseignements sur la solvabilité au nom d’un tiers.
        8. **Exonération de responsabilité et d’exactitude** : Ni Certn ni l’Agence d’évaluation du crédit ne donnent de garanties ni ne font de déclarations quant à la pertinence des Renseignements sur la solvabilité pour une fin spécifique. L’Utilisateur final reconnaît qu’il lui incombe de s’assurer que les Renseignements sur la solvabilité conviennent à l’utilisation qui doit en être faite. L’Utilisateur final reconnaît que les données recueillies afin d’établir des rapports contenant les Renseignements sur la solvabilité sont obtenues auprès de sources faillibles et comprend que leur exactitude n’est pas garantie par l’Agence d’évaluation du crédit. L’Utilisateur final dégage l’Agence d’évaluation du crédit et ses sociétés affiliées, mandataires, employés et prestataires indépendants de toute responsabilité, même en cas de négligence, qui engagerait l’Agence d’évaluation du crédit, et au titre de toute perte ou dépense subie ou engagée, directement ou indirectement, par l’Utilisateur final en raison de la confiance qu’il aurait accordée aux Renseignements sur la solvabilité.
7. **SÉCURITÉ**.
    1. L’Utilisateur final devra mettre en place un programme de sécurité informatique s’appuyant sur des mesures de protection administratives, techniques et physiques correspondant à la taille et à la complexité de l’Utilisateur final, ainsi qu’à la nature et à la portée de ses activités; ces mesures de protection devront être conçues pour (i) assurer la sécurité et la confidentialité des renseignements fournis par Certn, (ii) protéger contre toute menace ou tout danger anticipé en matière de sécurité et d’intégrité desdits renseignements; et (iii) protéger contre l’accès, l’utilisation, la divulgation, la modification, la destruction ou toute autre interférence non autorisés desdits renseignements qui pourraient entraîner un préjudice ou un inconvénient important pour un Consommateur.
    2. En plus de ce qui précède, l’Utilisateur final mettra en place une politique de confidentialité ou de ressources humaines qui sera clairement et précisément divulguée aux Consommateurs et qui respectera les Lois applicables, et il appliquera des procédures strictes pour s’assurer que le personnel ne peut pas utiliser les Rapports ou les renseignements personnels qui y sont liés à des fins inappropriées, illégales ou non autorisées.
    3. Vous vous engagez à ne pas : (i) copier, distribuer, louer, donner à bail, prêter, accorder en sous-licence ou transférer la Plateforme, et à ne pas mettre la Plateforme à la disposition de tiers, dont vos sociétés affiliées, sociétés apparentées ou filiales, sans le consentement écrit préalable exprès de Certn, (ii) modifier, décompiler, désosser ou désassembler la Plateforme ou tenter autrement de découvrir un code source sous-jacent, ou des idées, algorithmes, formats de fichiers ou interfaces de programmation, (iii) créer des œuvres dérivées de la Plateforme; (iv) modifier, supprimer ou dissimuler une mention de droit d’auteur, une marque de commerce, des avis de brevet, ou d’autres avis ou légendes figurant sur la Plateforme; (v) utiliser la Plateforme pour développer une offre de produits concurrentielle; (vi) utiliser des agents, robots, scripts, araignées ou autres moyens automatisés pour accéder à la Plateforme ou la gérer; ou (vii) permettre à votre personnel d’accéder à la Plateforme ou de demander des Rapports à des fins illégales ou non autorisées, même sur eux-mêmes, leurs associés ou une autre personne, sauf dans l’exercice de leurs fonctions officielles.
    4. Certn mettra les clés API à votre disposition pour accéder à la Plateforme, le cas échéant. Il vous incombe de sécuriser vos clés API et vous vous engagez à ne pas les publier et à ne pas les partager avec des personnes non autorisées, dont vos prestataires de services, sauf approbation écrite de Certn. Vous communiquerez immédiatement avec [security@certn.co](mailto:security@certn.co) si vous prenez connaissance d’une utilisation non autorisée de vos clés API.
8. **RENSEIGNEMENTS CONFIDENTIELS**.
    1. Chaque partie respectera la confidentialité de tous les renseignements et documents fournis ou mis à disposition, directement ou indirectement, par l’autre partie qui sont marqués comme confidentiels ou exclusifs, qui sont signalés comme confidentiels ou exclusifs au moment de leur divulgation, ou dont la nature et la manière dont ils sont divulgués devraient laisser entendre à une personne raisonnable qu’ils sont confidentiels (collectivement, les « **Renseignements confidentiels** »). Les Renseignements confidentiels de Certn comprennent, sans s’y limiter, les caractéristiques, les fonctionnalités et le contenu de la Plateforme, toute modification ou mise à jour prévue de celle-ci, et les Frais et renseignements tarifaires.
    2. Chaque partie garantira la stricte confidentialité de tous les Renseignements confidentiels en appliquant à leur égard le degré de diligence qu’elle met en œuvre à l’égard de ses propres renseignements confidentiels qui ne saurait, en tout état de cause, être moins qu’une diligence raisonnable. Chaque partie ne pourra utiliser les Renseignements confidentiels que pour exécuter ses obligations ou exercer ses droits en vertu des présentes. Les renseignements dont l’une quelconque des parties peut établir : (a) qu’ils étaient légalement en sa possession avant qu’elle les reçoive de l’autre partie; ou (b) qu’ils sont tombés dans le domaine public sans faute de la partie destinataire; ou (c) qu’ils ont été développés ou découverts de manière indépendante par ladite partie sans se fonder sur les renseignements confidentiels de l’autre partie, ne seront pas considérés comme des Renseignements confidentiels en vertu des Conditions. Chaque partie ne pourra divulguer des Renseignements confidentiels qu’à ceux de ses employés et représentants qui ont besoin de les connaître pour atteindre les objectifs prévus par les Conditions et chacun d’entre eux sera tenu de protéger les Renseignements confidentiels contre toute utilisation ou divulgation non autorisée en vertu d’une entente écrite stipulant des conditions aussi protectrices des Renseignements confidentiels que les dispositions des Conditions. Chacune des parties pourra également divulguer des Renseignements confidentiels en réponse à l’ordonnance valable d’un tribunal ou d’un autre organisme gouvernemental ou si la loi l’exige, à condition que la partie devant effectuer la divulgation donne un préavis suffisant à la partie émettrice desdits renseignements pour permettre à ladite partie émettrice de prendre des mesures de protection, et/ou qu’elle ne divulgue, quoi qu’il arrive, que tout ou partie des Renseignements confidentiels qui sont spécifiquement demandés.
    3. Chaque partie convient que toute violation de ces dispositions de confidentialité causera un préjudice irréparable à l’autre partie qui autorisera l’autre partie à demander une injonction ou une autre mesure équitable, en plus, et non en remplacement, de tout autre recours auquel ladite partie pourrait avoir droit. La divulgation des Renseignements confidentiels sera régie par les Conditions qui remplacent tout accord de confidentialité ou de non-divulgation antérieurement signé par ou au nom des parties. Lesdits Renseignements confidentiels seront traités comme s’ils avaient été divulgués en vertu des Conditions à la date de leur divulgation.
9. **FRAIS**.
    1. Vous devez payer Certn pour chaque Service demandé au taux indiqué dans la Plateforme, votre MSA ou Formulaire de commande, selon le cas (les « Frais ») plus les coûts et frais variables supplémentaires qui peuvent être imposés par des entités gouvernementales ou des tiers au titre des Services que vous demandez, et notamment les frais de vérification, les frais de greffe, les frais de traitement du comté, les frais inter-États et les frais internationaux, ainsi que les taxes clairement indiqués dans votre facture. Vous serez redevable de chaque Service que vous demanderez, et notamment des Rapports indiquant « rien à signaler », « impossible à vérifier » ou une autre mention similaire, et/ou une erreur de l’utilisateur lors de la saisie de données, des saisies en double et/ou une annulation par vous ou le Consommateur. Sauf indication contraire dans votre CCS ou votre Bon de commande, le paiement de tous les frais facturés sera dû dans les trente (30) jours suivant votre réception de la facture. La phrase précédente ne s’appliquera pas aux Services réglés par carte de crédit au moment de la commande.
    2. Certn se réserve le droit d’ajuster les Frais chaque année, qui vous seront communiqués avec un préavis d’au moins trente (30) jours.
    3. Nonobstant l’article 9(b), si un gouvernement ou un organisme de réglementation augmente ses frais pour tout Service fourni, Certn peut ajuster les Frais en conséquence pour vous répercuter entièrement ces coûts accrus. Vous serez avisé de tout ajustement de ces Frais au moins trente (30) jours à l’avance.
10. **RETENUES FISCALES.**  
      
    Certn pourra retenir tout impôt en votre nom, si vous le demandez, conformément aux Lois applicables. Il vous incombe de connaître toutes les lois, réglementations et obligations fiscales applicables dans votre région concernant ces retenues et d’informer Certn du montant spécifique à retenir et de toute autre obligation similaire. Vous vous engagez à fournir à Certn des renseignements exacts en temps opportun concernant tout changement des lois ou obligations fiscales qui pourrait affecter le processus de retenue. Certn décline toute responsabilité au titre des éventuelles pénalités, amendes ou autres responsabilités qui découleraient du fait que vous ignorez ou omettez d’informer Certn des lois fiscales applicables ou de toute taxe liée à la présente entente.
11. **ACCÈS AUX CONSENTEMENTS.**  
      
    Vous reconnaissez et acceptez que pour maintenir la conformité aux obligations légales, réglementaires et contractuelles, Certn se réserve le droit d’effectuer des vérifications à sa discrétion pour s’assurer que vous avez présenté et obtenu les consentements, les autorisations et les divulgations lors de l’accès aux Services par l’intermédiaire de l’API, et que ces consentements sont entièrement conformes aux lois et règlements applicables. Ces vérifications peuvent être effectuées par Certn ou un vérificateur tiers nommé par Certn, et vous acceptez de coopérer pleinement à ces vérifications, en donnant accès à tous les dossiers et documents pertinents sur demande.
12. **DONNÉES D’UTILISATION**.  
      
    Certn détient tous les droits, titres et intérêts relativement à toutes les données recueillies par Certn dans le cadre de l’exploitation de la Plateforme et de votre utilisation de celle-ci (les « **Données d’utilisation** »). Les Données d’utilisation peuvent inclure des mesures et des analyses de performance de la Plateforme, mais n’incluent pas de renseignements personnels ou de données publiques. Certn ne divulguera pas, sans votre consentement, de Données d’utilisation à des tiers d’une manière qui permettrait de vous identifier si ce n’est (i) aux prestataires de services tiers qui les utilisent pour le seul bénéfice de Certn ou selon ce qui est requis pour vous fournir la Plateforme; ou (ii) comme pourrait l’exiger la loi ou une procédure judiciaire.
13. **PROPRIÉTÉ INTELLECTUELLE.**
    1. Certn possède, ou a des droits exclusifs sur, tous les titres, intérêt, et droits de propriété relatifs aux brevets, droits d’auteur, marques de commerce, secrets commerciaux, savoir-faire, moyens de masquage, droits moraux et autres droits similaires, existant maintenant ou créés ultérieurement dans n’importe quel pays, et comprend notamment toute demande et tout enregistrement relatifs aux éléments susmentionnés (« **Droits de propriété intellectuelle** ») sur la Plateforme et tous les logiciels, technologies, matériels et renseignements associés à la Plateforme, qu’ils existent actuellement ou qu’ils soient développés ultérieurement.
    2. Vous possédez tous les droits, titres, intérêts et Droits de propriété intellectuelle relatifs aux Rapports et à toute application logicielle que vous possédez ou contrôlez (à l’exclusion des API ou marques de commerce de Certn qui y sont incorporées).
    3. Si vous transmettez des commentaires à Certn, vous acceptez de céder à Certn tous les droits, titres et intérêts relativement auxdits commentaires, et acceptez que Certn puisse librement utiliser et exploiter lesdits commentaires sans vous dédommager à cet égard.
14. **INDEMNISATION.**
    1. Vous acceptez de défendre, d’indemniser et de dégager de toute responsabilité Certn, et ses administrateurs, dirigeants et employés, eu égard à toute responsabilité envers des tiers, dommages, pertes, jugements, coûts, dépenses (ce qui inclut les honoraires d’avocat raisonnables), réclamations, actions, demandes et poursuites (collectivement, les « **Réclamations de Certn** ») découlant de : (a) votre violation d’une quelconque certification; (b) toute décision de transmettre ou transmission par vous d’une copie du Rapport à un tiers en violation des Conditions, ou (c) une conduite frauduleuse ou malveillante de la part de l’Utilisateur final ou des employés de l’Utilisateur final.
    2. Certn s’engage à défendre et à indemniser l’Utilisateur final, et ses administrateurs, dirigeants et employés, eu égard à toute responsabilité envers des tiers, dommages, pertes, jugements, coûts, dépenses (ce qui inclut les honoraires d’avocat raisonnables), réclamations, actions, demandes et poursuites (collectivement, les « **Réclamations de l’Utilisateur final** ») découlant de : (a) la violation de droits de propriété intellectuelle, dont notamment les brevets, marques de commerce, secrets commerciaux et droits d’auteur suite à l’utilisation de la Plateforme ou des Services, ou (b) une conduite frauduleuse ou malveillante de la part de Certn ou des employés de Certn.
15. **AVIS DE NON-RESPONSABILITÉ.**
    1. VOUS RECONNAISSEZ QUE CERTN OBTIENT LES RENSEIGNEMENTS QUI FIGURENT DANS SES RAPPORTS DE SOURCES TIERCES « EN L’ÉTAT » ET VOUS FOURNIT EN CONSÉQUENCE LESDITS RENSEIGNEMENTS « EN L’ÉTAT » ET « SELON LEUR DISPONIBILITÉ ». CERTN NE FAIT AUCUNE DÉCLARATION ET N’OFFRE AUCUNE GARANTIE, EXPRESS OU IMPLICITE, ET NOTAMMENT AUCUNE GARANTIE IMPLICITE DE QUALITÉ MARCHANDE OU D’ADÉQUATION À UN USAGE PARTICULIER, NI AUCUNE GARANTIE IMPLICITE DÉCOULANT DE LA CONDUITE DES AFFAIRES OU DES MODALITÉS D’EXÉCUTION EN CE QUI CONCERNE L’EXACTITUDE, LA VALIDITÉ OU L’EXHAUSTIVITÉ D’UN QUELCONQUE RAPPORT, OU RELATIVEMENT AU FAIT QUE LES RAPPORTS RÉPONDRONT À VOS BESOINS OU SERONT FOURNIS SANS INTERRUPTION, À MOINS QU’UNE TELLE GARANTIE NE PUISSE ÊTRE LÉGALEMENT EXCLUE OU MODIFIÉE; CERTN DÉCLINE EXPRESSÉMENT TOUTE DÉCLARATION ET GARANTIE DE CE TYPE. SAUF INDICATION EXPRESSE DANS LES CONDITIONS, CERTN DÉCLINE EXPRESSÉMENT LES GARANTIES IMPLICITES DE QUALITÉ MARCHANDE, D’ABSENCE DE CONTREFAÇON ET D’ADÉQUATION À UN USAGE PARTICULIER, ET LES GARANTIES IMPLICITES DÉCOULANT DU COURS DES AFFAIRES OU DES MODALITÉS D’EXÉCUTION. CERTN ET SES FOURNISSEURS, CONCÉDANTS DE LICENCE, PARTENAIRES ET PRESTATAIRES DE SERVICES NE GARANTISSENT PAS QUE LA FONCTIONNALITÉ DE LA PLATEFORME ET LES RENSEIGNEMENTS FOURNIS PAR LA PLATEFORME SERONT CORRECTS, ININTERROMPUS OU EXEMPTS D’ERREURS, OU QUE LEURS DÉFAUTS SERONT CORRIGÉS.
    2. CERTN DÉCLINE TOUTE RESPONSABILITÉ AU TITRE DES RÉSULTATS OU DES DÉCISIONS PRISES EN FONCTION DES RÉSULTATS FOURNIS DANS LES RAPPORTS. VOTRE SEUL ET UNIQUE RECOURS EN CE QUI CONCERNE LE CONTENU DES RAPPORTS EST DE CONTESTER LEURS RÉSULTATS.
    3. TOUT ÉVENTUEL DOCUMENT PROMOTIONNEL FOURNI PAR CERTN EST FOURNI À TITRE INFORMATIF SEULEMENT, N’EST PAS RÉGI PAR LES CONDITIONS ET N’A AUCUNE FORCE CONTRACTUELLE.
16. **LIMITATION DE RESPONSABILITÉ.**
    1. DANS LA MESURE MAXIMALE PERMISE PAR LA LOI, CERTN NE SERA PAS RESPONSABLE DES DOMMAGES INDIRECTS, PUNITIFS, SPÉCIAUX, ACCESSOIRES, CONSÉCUTIFS OU SIMILAIRES (DONT LES PERTES DE REVENUS OU DE PROFITS), OU RÉSULTANT DE LA CONFIANCE ACCORDÉE, QUI DÉCOULERAIENT DES CONDITIONS OU S’Y RAPPORTERAIENT, ET NOTAMMENT CONCERNANT L’UTILISATION OU L’INCAPACITÉ D’UTILISER LE SERVICE, OU TOUT RENSEIGNEMENT OBTENU À PARTIR DU SERVICE OU PAR L’INTERMÉDIAIRE DE CELUI-CI, OU TOUTE INTERRUPTION, INEXACTITUDE OU ERREUR DANS LE CONTENU, MÊME SI CERTN A ÉTÉ INFORMÉ DE LA POSSIBILITÉ DE TELS DOMMAGES.
    2. LA RESPONSABILITÉ CUMULATIVE ET GLOBALE DE CERTN DÉCOULANT DE CES CONDITIONS SE LIMITERA AU MONTANT LE PLUS ÉLEVÉ ENTRE LE MONTANT QUE L’UTILISATEUR FINAL AURA EFFECTIVEMENT PAYÉ AU COURS DE LA PÉRIODE DE DOUZE (12) MOIS PRÉCÉDANT LA DATE DE LA RÉCLAMATION, OU 100 000,00 USD. LE RECOUVREMENT DE CE MONTANT SERA VOTRE SEUL ET UNIQUE RECOURS EN VERTU DES PRÉSENTES, ET LES PARTIES CONVIENNENT QUE LES LIMITATIONS ET EXONÉRATIONS DE RESPONSABILITÉ ÉNONCÉES DANS LA PRÉSENTE SECTION S’APPLIQUERONT MÊME SI UN RECOURS LIMITÉ SPÉCIFIÉ DANS LES CONDITIONS EST RÉPUTÉ N’AVOIR PAS REMPLI SON OBJECTIF ESSENTIEL ET QUELLE QUE SOIT LA THÉORIE DE LA RESPONSABILITÉ INVOQUÉE. LES PARTIES CONVIENNENT QUE LES LIMITATIONS ET AVIS DE NON-RESPONSABILITÉ STIPULÉS DANS LA PRÉSENTE SECTION CONSTITUENT UNE BASE FONDAMENTALE DE LEUR NÉGOCIATION.
    3. NONOBSTANT TOUTE AUTRE DISPOSITION DES PRÉSENTES, AUCUNE DES PARTIES NE SAURAIT LIMITER OU EXCLURE SA RESPONSABILITÉ AU TITRE DE RÉCLAMATIONS DÉCOULANT D’UNE FRAUDE, DE SON INCONDUITE VOLONTAIRE OU DE SA NÉGLIGENCE GRAVE.
17. **MISES À JOUR.**
    1. Certn pourra modifier ses fournisseurs, les fonctionnalités de la Plateforme et la production, le soutien, la livraison, la mise en page ou la maintenance des Rapports, le cas échéant, ou interrompre la fourniture d’un Rapport, à sa seule discrétion, à condition qu’aucun changement de ce type ne se traduise par une réduction importante de l’utilité, de la fonctionnalité ou de l’intégrité des services de Certn qui vous sont offerts. Certn déploiera des efforts raisonnables d’un point de vue commercial pour vous donner un préavis d’au moins trente (30) jours concernant tout changement important impactant les Services de manière défavorable.
    2. Vous reconnaissez que Certn peut mettre à jour un Rapport dans le cadre de tout examen effectué par Certn au titre de l’assurance qualité dans les trente (30) jours suivant la date d’achèvement du Rapport. Le cas échéant, Certn vous transmettra, à vous et au Consommateur, un exemplaire du Rapport mis à jour.
18. **DURÉE ET RÉSILIATION.**
    1. L’entente entre les parties prendra effet à la date d’entrée en vigueur et prendra fin lors de sa résiliation par l’une des parties ou les deux, conformément à ce qui suit (la « **Durée** »).
    2. Certn pourra suspendre, limiter ou mettre fin à votre accès à la Plateforme ou à votre utilisation de celle-ci, aux Services ou à votre Compte à tout moment : (i) si l’Utilisateur final ne paie pas tous les frais dus en temps opportun; (ii) à la seule discrétion de Certn, si une telle action est nécessaire pour prévenir des erreurs ou des préjudices importants; (iii) si vous tentez d’accéder ou d’utiliser la Plateforme ou les Rapports d’une manière non autorisée ou illégale; (iv) si Certn a des raisons valables de penser que vous avez enfreint les Conditions; (v) si cela est demandé par un fournisseur de données tiers ou un organisme de réglementation; ou (vii) si un changement important des obligations légales existantes affecte de manière négative votre accès aux Services. Certn pourra (sans y être obligé) résilier votre compte si vous êtes inactif sur la Plateforme pendant plus de six (6) mois.
    3. Chacune des parties pourra résilier les Conditions pour une raison quelconque moyennant d’adresser un préavis écrit de trente (30) jours à l’autre partie, étant entendu que vous demeurerez redevable de tous les Frais engagés jusqu’à la date de résiliation.  

19. **ABSENCE DE CONSEIL JURIDIQUE.**
    1. Certn ne vous fournit pas, et ne peut pas vous fournir, de conseils juridiques ou d’autres services liés à la conformité, ni ne garantit votre conformité aux Lois dans le cadre de votre utilisation de la Plateforme ou des Rapports. Vous comprenez que toute documentation, information, conversation ou communication avec les représentants de Certn concernant des recherches, des vérifications ou d’autres services offerts par Certn ne saurait être considérée comme un avis juridique concernant une ladite utilisation. Vous convenez de consulter votre propre conseiller juridique (1) au sujet de l’utilisation des Rapports, notamment eu égard à la légalité de leur utilisation ou à la confiance accordée aux renseignements recueillis; et (2) s’agissant d’examiner tout Formulaire de Certn ainsi que le contenu des autorisations prescrites, des avis, des lettres préalables à une décision défavorable ou de décision défavorable et de toute pièce jointe aux Conditions pour vérifier leur conformité à l’ensemble des Lois. Vous convenez que l’envoi desdits avis et lettres de décision défavorable ou préalables à une décision défavorable, et leur teneur relèvent de votre seule responsabilité. Vous reconnaissez et convenez que vous n’êtes aucunement tenu d’utiliser les éventuels formulaires types et qu’il vous incombe de vérifier, de manière indépendante, la teneur de tout formulaire type que Certn vous fournit.
    2. Les renseignements divulgués par Certn (et notamment les Rapports) ne sauraient en aucun cas être interprétés comme l’avis de Certn sur la solvabilité, la capacité, les aptitudes, l’expérience, la situation financière, la surface financière, l’intégrité ou les motifs d’une partie ou d’un Consommateur faisant l’objet d’un Rapport. L’usage des Rapports ou des renseignements découlant de l’utilisation des Services suppose que vous fassiez preuve de discernement et de certaines compétences. Les renseignements fournis dans le cadre des services reflètent simplement un enregistrement des renseignements reçus ponctuellement par Certn auprès de diverses sources et, à ce titre, le Certn n’accepte aucune responsabilité pour les opinions, les recommandations, les prévisions, les commentaires, actions ou décisions prises en se fondant sur ces renseignements.
20. **DISPOSITIONS GÉNÉRALES**.
    1. **Loi applicable.** Si l’Utilisateur final est situé aux États-Unis, les Conditions seront régies et interprétées conformément aux lois de l’État du Delaware, sans donner effet à leurs principes en matière de conflit de lois. Si l’Utilisateur final est situé au Royaume-Uni ou dans l’Union européenne, les Conditions seront régies par les lois de l’Angleterre et du Pays de Galles, sans égard pour leurs principes en matière de conflit de lois qui imposeraient l’application des lois d’une autre juridiction. Si l’Utilisateur final est situé en Australie ou dans la région Asie-Pacifique, les Conditions seront régies par les lois de l’État de Victoria, en Australie, et du Commonwealth d’Australie, sans égard pour leurs principes en matière de conflit de lois qui imposeraient l’application des lois d’une autre juridiction. Si l’Utilisateur final est situé au Canada ou ailleurs que dans les juridictions susmentionnées, les Conditions seront régies par les lois de la province de Colombie-Britannique sans égard pour leurs principes en matière de conflit de lois qui imposeraient l’application des lois d’une autre juridiction.
    2. **Cession**. Vous ne pouvez céder aucun de vos droits ou obligations en vertu des Conditions sans le consentement écrit préalable de Certn qui ne saurait vous le refuser sans motif valable. Sous réserve de ce qui précède, les droits et obligations prévus par les Conditions s’appliqueront au profit de vos ayants droit, cessionnaires et successeurs autorisés et leur seront opposables. Toute tentative de cession effectuée en violation de cette clause sera nulle et non avenue.
    3. **Dispositions relatives à l’arbitrage applicables aux Consommateurs.** Si vous avez des conditions d’utilisation, un document ou une entente similaire applicables aux Consommateurs qui comprennent une disposition d’arbitrage, vous acceptez d’ajouter le texte suivant (ou un texte substantiellement similaire) à ladite disposition d’arbitrage : « Nos droits et obligations en vertu de la présente disposition d’arbitrage s’appliquent au bénéfice de l’agence d’information sur le consommateur, que l’agence de renseignements sur le consommateur soit nommée comme codéfendeur avec nous ou désignée à titre individuel eu égard à toute réclamation qui serait par ailleurs subordonnée à la présente disposition d’arbitrage si elle était formulée contre nous. »
    4. **Respect des sanctions.** Ni vous, ni une quelconque personne ayant un intérêt bénéficiaire direct ou indirect dans votre entité (i) n’a fait ni ne fait l’objet de sanctions administrées ou appliquées par les États-Unis (dont notamment le Bureau du contrôle des actifs étrangers du Département du Trésor des États-Unis), le Royaume-Uni, l’Union européenne, le Canada ou une autre autorité gouvernementale (collectivement, les « Sanctions »), (ii) n’est constituée ou domiciliée dans un pays ou un territoire faisant l’objet de sanctions à l’échelle du pays ou du territoire; ni (iii) n’est par ailleurs une partie avec laquelle Certn n’est pas autorisée à faire affaire en vertu des Lois applicables.
    5. **Assurance**. Les parties doivent, pendant la Durée de validité, conserver en vigueur une couverture d’assurance appropriée conformément aux meilleures pratiques applicables au secteur de ladite partie.
    6. **Intégration**. Les Conditions, ainsi que les Conditions du Site Web, l’ATD et tout(e) annexe, document ou pièce jointe directement mentionnés dans les présentes, reflètent l’intégralité de l’accord des parties concernant son objet et remplacent tout accord antérieur ou contemporain sur ce sujet. Pour éviter toute ambiguïté, il est précisé que, si vous avez signé un CCS ou un Bon de commande distinct, les conditions dudit instrument régiront la relation entre les parties et remplaceront les Conditions comme indiqué spécifiquement dans l’accord concerné.
    7. **Force majeure.** Certn ne sera pas responsable de tout éventuel manquement ou retard dans son exécution des obligations que lui imposent les Conditions qui découlerait de causes indépendantes de sa volonté, dont notamment les conflits du travail, grèves, lockouts; pannes d’Internet ou des systèmes de télécommunication; pénuries de main-d’œuvre ou incapacités à trouver de la main-d’œuvre, de l’énergie ou des fournitures; guerres, attentats terroristes, émeutes; catastrophes naturelles; mesures gouvernementales; actes de piraterie informatique ou émanant d’autres tiers malveillants, et problèmes rencontrés sur Internet en général; le cas échéant, l’exécution sera excusée dans la mesure où elle est empêchée ou retardée en raison d’un des événements susmentionnés.
    8. **Relation**. Ces Conditions ne créent aucune relation d’agence, de partenariat ou de coentreprise, ni aucun pouvoir de lier l’autre partie.
    9. **Divisibilité**. Si une disposition est jugée inapplicable, ladite disposition et toute disposition connexe seront interprétées de manière à remplir au mieux l’objectif essentiel des dispositions inapplicables.
    10. **Absence de renonciation. T**oute renonciation à une disposition des Conditions ne sera valable que si elle est établie par écrit et qu’elle ne s’applique qu’à l’élément spécifique mentionné. Le défaut d’appliquer une disposition ne saurait constituer une renonciation à ladite disposition.
    11. **Réparation en equity** Rien dans les Conditions ne saurait limiter la capacité d’une partie à demander réparation en equity. Les titres des sections ne sauraient servir à interpréter les présentes.
    12. **Clause de survie**. Toutes les dispositions qui, de par leur nature, sont destinées à survivre, et notamment les obligations de paiement, les avis de non-responsabilité, les obligations de confidentialité et d’indemnisation, et les limitations de responsabilité, survivront à la résiliation des Conditions, de même que les dispositions de ce type énoncées dans tout(e) addenda, pièce jointe et/ou annexe joints aux présentes.
21. **ASSISTANCE**.  
      
    Vous pouvez demander de l’assistance concernant la Plateforme pendant les heures d’ouverture normales de Certn, par courriel à [support@certn.co](mailto:support@certn.co). Bien que Certn fasse tout son possible d’un point de vue commercial pour assurer la disponibilité continue de la Plateforme, Certn ne fait aucune déclaration et ne donne aucune garantie concernant le fait que la Plateforme sera disponible et fonctionnera sans interruption.
22. **AVIS**.  
      
    Une communication électronique (un « **Avis électronique** ») sera considérée comme un avis écrit aux fins des Conditions si elle est envoyée à l’adresse électronique indiquée ci-dessous ou à l’adresse spécifiée par la partie destinataire. L’Avis électronique sera réputé avoir été reçu au moment où la partie qui envoie l’Avis électronique recevra confirmation de sa réception par la partie destinataire.  
    Avis adressé par courriel à Certn : [compliance@certn.co](mailto:compliance@certn.co) ou courrier postal : 1006 Fort St Suite 300, Victoria, BC V8V 3K4.  

POLITIQUE DE CONFIDENTIALITÉ - FR
---------------------------------

### Version 1.2

##### Effective June 25th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**POLITIQUE DE CONFIDENTIALITÉ**
================================

Notre mission est de contribuer à renforcer votre sécurité et votre confiance en fournissant des services internationaux de vérification des données et des antécédents. Notre engagement à protéger votre droit à la vie privée est au cœur de notre mission de promotion de la fiabilité et de la confiance. Cette politique décrit la façon dont nous recueillons, utilisons et partageons vos renseignements personnels, notamment:

* pour vous offrir une meilleure expérience sur notre site Web grâce à la collecte de données statistiques de navigation anonymisées provenant de l’utilisation de témoins ou d’autres technologies;
* pour gérer votre compte lorsque vous vous êtes inscrit chez nous, y compris pour gérer votre inscription, le cas échéant, et fournir une meilleure assistance et un meilleur soutien;
* pour communiquer avec nos Clients ou Consommateurs par courriel, téléphone ou toute autre forme de communication électronique équivalente, au besoin et en lien avec le Service demandé;
* pour vous fournir des nouvelles et des renseignements généraux sur nos Services;
* pour produire un rapport sur le consommateur à votre sujet, si vous avez soumis et consenti à une demande de vérification d’antécédents avec nous, ou avec notre Client.

En utilisant les sites Web et les Services de Certn, tels que définis ci-dessous, vous confirmez avoir lu, compris et accepté la présente Politique.

**1\. QUI SOMMES-NOUS ET QUI ÊTES-VOUS?**
-----------------------------------------

La présente politique de confidentialité (la « **Politique** ») décrit la façon dont Certn Holdings Inc. et ses sociétés affiliées y compris Certn (Canada) Inc., Certn (États-Unis) Inc., Credence Background Screening (UK) et toute autre filiale en propriété exclusive (collectivement « **Certn** » ou « **nous** » ou « **notre** »), collecte, utilise, divulgue et traite les Renseignements personnels en rapport avec les sites Web appartenant à Certn (le ou les « **sites Web** »), ainsi que ses produits et services (nos « **Services** »).

La présente Politique s’applique aux utilisateurs suivants :

**« Consommateur »** : Personnes au sujet desquelles nous avons reçu des renseignements dans le cadre de l’utilisation de nos sites Web ou de la prestation de nos Services.

**« Clients »** : Organismes ou personnes utilisant nos Services.

**« Visiteurs du site Web »** : Personnes, Consommateurs ou Clients d’âge légal accédant à notre site Web.

Nous ne sollicitons pas sciemment des renseignements de personnes de moins de treize (13) ans. Si vous avez connaissance de Renseignements personnels partagés par un enfant ou en son nom, veuillez communiquer avec nous en utilisant les coordonnées fournies dans la section « Nous joindre » ci-dessous.

**2\. QU’EST-CE QUE LES RENSEIGNEMENTS PERSONNELS ET QU’EN FAISONS-NOUS?**
--------------------------------------------------------------------------

Aux fins de la présente Politique, on entend par « **Renseignements personnels** » toute information qui identifie, concerne, décrit, peut être associée ou pourrait raisonnablement être associée, directement ou indirectement, à une personne identifiée ou identifiable.

Les Renseignements personnels ne comprennent pas les renseignements commerciaux, comme l’adresse et le numéro de téléphone professionnels de nos Clients.

Nous recueillons, traitons et divulguons uniquement les Renseignements personnels requis dans le cadre de la prestation de nos Services. Le « **traitement** » (ou « **traite** » ou « **traités** ») comprend toute opération ou tout ensemble d’opérations effectuées sur des Renseignements personnels ou sur des ensembles de Renseignements personnels, que ce soit ou non par des moyens automatisés. Cela inclut la collecte, l’enregistrement, l’organisation, la structuration, le stockage, l’adaptation ou la modification, la récupération, la consultation, l’utilisation, la divulgation par transmission, le transfert, la diffusion ou toute autre forme de mise à disposition, l’alignement ou la combinaison, la restriction, l’effacement ou la destruction des Renseignements personnels.

Nous ne prenons pas de décisions à votre sujet, de manière automatisée ou autre, et nous ne tentons pas d’analyser ou de prédire votre comportement, vos préférences, vos intérêts, votre santé ou d’autres caractéristiques personnelles. Cependant, il est possible que nous effectuions un Traitement automatisé selon les instructions de notre Client.

En utilisant notre site Web ou nos Services, vous consentez au Traitement de vos Renseignements personnels, sous réserve des dispositions de la présente Politique. **Si vous n’êtes pas d’accord avec la présente Politique ou si vous ne souhaitez pas nous fournir vos Renseignements personnels, veuillez ne pas utiliser notre site Web ou nos Services.**

Si vous choisissez de nous fournir un nombre limité de Renseignements personnels, il se peut que nous ne soyons pas en mesure de fournir toute notre gamme de Services ou d’offrir la meilleure expérience possible sur notre site Web.

**3\. QUELS SONT NOS PRINCIPES DE TRAITEMENT DES RENSEIGNEMENTS?**
------------------------------------------------------------------

Nous nous engageons à protéger vos Renseignements personnels et à respecter les principes suivants, quel que soit le type de Traitement des données que nous effectuons pour vous :

1. **Légalité, équité et transparence lors du Traitement des Renseignements personnels :** Tous les Renseignements personnels recueillis en lien avec nos Services sont traités en tenant compte de l’intérêt contractuel mutuel de notre Client et du Consommateur.
2. **Intégrité et confidentialité :** Certn protège les données contre l’accès non autorisé ou illégal et les dommages accidentels. Nous sommes certifiés SOC 2, SOC 3 et ISO 27001. Pour en savoir plus sur la façon dont nous protégeons les Renseignements personnels et non personnels, veuillez communiquer avec nos agents de protection de la vie privée (coordonnées ci-dessous).
3. **Limitation de la finalité :** Nos conditions stipulent que les Clients sont tenus de certifier une Finalité autorisée, telle que définie ci-dessous, avant d’utiliser nos Services. Les Consommateurs sont informés de la Finalité autorisée avant que nous traitions tout Renseignement personnel.
4. **Minimisation des données** **:** Nous recueillons uniquement les Renseignements personnels nécessaires pour fournir les Services conformément à la Finalité autorisée.
5. **Limite de stockage :** Certn ne conservera les données que le temps nécessaire à la réalisation de la Finalité autorisée définie, à nos responsabilités légales ou à l’exécution de nos engagements contractuels.
6. **Exactitude des données :** Certn prend des mesures raisonnables pour s’assurer que les Renseignements personnels traités sont complets, à jour et exacts. Pour nous assurer que toutes les données sont vérifiées avec exactitude, nous encourageons les Consommateurs à examiner leurs saisies de données avant de soumettre une vérification par l’entremise de notre plateforme. Nous offrons aux demandeurs la possibilité de corriger leurs Renseignements personnels et de traiter les différends pour toute inexactitude signalée.
7. **Responsabilité :** Certn croit en la transparence du Traitement des données et au contrôle des Consommateurs. Nous collaborons avec nos Clients et notre personnel dans le respect des droits à la vie privée des Consommateurs et afin de maintenir les politiques et procédures standard de l’industrie pour opérationnaliser la protection de la vie privée dans toutes les activités de traitement des données à l’interne et à l’externe. Certn a nommé un agent de protection de la vie privée désigné et nous vous encourageons à communiquer avec lui à l’adresse [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co) pour toute question ou tout commentaire que vous pourriez avoir en lien avec la présente Politique ou le Traitement de vos Renseignements personnels.

**4\. COMMENT CETTE POLITIQUE EST-ELLE MISE À JOUR?**
-----------------------------------------------------

**Nous nous** réservons le droit de modifier la présente Politique à tout moment. On encourage tous les visiteurs du site Web à consulter périodiquement la présente Politique pour se tenir informés des mises à jour. Si vous continuez à utiliser notre site Web et nos Services après l’affichage des modifications apportées à la présente Politique, cela signifie que vous acceptez la nouvelle Politique révisée et que vous consentez à être lié par celle-ci.

**5\. QUELS RENSEIGNEMENTS PERSONNELS RECUEILLONS-NOUS, POURQUOI, COMMENT ET AUPRÈS DE QUI?**
---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

### **Fondement juridique du traitement**

**Nous** traitons vos Renseignements personnels pour (i) fournir nos Services, (ii) pour communiquer avec vous, (iii) à des fins de sécurité et de prévention des fraudes, et (iv) pour se conformer à la loi. Nous pouvons également utiliser les Renseignements personnels à d’autres fins assujetties à votre consentement. Nous ne traiterons pas vos Renseignements personnels à moins que nous en ayons légalement le droit de le faire. .

Pour Traiter vos Renseignements personnels en toute légalité, nous nous appuyons au minimum sur un fondement juridique tel que défini par la loi applicable. En fonction de la relation que vous entretenez avec nous, le fondement juridique permettant de Traiter vos Renseignements personnels peut inclure, entre autres, votre consentement, l’obligation de Traiter les données pour l’exécution d’un contrat avec vous, pour se conformer à une obligation légale ou sur la base d’un intérêt légitime.

Si votre consentement représente le fondement juridique sur lequel nous nous appuyons afin de recueillir et d’utiliser vos Renseignements personnels, vous pouvez retirer ou modifier votre consentement à la collecte ou à l’utilisation future de vos Renseignements personnels à tout moment, et nous vous expliquerons les conséquences de ce geste. Si nous utilisons vos Renseignements personnels à des fins de vente ou de marketing, vous pouvez nous demander d’interrompre cette activité à tout moment et nous agirons en conséquence.

### **Finalité autorisée pour le traitement**

Nos Clients doivent certifier avoir un objectif autorisé avant que nous puissions Traiter les Renseignements personnels aux fins de la prestation des Services. « **Finalité autorisée** » comprend les fins d’emploi, les fins de location ou conformément aux instructions écrites du Consommateur avec lequel le Client a l’intention de conclure un contrat.

Nous ne réutiliserons pas les Renseignements personnels à d’autres fins que celles pour lesquelles ils ont été recueillis, à moins qu’une ou plusieurs des conditions suivantes ne soient avérées :

* la nouvelle utilisation est compatible avec l’utilisation initiale, ce qui signifie que vous devriez raisonnablement vous y attendre;
* nous vous avons informé de la nouvelle utilisation et vous avons donné l’occasion de vous y opposer; ou
* la nouvelle utilisation est autrement autorisée ou exigée par la loi.

Nous recueillons, utilisons et divulguons les Renseignements personnels des Consommateurs lorsque ceux-ci sont conscients de la Finalité autorisée pour laquelle les renseignements seront traités et qu’ils ont donné leur consentement à un tel Traitement, sauf lorsque le Traitement des Renseignements personnels sans consentement est autorisé ou exigé par la loi. Sous réserve des exigences réglementaires, l’exploitation de nos Services dans certains territoires exige que nous ou nos Clients obtenions des consentements supplémentaires ou particuliers sous forme de formulaires de consentement supplémentaires, d’appels téléphoniques, par l’intermédiaire d’une plateforme en ligne ou d’autres méthodes. Lorsque le Consommateur ne nous donne pas directement ce consentement ou un consentement spécifique, mais le donne à nos Clients, nous demandons à nos Clients d’obtenir le consentement du Consommateur avant de nous fournir les Renseignements personnels du Consommateur soumis à vérification pour l’un de nos Services. Le Consommateur peut retirer ce consentement précédemment accordé à tout moment en communiquant avec nous. Le retrait de ce consentement n’influe nullement sur la légalité de tout traitement fondé sur le consentement avant le retrait.

### **Quels renseignements traitons-nous?**

* **Traitement** **des renseignements non personnels** **:** Nous traitons les Renseignements non personnels afin de suivre les tendances et d’analyser les habitudes d’utilisation de notre site Web et de notre plateforme. Les renseignements non personnels (« **renseignements non personnels** ») désignent des renseignements ou du contenu autres que des Renseignements personnels, y compris, par exemple, des renseignements agrégés ou anonymisés sur nos utilisateurs et d’autres renseignements qui n’identifient aucune personne.
* **Traitement des renseignements sur les visiteurs du site Web :** Nous pouvons enregistrer le nom et la version de votre système d’exploitation, l’identifiant de l’appareil, le type de navigateur, le système d’exploitation, l’adresse du protocole Internet (IP), la résolution de l’écran, les pages que vous avez consultées sur notre ou nos sites Web, le temps que vous avez passé sur une page, les heures d’accès, les renseignements généraux sur l’emplacement comme la ville, l’État ou la zone géographique, et les renseignements sur votre utilisation et vos actions sur notre site Web.
* **Traitement des Renseignements personnels des Clients :** Lorsque vous vous abonnez à nos Services, on pourrait vous demander de saisir votre nom complet, votre adresse courriel, votre nom d’entreprise, votre adresse professionnelle, votre numéro de téléphone, votre adresse de facturation, votre adresse de carte et d’autres renseignements fournis par le Client dans des champs personnalisés, le cas échéant. Les renseignements financiers, tels que les données liées à votre mode de paiement (p. ex. numéro de carte de crédit valide, marque de carte, date d’expiration) ne sont jamais recueillis par nous, que ce soit sur notre site Web ou autrement. Lors du traitement des paiements, vous êtes transféré vers une page sécurisée du site Web de Stripe ou d’un autre fournisseur de services de paiement certifié PCI DSS. Cette page peut être vêtue de notre « livrée », mais elle n’est pas gérée par nous. Tous les renseignements financiers sont traités par notre service de traitement des paiements et nous vous encourageons à consulter sa politique de confidentialité et à communiquer directement avec lui pour obtenir des réponses à vos questions.
* **Traitement des Renseignements personnels des Consommateurs :** Certn ne recueillera les Renseignements personnels des Consommateurs que si vous choisissez volontairement de les fournir en raison d’une vérification des antécédents autorisée par vous et/ou par les lois applicables. Le type de Renseignements personnels que Certn peut recueillir à votre sujet par l’intermédiaire de notre site Web ou autrement varie en fonction des réglementations locales et de la demande de Service de vérification des données. Par souci de clarté, vous trouverez ci-dessous une liste non exclusive des Renseignements personnels que nous pouvons recueillir, la raison de la collecte et le déroulement de la collecte dans le cadre de la prestation de nos Services.

Certains renseignements, y compris les casiers judiciaires, les renseignements sur le crédit et les données biométriques, peuvent être considérés comme sensibles ou peuvent faire l’objet de protections spéciales dans certains territoires. Ces renseignements ne seront pas recueillis dans tous les cas et ne seront pas recueillis là où la loi l’interdit, et là où la loi le permet, ils ne seront recueillis et utilisés que conformément à la loi applicable.

| **Renseignements personnels que nous pouvons recueillir** | **Raison de la collecte** | **Déroulement de la collecte** |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Votre/vos nom(s) | Requis à des fins d’identification. Les anciens noms peuvent être nécessaires pour effectuer une vérification complète des antécédents, car il est possible que les anciens dossiers soient conservés sous un ancien nom. | Fournis par vous, en tant que Consommateur ou Client, par des documents publics, des agences d’évaluation du crédit ou des tiers que vous nous avez autorisés à contacter. |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Date de naissance | Requise à des fins d’identification. | Fournie par vous |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Lieu de naissance | Requis pour certains de nos services. | Fournie par vous |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Documentation d’identification et données biométriques | Si on nous demande de vérifier votre identité par la voie de notre Service OneID, nous utilisons un système biométrique basé sur la technologie de reconnaissance faciale (données biométriques) pour vérifier et confirmer votre identité en direct en ligne en faisant correspondre une image en temps réel de votre visage à la photo figurant sur votre document d’identification. | Fournies par vous |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Coordonnées | Certains de nos services exigent que nous recueillions l’historique des adresses résidentielles. De plus, pour nous assurer que nous sommes en mesure de communiquer avec vous dans le but de vous fournir des services, nous aurons peut-être besoin de votre adresse postale, de votre adresse courriel ou de votre numéro de téléphone. Nous n’utiliserons les coordonnées que dans le but de fournir des services et de nous conformer aux instructions de notre Client et à nos obligations légales. Nous ne communiquerons avec vous pour aucune autre raison. | Fournies par vous, les agences d’évaluation du crédit ou les registres publics |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Numéros d’identité délivrés par le gouvernement | Certains services exigent ces renseignements, car les dossiers que nous devons récupérer auprès de tiers sont souvent associés à un numéro d’identité produit par une entité gouvernementale. Cela peut comprendre les casiers judiciaires, les dossiers de crédit, les antécédents professionnels ou les dossiers de conduite. | Fournis par vous |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Antécédents criminels et casiers judiciaires | Nécessaires pour la vérification du casier judiciaire. | Fournis par vous, les organismes d’application de la loi ou d’autres organismes gouvernementaux, les tribunaux ou les registres publics |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Antécédents de crédit ou de faillite | Certains services exigent que nous obtenions des renseignements financiers ou d’identité qui se trouvent dans un dossier de crédit auprès d’une agence d’évaluation du crédit ou dans des dossiers publics. | Agences d’évaluation du crédit, agences gouvernementales ou registres publics |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Antécédents professionnels | Pour vérifier les antécédents professionnels et l’historique des activités connexes sur une certaine période | Fournis par vous, notre Client, les employeurs actuels ou passés ou leurs fournisseurs de services de tenue de dossiers, les agences qui vous ont placé chez vos employeurs actuels ou passés, ou les références que vous avez fournies |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Antécédents en matière d’éducation | Pour vérifier les antécédents en matière d’éducation ou l’historique des activités connexes sur une certaine période | Fournis par vous, notre Client, les établissements d’enseignement que vous avez fréquentés ou les fournisseurs de services de tenue de dossiers des établissements d’enseignement que vous avez fréquentés, les autorités scolaires gouvernementales dans les territoires où vous avez fait vos études, ou les références que vous avez fournies |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Titres professionnels, désignations, adhésions, sanctions ou réprimandes | Pour vérifier si vous êtes un certain type de professionnel, si vous participez à des cours de perfectionnement professionnel ou que vous les avez achevés, ou si vous avez fait l’objet de sanctions ou de réprimandes professionnelles | Fournis par vous, notre Client, les organismes professionnels auxquels vous avez été associé, ou leurs fournisseurs de services de tenue de dossiers, les registres publics ou les références que vous avez fournies |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Opinions à votre sujet | Pour mener des entrevues de référence. De plus, des opinions peuvent être exprimées lors des vérifications relatives à l’emploi ou au bénévolat. | Fournies par vous, notre Client, vos employeurs actuels ou passés ou leurs fournisseurs de services de tenue de dossiers, les agences qui vous ont placé chez vos employeurs actuels ou passés, ou les références que vous avez fournies |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Apparition sur des listes de surveillance ou de sanctions gouvernementales | Certains Clients souhaitent vérifier la présence sur les listes de surveillance ou de sanctions du gouvernement. | Fournie par les organismes d’application de la loi ou d’autres organismes gouvernementaux, des renseignements publics |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Admissibilité au travail | Pour vérifier la situation juridique des employés éventuels dans le territoire où ils exercent leurs activités. | Fournie par vous, notre Client ou des organismes gouvernementaux |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Dossiers de conduite | Pour vérifier la validité du permis de conduire et les antécédents de conduite | Fournis par vous, notre Client ou des organismes gouvernementaux |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Antécédents de mandats d’administrateur et de gouvernance d’entreprise | Pour vérifier l’association actuelle ou passée avec les sociétés en tant qu’administrateur ou dirigeant | Fournis par vous, notre Client, les registres publics, les sociétés auxquelles vous avez déjà été associé |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Renseignements sur les dossiers publics et résultats médiatiques négatifs | Certains services exigent que nous obtenions des renseignements publics, y compris des résultats médiatiques négatifs | Fournis par vous, notre Client, les organismes gouvernementaux ou les registres publics |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Enregistrements d’appels téléphoniques | Nous surveillons certains appels téléphoniques à des fins d’assurance de la qualité et de formation | Fournis par vous |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Résultats des tests de dépistage de drogues (pour les Consommateurs américains seulement) | Lorsqu’il s’agit de tests de dépistage de substances contrôlées, nous en communiquerons les résultats émis par des laboratoires de dépistage de drogues | Fournis par des laboratoires après votre test de dépistage de drogues |
| --- | --- | --- |

### **Comment traitons-nous les Renseignements personnels?**

La plupart des Renseignements personnels que nous recueillons proviennent de vous, directement ou par l’entremise de l’un de nos Clients. Nos processus de collecte et de transcription des Renseignements personnels sont automatisés dans la mesure du possible et sont soumis à des contrôles de qualité rigoureux. Les renseignements qui s’avèrent inexacts, soit à l’issue de nos propres vérifications, soit à la suite de votre demande de correction, sont mis à jour.

Lorsque nous fournissons des Services directement aux Consommateurs :

* Vous déterminez les Renseignements personnels que nous recueillons et leur finalité;
* Une fois que nous aurons reçu votre consentement, nous recueillerons et traiterons les renseignements conformément aux lois applicables; et
* Vous contrôlez et possédez les Renseignements personnels, et vous pouvez en demander la correction ou la suppression à tout moment.

Lorsque nous fournissons des Services aux Clients :

* Le Client fournit des instructions sur les Renseignements personnels à recueillir et sur la façon de les recueillir;
* Le cas échéant, le Client s’assure que les Consommateurs sont avisés de la collecte et du Traitement de leurs Renseignements personnels, ou qu’ils donnent leur consentement à cette fin, conformément aux lois applicables;
* Le Client s’assure que les Renseignements personnels sont recueillis et traités légalement, équitablement et de manière transparente, conformément à la Finalité autorisée;
* Le Client confirme que les Renseignements personnels sont exacts et, au besoin, tenus à jour, corrigés ou effacés; et
* Le Client s’assure que des mesures de protection appropriées sont en place pour protéger les Renseignements personnels.

Nous sommes généralement responsables des aspects suivants de la collecte et du Traitement des Renseignements personnels :

* Nous réalisons les Services demandés par notre Client ou notre Consommateur, conformément à leurs instructions;
* Nous protégeons les Renseignements personnels dont nous avons la garde contre la perte, le vol, l’accès, la divulgation, la copie, l’utilisation ou la modification non autorisés, d’une manière adaptée à leur caractère sensible, et conformément aux instructions de notre Client et aux lois applicables;
* Nous nous conformons à toutes les obligations légales qui peuvent nous incomber en tant que Sous-traitants de données, dépositaire, fournisseur de services ou dans l’exercice de fonctions semblables en vertu des lois applicables.

La collecte de Renseignements personnels à des fins de sécurité se fait en fonction de notre intérêt légitime et de notre obligation légale de nous assurer que les Renseignements personnels dont nous avons la garde sont protégés.

**6\. COMMENT LES RENSEIGNEMENTS PERSONNELS SONT-ILS PARTAGÉS ET QUAND NOUS LIVRONS-NOUS AU TRAITEMENT TRANSFRONTALIER?**
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Les Renseignements personnels que nous recueillons sont stockés sur l’infrastructure fournie par AWS au Canada, ainsi qu’aux États-Unis, au Royaume-Uni et en Australie (« **Emplacements** **de stockage** »). Il peut être nécessaire pour nous de recueillir, de Traiter et de divulguer des Renseignements personnels au-delà des frontières, y compris en dehors de nos emplacements de stockage, afin de vérifier les antécédents professionnels ou scolaires, en plus de fournir d’autres Services semblables. À ce titre, nous pouvons transférer vos Renseignements personnels pour les raisons suivantes :

1. Décision d’adéquation
2. Mesures de protection appropriées
3. Votre consentement
4. Autres dispositions juridictionnelles

Dans les cas où le Client est situé dans l’État de Californie, la province de Québec, le Royaume-Uni, l’Australie, l’UE et/ou l’EEE, ou si le Consommateur réside dans l’État de Californie, le Royaume-Uni, l’UE et/ou l’EEE, des exigences particulières peuvent s’appliquer au transfert de Renseignements personnels. Lorsque vous naviguez sur notre site Web, vous consentez à cette Politique. De plus, lorsque vous soumettez vos renseignements, vous consentez à un tel transfert transfrontalier.

Nous prenons toutes les mesures raisonnablement nécessaires pour nous assurer que vos Renseignements personnels sont traités de manière sécurisée et conformément à la présente Politique, et nous ne transférerons pas les Renseignements personnels à un organisme ou à un pays, à moins qu’il n’y ait des contrôles adéquats en place pour assurer la sécurité de vos données.

Si vous avez des questions sur le Traitement de vos renseignements à l’étranger ou si vous avez des restrictions ou des conditions concernant la divulgation de vos renseignements au-delà des frontières, veuillez communiquer avec nous dès que possible afin que nous puissions discuter de vos exigences particulières.

**7.QUI D’AUTRE PEUT ACCÉDER AUX RENSEIGNEMENTS RECUEILLIS?**
-------------------------------------------------------------

En plus des parties précisées dans la figure ci-dessus, les tiers suivants peuvent avoir un accès légitime à vos Renseignements personnels :

* les vérificateurs chargés de l’exécution des vérifications de conformité prévus par contrat ou par la loi;
* les sociétés affiliées et partenaires de Certn qui participent à la prestation de nos Services; et
* des tiers qui fournissent des services pour nous ou pour notre compte, y compris, mais sans s’y limiter, le traitement des paiements, l’analyse des données, la livraison des courriels, et les services SaaS, IaaS ou PaaS.

Lorsque nous fournissons des Services à un Client, les Renseignements personnels du Consommateur sont traités et signalés par l’entremise de notre plateforme sécurisée. Outre nos Clients et le personnel autorisé de Certn qui peuvent accéder à vos Renseignements personnels aux fins décrites dans la présente Politique, nous pouvons fournir vos Renseignements personnels aux autorités ou aux sociétés partenaires qui fournissent des services pour nous aider dans nos activités commerciales, comme la prestation d’un service à la Clientèle ou le traitement de votre paiement. Pour en savoir plus sur les sociétés tierces qui nous fournissent de tels services, veuillez cliquer [ici](https://info.certn.co/dpa-subprocessors/).

Dans des circonstances exceptionnelles, nous pouvons être tenus de communiquer des Renseignements personnels à des organismes d’application de la loi, à des organismes de sécurité nationale, à des tribunaux ou à d’autres institutions semblables, comme l’exige la loi. Si nous recevons une commande de production, une assignation à témoigner, un mandat ou toute autre demande exécutoire, nous agirons conformément aux lois applicables. Nous ne vendons ni ne divulguons vos Renseignements personnels à des gouvernements, à des services de marketing ou de publicité, à d’autres Clients ou à quiconque, sauf dans les cas prévus dans la présente Politique ou comme l’exige la loi.

**8\. COMMENT STOCKONS-NOUS ET PROTÉGEONS-NOUS LES RENSEIGNEMENTS PERSONNELS?**
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Nous sommes certifiés SOC2, SOC3 et ISO27001 et nous maintenons des mesures de protection techniques, administratives, organisationnelles, physiques, électroniques et procédurales avancées qui respectent ces normes et protègent vos Renseignements personnels contre l’accès, la perte, l’utilisation abusive, l’interférence ou la modification non autorisés au moment de leur collecte, de leur utilisation, de leur divulgation et de leur stockage. Nous effectuons régulièrement des vérifications de sécurité, des analyses de vulnérabilité et des tests de pénétration pour assurer la conformité aux pratiques et aux normes de sécurité de l’industrie.

Tout notre personnel et tous nos fournisseurs et Sous-traitants font l’objet d’un contrôle de sécurité avant d’accepter un emploi. Tous les membres du personnel ont reçu une formation en protection des données et sont conscients de leurs responsabilités. Une telle formation est dispensée à plusieurs reprises, de façon régulière ou aléatoire, mais au moins une fois par an.

Nous limitons l’accès aux Renseignements personnels aux personnes ayant un besoin commercial légitime, conformément à la raison et à l’objectif pour lesquels les renseignements ont été fournis. Nous mettons en œuvre diverses mesures de sécurité pour assurer la sécurité de vos Renseignements personnels lorsque des commandes sont passées ou lorsque vous saisissez ou soumettez vos Renseignements personnels ou que vous y accédez. Nous chiffrons les renseignements traités en transit et au repos. Tous les renseignements sensibles fournis sont transmis au moyen du protocole de sécurité de la couche transport (« Transport Layer Security » o « TLS »), puis stockés dans notre base de données et accessibles uniquement par les personnes autorisées ayant des droits d’accès spéciaux à nos systèmes et qui sont tenues de préserver la confidentialité des renseignements.

De plus, nous avons mis en place des processus pour encourager nos Clients à se conformer aux lois sur le droit à la vie privée et aux normes de sécurité applicables. Ces processus comprennent, sans s’y limiter, la conclusion d’ententes contraignantes avec nos Clients et la réalisation de vérifications mutuelles aléatoires des procédures et pratiques internes de chacun afin de veiller à ce que les normes réglementaires et les niveaux de sécurité soient en tout temps respectés et dépassés mutuellement.

**9\. PENDANT COMBIEN DE TEMPS VOS RENSEIGNEMENTS PERSONNELS SONT-ILS CONSERVÉS?**
----------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Nous conserverons vos renseignements pendant aussi longtemps que nécessaire pour vous fournir nos Services et/ou pour nous conformer à nos obligations contractuelles et légales, résoudre les différends et faire respecter nos accords.

Les données requises pour prouver la validité d’un droit ou d’un contrat seront conservées pendant la durée prévue par la loi applicable. À votre demande de résiliation de votre compte, nous désactiverons ou supprimerons votre compte et les renseignements de nos bases de données actives. Cependant, certains renseignements peuvent être conservés dans nos dossiers pour prévenir la fraude, dépanner les problèmes, contribuer à toute enquête, faire respecter nos conditions ou se conformer aux exigences légales.

En ce qui concerne les Renseignements personnels des Consommateurs, à moins que les dossiers n’aient été soumis à une demande de suppression, le calendrier de conservation et d’élimination ne doit pas dépasser trois (3) ans. Des exceptions peuvent exister pour des ensembles de données spécifiques régis par les exigences de conservation réglementaires ou de la part de tiers fournisseurs de données. Par exemple, nous ne stockerons aucune de vos données biométriques après la vérification de votre identité par OneID. Au besoin, nous pouvons conserver des renseignements généraux dans un journal et à des fins de vérification.

**10\. COMMENT EXERCER VOS DROITS À LA VIE PRIVÉE?**
----------------------------------------------------

Quel que soit votre lieu de résidence, nous examinerons gratuitement toute demande relative à la protection de la vie privée et prendrons des mesures pour vous aider à exercer vos droits en matière de protection de la vie privée, quant à : i) être informé, ii) accéder, iii) rectifier, iv) effacer, v) limiter le Traitement, vi) assurer la portabilité des données, vii) s’opposer au traitement, viii) ne pas faire l’objet d’une décision fondée sur une prise de décision automatisée, et ix) déposer une plainte.

Vous pouvez utiliser les informations de la section « Nous joindre » pour soulever toute demande ou question concernant l’exercice de vos droits à la vie privée.

À la réception d’une demande écrite, et après avoir vérifié que vous êtes le propriétaire des données, nous répondons aux demandes, aux différends et aux plaintes relatifs au droit à la vie privée dès que possible, et dans tous les cas, dans les délais prescrits par la loi. Toutefois, si nous refusons de le faire, nous vous donnerons un avis écrit en indiquant les raisons, et ce, dans les 30 jours suivant la réception de votre demande.

À des fins de conformité et lorsque la loi ou le contrat l’exige, avant de donner suite à une demande de droit à la vie privée, nous informerons le Client lié à cette demande, le cas échéant, ainsi que tout autre tiers qui pourrait avoir traité vos Renseignements personnels.

**11\. Y A-T-IL D’AUTRES QUESTIONS DE COMPÉTENCE?**
---------------------------------------------------

### **É.-U. Californie**

Aux fins de la Loi sur la protection des Renseignements personnels des consommateurs de la Californie (« California Consumer Privacy Act » ou « **CCPA** »), nous ne « vendons » pas de Renseignements personnels sur les Consommateurs à des tiers à des fins de marketing direct. Les Renseignements personnels traités aux fins de la vérification des antécédents sont exemptés de la CCPA.

Dans la mesure où vous êtes un résident californien et dans l’éventualité où nous aurions traité des catégories de vos Renseignements personnels au-delà de l’exemption de la CCPA dans le cadre d’une vérification des antécédents, vous avez le droit d’accéder à vos Renseignements personnels, de les supprimer, de les faire divulguer, de refuser de les vendre et d’être exempté de toute discrimination. Vous pouvez communiquer avec nous pour exercer l’un de ces droits. À des fins de conformité, nous pouvons exiger des renseignements supplémentaires de votre part afin d’honorer votre demande.

### **É.-U. Nevada**

**Nous ne vendons** pas de Renseignements personnels sur les Consommateurs à des tiers à des fins de marketing direct.

### **Résidents de l’UE, de l’EEE, de la Suisse et du Royaume-Uni**

Sous réserve du fait que nous traitons occasionnellement des Renseignements personnels de résidents de l’UE, de l’EEE, de la Suisse et du Royaume-Uni, nous avons pris des mesures pour nous conformer à ces normes juridictionnelles et nous assurer que tous les destinataires de ces Renseignements personnels offrent un niveau adéquat de protection des données, en nous engageant, entre autres, à respecter les clauses contractuelles types et/ou les accords internationaux de transfert de données, le cas échéant.

Les Consommateurs de l’UE, de l’EEE, de la Suisse et du Royaume-Uni disposent de certains droits concernant le Traitement des Renseignements personnels. Si vous êtes un résident de l’UE/EEE/R.-U., vous avez :

* le droit de demander des détails sur les Renseignements personnels que nous détenons à votre sujet;
* le droit de nous demander de mettre à jour vos renseignements s’ils sont inexacts ou incomplets;
* le droit de nous demander de supprimer vos renseignements dans certaines circonstances;
* le droit de retirer votre consentement à l’utilisation de vos renseignements lorsque nous nous appuyons sur ce consentement;
* dans certaines circonstances, vous avez le droit d’obtenir certaines de vos informations dans un format utilisable et/ou de demander que nous transmettions ces données à un tiers lorsque cela est techniquement possible;
* le droit de demander que nous limitions le Traitement de vos Renseignements personnels dans certaines circonstances; et
* le droit de déposer une plainte auprès de votre autorité locale de protection des données si vous croyez que nous n’avons pas été en mesure de vous aider.

Si vous souhaitez exercer vos droits ayant trait au rapport concernant votre crédit à la consommation, nous appuierons votre demande en notre qualité de Sous-traitant de données et en accord avec notre Client qui a commandé le rapport en sa qualité de responsable du traitement.

Pour enregistrer votre demande, veuillez communiquer avec nous. Nous communiquerons avec vous si nous avons besoin de renseignements supplémentaires de votre part afin de fournir les renseignements applicables ou d’entreprendre des démarches particulières pour honorer votre demande dans l’exercice de vos droits.

### **Brésil**

Les résidents du Brésil peuvent disposer de certains droits afin :

* de confirmer si nous traitons vos Renseignements personnels;
* de demander l’accès à vos Renseignements personnels que nous traitons;
* de corriger les Renseignements personnels incomplets, inexacts ou périmés;
* demander l’anonymisation, le blocage ou la suppression d’informations inutiles ou excessives ou d’informations traitées en non-conformité avec les dispositions de la LGPD (Lei Geral de Proteção de Dados Pessoais);
* demander la portabilité des données;
* être informé des tiers avec lesquels vos Renseignements personnels ont été partagés; et
* demander un examen des décisions automatisées qui ont une incidence sur vos intérêts.

Pour exercer vos droits ayant trait au rapport concernant votre crédit à la consommation, nous appuierons votre demande en notre qualité de Sous-traitant et en accord avec notre Client qui a commandé le rapport en sa qualité de responsable du traitement.

Pour enregistrer votre demande, veuillez communiquer avec nous en utilisant les coordonnées fournies ci-dessous. Nous communiquerons avec vous si nous avons besoin de renseignements supplémentaires de votre part afin de fournir les renseignements applicables ou d’entreprendre des démarches particulières pour honorer votre demande dans l’exercice de vos droits.

### **Australie**

Veuillez voir ci[\-dessous](#_heading=h.1ci93xb).

**12\. COMMENT UTILISONS-NOUS LES TÉMOINS?**
--------------------------------------------

Notre site Web utilise des témoins et d’autres technologies semblables pour fournir des fonctionnalités, analyser le trafic et personnaliser une partie de votre contenu Web.

**Que sont les témoins?**

Les témoins sont de petits fichiers de données texte qui sont envoyés à votre ordinateur ou appareil mobile par un site Web pendant la navigation. On vous présentera des renseignements sur nos témoins et une option vous permettant d’accepter tous les témoins ou personnaliser vos préférences en matière de témoins lors de votre première visite de notre site Web et occasionnellement à partir de la bannière de témoins par la suite. Vous pouvez consentir à tous les témoins ou les refuser à tout moment lorsque vous naviguez sur le site Web. Vous pouvez choisir et gérer tous vos témoins à tout moment par le biais des paramètres de votre navigateur. Si vous désactivez les témoins, vous pourriez ne pas être en mesure d’accéder ou d’utiliser pleinement certaines parties ou fonctionnalités du site Web.

Il existe différents types de témoins avec différentes fonctions :

* **Témoins de session :** ils ne sont stockés sur votre ordinateur que pendant votre session Web. Ils sont automatiquement supprimés lorsque le navigateur est fermé. Ils stockent habituellement un identifiant de session anonyme vous permettant de naviguer sur un site Web sans avoir à vous connecter à chaque page. Ils ne recueillent aucun renseignement sur votre ordinateur.
* **Témoins persistants :** un témoin persistant est un témoin stocké sous forme de fichier sur votre ordinateur et il y demeure lorsque vous fermez votre navigateur Web. Le témoin peut être lu par le site Web qui l’a créé lorsque vous revenez visiter ce site Web.
* **Témoins de première partie :** la fonction de ce type de témoin est de conserver vos préférences pour un site Web particulier pour l’entité propriétaire de ce site Web. Ils sont stockés et échangés entre les serveurs de Certn et le disque dur de votre ordinateur. Ils ne servent à rien d’autre que la personnalisation telle que définie par vous. Ces témoins peuvent être des témoins temporaires ou persistants.
* **Témoins tiers :** la fonction de ce type de témoin est de conserver votre interaction avec un site Web particulier pour une entité qui n’est pas propriétaire de ce site Web. Ils sont stockés et échangés entre le serveur d’un tiers et le disque dur de votre ordinateur. Ces témoins sont généralement des témoins persistants.

Les témoins de première partie sont nécessaires au bon fonctionnement de notre site Web. Notre site Web permet également l’utilisation de témoins tiers, qui peuvent être lus à l’externe par d’autres organismes. À ce titre, nous ne pouvons être tenus responsables des témoins tiers, c.-à-d. des témoins qui ne sont pas initiés par nous. Nos plateformes de service, que nous utilisons pour recueillir des renseignements auprès des Consommateurs et des Clients, n’utilisent pas de témoins tiers.

**Utilisation de témoins**

**Témoins nécessaires :** En utilisant notre site Web, vous acceptez que nous puissions stocker les témoins nécessaires sur votre appareil, en plus d’y accéder. Ces témoins ne recueillent pas de renseignements à votre sujet qui pourraient être utilisés à des fins de marketing ou de mémorisation des sites que vous avez visités sur Internet.

**Témoins** **statistiques :** Ils sont anonymes et ne peuvent pas être utilisés pour vous identifier. Les témoins statistiques nous aident à améliorer les fonctions de notre site Web et à recueillir des renseignements sur la façon dont vous utilisez le site Web (comme la fréquence à laquelle vous visitez notre site Web, les liens sur lesquels vous avez cliqué, les pages que vous préférez). Le consentement à ces témoins nous permettra de produire des rapports statistiques anonymes à des fins d’amélioration du site Web.

**Témoins de** **préférence :** Afin de mémoriser les choix que vous avez faits précédemment (comme la langue sélectionnée ou le nom d’utilisateur et le mot de passe enregistrés), de permettre une navigation plus rapide et de fournir des fonctions améliorées, nous devons activer les témoins de préférence. Les renseignements recueillis par ces témoins sont habituellement anonymisés.

**Témoins de** **marketing :** Ils peuvent être définis sur des sites Web par des tiers. Ils ne stockent pas de Renseignements personnels, mais identifient votre navigateur et votre appareil Internet pour aider les annonceurs à vous montrer des publicités pertinentes.

**Données du journal du site Web :** Les serveurs Web de Certn enregistrent les renseignements suivants lors des visites de notre site Web : Adresses IP, type de système d’exploitation, heure et durée de la visite, pages Web visitées et type de navigateur. Nous ne lions pas les informations du journal du serveur à d’autres informations d’une manière qui permettraient l’identification des visiteurs de notre site Web. En plus d’analyser ces journaux pour vous offrir une meilleure expérience sur notre site Web, les journaux du serveur peuvent être examinés à des fins de sécurité et, au besoin, pour détecter les activités non autorisées sur notre site Web. Dans de tels cas, les données de journal du serveur, contenant des adresses IP, seraient communiquées aux organismes d’application de la loi afin qu’ils puissent identifier les utilisateurs dans le cadre de leur enquête sur les activités non autorisées.

**13\. QUI EST L’AGENT DE PROTECTION DE LA VIE PRIVÉE?**
--------------------------------------------------------

Nous disposons d’un agent de protection de la vie privée qui peut être contacté en cas de problème de confidentialité ou de protection des données à l’adresse privacy@certn.co.

**14\. NOUS JOINDRE**
---------------------

Si vous avez des questions concernant la présente Politique, les pratiques de ce site Web ou vos interactions avec ce site Web, vous pouvez communiquer avec nous à l’adresse privacy@certn.co ou utiliser les options disponibles énoncées ci-dessous :

| **CANADA**Certn (Canada) inc. | Adresse : Téléphone : Courriel : | 1006 Fort StBureau 300Victoria, C.-B. V8V 3K4+1 844 987-0690privacy@certn.co pour toute question relative à la confidentialitésupport@certn.co pour toute question relative au soutiencompliance@certn.co pour toute question relative à la conformitélegal@certn.co pour toute question juridique |
| --- | --- | --- |
| **ÉTATS-UNIS** Certn (États-Unis) Inc. | Adresse : Téléphone : Courriel : | Trust Center1209 Orange StreetWilmington, New Castle County, Delaware, 19801+1 844 987-0690privacy@certn.co pour toute question relative à la confidentialitésupport@certn.co pour toute question relative au soutiencompliance@certn.co pour toute question relative à la conformitélegal@certn.co pour toute question juridique |
| --- | --- | --- |
| **ROYAUME UNI**Credence Background Screening Limited | Adresse : Téléphone : Courriel : | 160 London RoadSevenoaks, Kent, TN13 1BT +44 (0)1732 748 900contact@credence.co.uk et support@credence.co.uk pour les questions d’ordre généraldpo@credence.co.uk pour toute question relative à la confidentialité |
| --- | --- | --- |
| **AUSTRALIE**InterCheck Global Pty. Ltd. | Adresse : Téléphone : Courriel : | 356 Collins StreetMelbourne, 3000, Victoria+61 (03) 8820 4069 help@intercheck.com.au |
| --- | --- | --- |

**15\. AUSTRALIE - INTERCHECK GLOBAL PTY LTD.**
-----------------------------------------------

Certn s’est récemment associée à InterCheck Global Pty Ltd. (« **InterCheck Australia** ») dans le but de fournir des services particuliers en Australie. Si vous êtes situé en Australie, soit en tant que Consommateur ou Client, les conditions ci-dessus sont assujetties au présent article et restreintes par celui-ci. Toute référence à « **nous** », « **notre** » « **nos** » ou « **Certn** » inclut notamment InterCheck Australia.

1. Notre engagement en matière de confidentialité

Nous comprenons que la confidentialité est importante pour vous et nous apprécions la confiance dont vous faites preuve envers nos services. C’est pourquoi InterCheck Australia s’engage pleinement à protéger vos Renseignements personnels et sensibles et vise à être claire et ouverte quant à la façon dont elle utilise vos renseignements pour vous fournir ses services.

La sécurité de l’information et la confidentialité sont au cœur de tout ce que nous faisons, afin que vous puissiez continuer à avoir confiance dans vos relations avec notre organisation maintenant et à l’avenir.

À ce titre, InterCheck Australia s’engage pleinement à préserver la confidentialité de vos Renseignements personnels. Nous assurons la conformité aux lois fédérales et étatiques australiennes sur la protection des Renseignements personnels et aux principes australiens sur la protection des Renseignements personnels, tels qu’ils sont énoncés dans la Loi sur la protection des Renseignements personnels de 1988.

Cette politique décrit la façon dont nous recueillons, manipulons, stockons, partageons, détruisons et utilisons vos Renseignements personnels, de manière à ce que vous puissiez comprendre comment nous gérons et protégeons vos renseignements.

2. Présentation

InterCheck Australia fournit des services de vérification au nom et dans l’intérêt de nos Clients qui nous engagent pour fournir des vérifications préalables à l’emploi et des vérifications de probité des employés, bénévoles, entrepreneurs et consultants éventuels ou existants, et ce, afin d’évaluer leur aptitude à l’emploi ou à un poste de confiance. Ce service s’étend aux personnes qui ont besoin de services de vérification en leur nom et dans leur intérêt en vue d’occuper un emploi ou un poste de confiance, ou encore à des fins de vérification.

3. Pourquoi recueillons-nous des Renseignements personnels?

InterCheck Australia est une société australienne qui fournit des services de vérification des antécédents et de vérification aux particuliers et aux entreprises. Afin de fournir nos services, InterCheck Australia doit recueillir des Renseignements personnels et sensibles auprès de personnes dans le but de réaliser nos services. Nous pouvons également utiliser certaines de ces informations pour mieux comprendre vos besoins, en tant que Client, ce qui nous permettra de mieux concevoir et d’améliorer nos produits et services et de vous informer potentiellement des autres produits et services susceptibles de vous intéresser.

4. Quels renseignements recueillons-nous?

Dans le cadre de nos activités, nous devons recueillir des Renseignements personnels. Nous recueillons différents Renseignements personnels et sensibles en fonction du produit ou du service que vous avez demandé ou de la façon dont vous avez utilisé nos services. Les renseignements que nous recueillons auprès de vous peuvent comprendre :

1. **Pour la vérification des antécédents criminels :** Obtenus auprès de la Police fédérale australienne (« Australian Federal Police » ou « AFP ») et/ou de la Commission australienne du renseignement criminel (« Australian Criminal Intelligence Commission » ou « ACIC ») -Nom incluant le nom, le ou les prénom(s), tous les noms connus antérieurement, y compris les alias. Coordonnées, y compris les numéros de téléphone et les adresses de courriel. Date de naissance et lieu de naissance. Renseignements sensibles, y compris le type de genre et les renseignements biométriques, comme les photographies recueillies à partir de votre téléphone ou d’une caméra Web. Renseignements démographiques, comme la profession, le lieu de résidence au cours des cinq dernières années. Les documents d’identité, y compris les permis de conduire (permis de conduire, permis d’armes à feu) ou les détails du passeport. Des renseignements ou des opinions concernant le processus de demande actuel ou précédent du candidat, y compris des renseignements relatifs à l’objectif de la vérification entamée au sujet du candidat, y compris son lieu de travail.
2. **Pour les autres vérifications des antécédents ou contrôles :** Dans le but de fournir des services de vérification, nous pourrions devoir recueillir ce qui suit : Qualifications ou adhésions, renseignements sur le curriculum vitae, professions, références et détails des références, coordonnées, adresses, date et lieu de naissance, compétences, qualifications, historique résidentiel, détails de crédit ou bancaires, citoyenneté et statut d’immigration, associations professionnelles ou commerciales et adhésions ou accréditations, antécédents professionnels et responsabilités passées ou tout autre renseignement relatif à votre carrière.
3. **Renseignements sur les documents d’identité :** Aux fins de vérification de l’identité et pour confirmer que la personne qui fait la demande est la même personne qui donne son consentement, nous pourrions devoir recueillir des documents d’identité et des renseignements connexes, y compris des renseignements biométriques, comme une photographie en direct afin de faire correspondre le demandeur aux documents d’identité.
4. **Coordonnées et renseignements professionnels :** Afin de fournir nos services et notre soutien de manière professionnelle et efficace, nous pouvons recueillir des renseignements tels que l’adresse courriel, les numéros de téléphone, les adresses commerciales et postales résidentielles, la profession et le rôle, les détails de la carte de crédit et les renseignements professionnels, y compris les coordonnées d’ABN qui nous permettent de transiger avec la personne et/ou de lui fournir nos services et notre soutien.
    5. Renseignements sensibles

En raison de la nature des produits et services qu’InterCheck Australia fournit, certains de vos Renseignements personnels recueillis et conservés par nous seront des « renseignements sensibles ». Ces renseignements ne seront obtenus qu’avec votre consentement et nous ne les utiliserons qu’aux fins pour lesquelles vous les avez fournis, sauf lorsque la loi le permet autrement. Certains types de renseignements sensibles que nous recueillons comprennent la citoyenneté et le statut d’immigrant, les renseignements sur les antécédents criminels, les renseignements biométriques et démographiques et les renseignements sur le sexe.

6. Comment recueillons-nous vos Renseignements personnels?

Les Renseignements personnels ou sensibles que nous recueillons à votre sujet sont ceux que vous nous fournissez ou que vous nous autorisez à obtenir.

InterCheck Australia collecte ces renseignements directement auprès de vous, de votre employeur ou d’un tiers, uniquement lorsque vous avez donné votre consentement les autorisant à fournir ces renseignements. Tous les renseignements recueillis le sont de manière légale, équitable et non intrusive et ne sont collectés qu’avec votre consentement.

Nous recueillons des informations personnelles par les moyens suivants :

* Par le biais de notre formulaire de demande en ligne sécurisé sur notre site Web.
* Lorsque vous remplissez et envoyez un formulaire de demande papier signé, soit par la poste, soit par voie électronique.
* En personne, par téléphone ou par courriel, par exemple, lorsque vous communiquez avec notre centre d’assistance; les Clients sont informés des risques liés à l’envoi de toute information, y compris des Renseignements personnels comme des documents d’identité, par la poste ou par courriel dans ces cas.
* Lorsque vous vous connectez à un tiers ou que vous vous connectez à nos services par l’intermédiaire d’un tiers, par exemple un partenaire d’intégration, et que vous avez consenti et êtes conscient qu’InterCheck Australia collectera les renseignements dans le but de fournir nos services de vérification préalable à l’embauche.
* Dans le cadre de la prestation de services à votre intention. Nous pouvons également recueillir des renseignements vous concernant auprès de tiers fournisseurs et de services de bases de données gouvernementales, dans le but de vous identifier et de vous faire correspondre aux documents d’identité fournis.
    7. Utilisation et divulgation de vos Renseignements personnels

Nous faisons attention à la façon dont nous utilisons vos renseignements. La principale raison pour laquelle nous recueillons, utilisons et partageons vos Renseignements personnels est de permettre la prestation de nos produits et services. Nous pouvons également utiliser vos renseignements pour mieux comprendre vos besoins, ce qui nous permettra de mieux concevoir et améliorer nos produits et services et de vous informer potentiellement des autres produits et services susceptibles de vous intéresser.

Nous recueillons, conservons, utilisons et divulguons des Renseignements personnels à diverses fins commerciales, notamment :

* pour fournir les produits ou services que vous nous avez demandés, y compris :
* pour déposer une demande de vérification des antécédents criminels coordonnée à l’échelle nationale et obtenir les résultats des vérifications policières auprès du Service national de vérification policière (« National Police Checking Service »), le service administré et exploité par l’ACIC;
* pour nous conformer à nos obligations en vertu de l’entente que nous avons conclue avec l’ACIC concernant le Service national de vérification policière. Pour en savoir plus sur notre entente avec l’ACIC, veuillez consulter la partie ci-dessous :
* pour effectuer une vérification en ligne du droit au visa (« Visa Entitlement Verification Online » ou « VEVO ») ou pour vérifier l’identité par l’entremise du Département australien des affaires intérieures (« Australian Department of Home Affairs »);
* à des fins de preuve d’identité;
* pour communiquer avec vous et pour traiter vos demandes, plaintes ou préoccupations et pour y donner suite;
* pour traiter les paiements;
* pour communiquer avec vous;
* à toute autre fin que nous expliquons quand les Renseignements personnels ont été recueillis, y compris l’utilisation et les divulgations décrites dans la présente Politique, et
* pour aider à améliorer notre entreprise, nos produits et nos services et pour aider à gérer notre entreprise;
* pour communiquer avec vous au sujet de votre relation avec nous, y compris la possibilité de vous fournir nos produits et services;
* pour se conformer aux lois et aux obligations et pour fournir de l’aide aux autorités gouvernementales ou aux organismes d’application de la loi;
* être en mesure de présenter une demande et d’obtenir les résultats d’une vérification d’identité auprès de l’émetteur du document par l’entremise du Service de vérification des documents (« Document Verification Service » ou « DVS »), qui relève du Département des affaires intérieures.
    8. Accréditation auprès de l’ACIC

InterCheck Australia est un organisme dûment accrédité, conformément à son entente en vertu de l’Entente d’accès contrôlé par des organismes dûment accrédités aux vérifications des antécédents criminels coordonnées à l’échelle nationale (« Agreement for controlled access by duly Accredited Bodies to Nationally Coordinated Criminal History Checks »), ou « Entente », afin d’entreprendre l’exécution des vérifications des antécédents criminels coordonnées à l’échelle nationale (« Nationally Coordinated Criminal History Checks » ou « NCCHC ») pour les candidats admissibles.

Cette entente énonce les obligations et les exigences nécessaires pour qu’InterCheck Australia conserve son statut d’accréditation et son droit d’accès au Service national de vérification policière. Si vous souhaitez communiquer avec l’ACIC, veuillez envoyer toutes vos demandes par courriel à npcs@acic.gov.au

9. Vous fournir de nouveaux produits ou services

De temps à autre, nous pouvons également utiliser vos renseignements pour vous informer des produits ou services (y compris des tiers) susceptibles de vous intéresser. Pour ce faire, nous pouvons communiquer avec vous par courriel, téléphone, SMS, médias sociaux, courrier ou d’autres formes de publicité.

10. À vous de choisir de vous abonner ou de vous désabonner

Si vous ne souhaitez pas que nous vous envoyions des communications de marketing par courriel, vous pouvez vous désabonner en tout temps en utilisant l’option qui vous est offerte à cette fin. Pour vous désabonner de toute autre forme de communication, veuillez communiquer avec notre délégué à la protection des données en utilisant les coordonnées fournies ci-dessous.

11. Pendant combien de temps conserverons-nous vos Renseignements personnels?

Nous conserverons vos renseignements pendant aussi longtemps que vous êtes un Client d’InterCheck Australia, ou conformément à nos obligations légales. Par exemple, les vérifications australiennes des antécédents criminels sont supprimées après 12 mois et les documents d’identité à l’appui de cette même demande doivent être conservés pendant 12 mois et supprimés dans les 15 mois.

12. À qui divulguons-nous vos Renseignements personnels?

Nous ne divulguerons vos renseignements qu’en conformité avec les services professionnels que nous fournissons, comme indiqué dans la présente Politique. Pendant le processus de prestation de nos services et selon les produits ou services fournis ou la raison de votre interaction avec InterCheck Australia, nous pouvons partager des renseignements vous concernant avec des tiers, tels que :

* les tiers fournisseurs, y compris, mais sans s’y limiter, les fournisseurs de vérifications criminelles, les organismes d’application de la loi, les organismes de réglementation et d’octroi de licences, les agences de crédit, les registres publics, les dossiers judiciaires, les fournisseurs de services d’enseignement ou les organismes professionnels;
* les employeurs actuels ou précédents, par exemple, pour confirmer votre emploi;
* les organismes partenaires;
* les organismes gouvernementaux et organismes d’application de la loi ou organismes de réglementation;
* les entreprises auxquelles est confiée une partie de nos activités, y compris le marketing direct et le soutien informatique;
* les vérificateurs.
    13. Partageons-nous le résultat des vérifications de vos antécédents avec des tiers?
* Lorsque vous avez donné votre consentement, dans le cadre d’une vérification des antécédents commandée par l’un des Clients commerciaux d’InterCheck Australia, InterCheck Australia communiquera à ce Client le résultat de la vérification de vos antécédents.
* Si InterCheck Australia vous offre la possibilité de partager les résultats des services que vous avez obtenus avec un ou plusieurs organismes, et que vous choisissez de partager ces résultats, InterCheck Australia partagera les résultats avec ces organismes (mais ne partagera aucune information sous-jacente fournie à InterCheck Australia pour obtenir les résultats).
* Nous pouvons divulguer des Renseignements personnels à un tiers qui a reçu les résultats de la vérification de vos antécédents, y compris le résultat d’une vérification policière, pour permettre à ce tiers de vérifier ce résultat, au moyen d’une fonction ou d’une fonctionnalité de vérification. Lorsque vous avez consenti à ce que nous transmettions les résultats de la vérification de vos antécédents, y compris le résultat d’une vérification policière, à un tiers, vous consentez également à ce que nous mettions ces renseignements à la disposition de ce tiers par l’entremise d’une fonction ou d’une fonctionnalité de vérification.
* Lorsque vous divulguez des Renseignements personnels à un tiers en lui remettant une copie du résultat de la vérification de vos antécédents ou du résultat d’une vérification de police effectuée à votre sujet (en format électronique ou papier), vous consentez également à ce que nous divulguions vos Renseignements personnels à ce tiers par le biais d’une fonction ou d’une fonctionnalité de vérification.
* Vous reconnaissez et acceptez qu’une telle divulgation par l’entremise d’une fonction ou d’une fonctionnalité de vérification soit appropriée et nécessaire pour assurer la sécurité et l’intégrité des Renseignements personnels contenus dans les résultats de la vérification de vos antécédents ou des vérifications policières effectuées à votre sujet.
    14. Comment stockons-nous et protégeons-nous vos Renseignements personnels?

InterCheck Australia s’engage à protéger et à sécuriser vos Renseignements personnels. Nous prenons des précautions raisonnables pour nous assurer que tous les Renseignements personnels que nous détenons à votre sujet sont protégés et mis à l’abri de toute utilisation abusive, perte, utilisation non autorisée, modification ou divulgation, par la mise en œuvre de mesures de sécurité techniques, physiques et administratives de l’information, comme le prescrit notre Politique sur la sécurité de l’information de l’entreprise.

La confidentialité et l’intégrité des Renseignements personnels sont protégées comme suit :

| Stockage sécurisé | Vos renseignements sont stockés à l’aide de services d’hébergement en nuage de classe entreprise sécurisés au moyen d’un chiffrement AES-256 dans le centre de données AWS situé à Sydney. |
| --- | --- |
| Formation du personnel | InterCheck Australia intègre la confidentialité et la sécurité dans notre culture. Nous formons notre personnel sur la façon de protéger vos renseignements en favorisant la sensibilisation et la conformité aux procédures dans nos activités commerciales. |
| --- | --- |
| Sécurité des systèmes | Restriction de l’accès à nos systèmes internes à l’aide de contrôles d’accès techniques selon le principe du besoin de savoir. Pare-feu limitant l’accès aux composants internes des systèmes à une liste blanche d’adresses IP autorisées. Exécution de scanneurs antivirus et anti-logiciels malveillants avec des signatures de menace à jour.Correctifs réguliers appliqués aux serveurs et aux postes de travail exécutant les systèmes d’exploitation actuels et les navigateurs modernes. |
| --- | --- |
| Sécurité physique et de l’immeuble | Nous contrôlons l’accès aux zones sensibles, la gestion des documents physiques et électroniques et l’élimination sécurisée des documents. Des mesures de sécurité physique sont en place pour empêcher tout accès non autorisé à nos locaux. |
| --- | --- |
| Sécurité transactionnelle | Nous appliquons des connexions à l’aide du protocole sécurisé de cryptage (« Secure Socket Layer » ou « SSL ») pour chaque page de notre site Web et de notre application. L’utilisation de SSL signifie que le trafic de données entre votre ordinateur et notre site est chiffré et protégé en tout temps. |
| --- | --- |
| Vérification et essais | InterCheck Australia emploie des experts en sécurité indépendants et certifiés par l’industrie qui possèdent l’expérience et les antécédents nécessaires pour soutenir nos objectifs de sécurité. |
| --- | --- |
| Détruire ou anonymiser les données lorsqu’elles ne sont plus requises | Nous conserverons les renseignements associés à votre compte pendant la période requise pour nous conformer aux lois applicables en matière de tenue de dossiers. Par exemple, dans le cas des vérifications policières, nous sommes tenus de conserver les renseignements utilisés pour soumettre votre demande pendant au moins 12 mois et de supprimer le résultat des vérifications dans les 12 mois.Sinon, nous conserverons les renseignements jusqu’à ce que vous supprimiez votre compte. Lorsque nous n’avons plus besoin de renseignements, nous prenons des mesures raisonnables pour les détruire ou les dépersonnaliser. |
| --- | --- |

15. Transfert de Renseignements personnels à l’étranger

Aux fins d’une Vérification australienne des antécédents criminels coordonnée à l’échelle nationale, InterCheck Australia **ne** transférera ni ne stockera aucune donnée liée à ce service à l’étranger sans votre consentement et celui de l’ACIC.

Pour d’autres types de vérification des antécédents qui font partie de notre gamme de produits et dans le cadre de la prestation de ces services, nous pourrions devoir transférer des Renseignements personnels à l’étranger afin de communiquer avec des fournisseurs d’information, des employeurs éventuels ou passés et/ou nos entités connexes à l’étranger. Nous ne transférerons des Renseignements personnels à l’étranger que :

* si le candidat a consenti au transfert;
* si le transfert est nécessaire pour nous permettre de fournir au Client le service demandé;
* s’il n’est pas pratique d’obtenir le consentement d’un candidat, si le transfert est au profit du candidat et si le consentement du candidat serait probablement donné, ou
* si nous avons pris des mesures raisonnables pour nous assurer que les Renseignements personnels d’un candidat ne seront pas conservés, utilisés ou divulgués par le destinataire d’une manière incompatible avec la présente Politique et la Loi sur la protection des Renseignements personnels.
    16. Renseignements sur les transactions

Nous ne stockons **pas** directement les informations relatives aux cartes. ANZ Bank Australia saisit tous les renseignements relatifs aux cartes en notre nom et conformément à ses propres politiques de sécurité des données.

17. Confidentialité concernant les mineurs et les enfants

En règle générale, nous demanderons le consentement d’un parent ou d’un tuteur pour recueillir les Renseignements personnels des enfants de moins de 16 ans. Cependant, si nous sommes légalement tenus de fournir le produit à une personne âgée de moins de 16 ans sans ce consentement, nous ne pouvons pas l’obtenir dans ces circonstances. Pour certains produits fournis par InterCheck Australia, nous sommes tenus d’obtenir le consentement d’un parent ou d’un tuteur pour les personnes âgées de moins de 18 ans, par exemple, les vérifications australiennes des antécédents criminels. Le consentement des parents ou des tuteurs devra être obtenu dans ces circonstances.

18. Comment pouvez-vous accéder à vos Renseignements personnels et les corriger s’ils sont erronés?

Vous avez le droit de demander l’accès à vos Renseignements personnels que nous détenons à votre sujet à tout moment. Vous pouvez faire une telle demande en communiquant avec l’agent de protection de la vie privée d’InterCheck Australia ou l’équipe de soutien d’InterCheck Australia en utilisant les coordonnées indiquées dans la présente Politique. Nous confirmerons toujours votre identité avant de donner accès à vos Renseignements personnels. InterCheck Australia fournira gratuitement ces Renseignements personnels au candidat, à moins qu’il existe un sujet exceptionnel en vertu des lois pertinentes sur la protection de la vie privée.

Si un candidat est en mesure d’établir que les renseignements détenus par InterCheck Australia à son sujet ne sont pas exacts, complets ou à jour, le candidat peut alors nous demander de corriger ces renseignements. Nous prendrons alors des mesures raisonnables pour corriger ces informations ou si nécessaire, nous discuterons avec le candidat de mesures alternatives.

Les candidats peuvent demander l’accès aux Renseignements personnels qu’InterCheck Australia détient à leur sujet en contactant notre équipe de soutien au (03) 8820 4069 ou par courriel à l’adresse help@intercheck.com.au, où seront gérés toutes les questions, litiges et plaintes.

19. Contester les résultats de la vérification de vos antécédents criminels (émis par l’ACIC)

Si vous croyez que le résultat de la vérification policière effectuée à votre sujet est erroné, vous avez le droit de contester le résultat. Pour contester votre résultat, vous pouvez contacter InterCheck Australia directement au numéro ou à l’adresse courriel ci-dessous, et nous vous informerons de toutes les informations et preuves que vous devez nous fournir pour qu’InterCheck Australia puisse déposer le formulaire de contestation de vérification d’antécédents criminels de l’ACIC (formulaire de contestation) auprès de l’ACIC, qui est coordonnée au niveau national.

La police enquêtera alors sur le litige, en examinant notamment toutes les informations et preuves à l’appui, et vous en communiquera le résultat (qu’il s’agisse d’une réussite ou d’un échec).

Pour plus d’informations sur la procédure de litige, consultez notre page d’aide sur les litiges. Si vous avez d’autres questions, veuillez communiquer avec nous à l’adresse [help@intercheck.com.au](mailto:help@intercheck.com.au) ou nous appeler au (03) 8820 4069 pour obtenir de l’aide.

20. Répondre aux préoccupations ou aux plaintes en matière de confidentialité

Chez InterCheck, nous apprécions nos Clients. Nous nous efforcerons toujours d’être équitables et réactifs. Si vous avez une plainte, vous êtes en droit d’attendre que nous la traitions de manière amicale et professionnelle. Les Clients ont le droit d’exprimer leurs préoccupations quant à la manière dont nous traitons leurs Renseignements personnels et nous nous efforçons de répondre à ces préoccupations de manière professionnelle et rapide. Les Clients ayant des questions sur nos pratiques en matière de protection de la vie privée, sur la présente Politique ou ayant une plainte concernant notre service peuvent contacter notre Responsable de la protection de la vie privée pour résoudre leurs plaintes.

Lorsque nous recevons une plainte, nous la considérons comme un retour d’information précieux qui peut nous aider à améliorer les services que nous offrons et à faire en sorte que vos besoins soient satisfaits de la meilleure manière possible.

Les Clients peuvent envoyer leurs questions ou leurs plaintes concernant la confidentialité à l’adresse suivante

**The Privacy Officer InterCheck Australia**

**PO Box 213, Flinders Lane Vic 8009**

Vous pouvez également communiquer avec notre Responsable de la protection de la vie privée au : Courriel : [help@intercheck.com.au](mailto:help@intercheck.com.au)

Téléphone : (03) 8820 4069

Nous ferons tout notre possible pour enquêter sur votre plainte et vous informer du résultat dès que possible. Si la question n’est pas résolue à votre satisfaction, vous pouvez alors adresser votre plainte au Bureau du Commissaire australien à l’information (« Office of the Australian Information Commissioner »), qui peut être contacté sur le site Web suivant : [https://www.oaic.gov.au/privacy/privacy-complaints/](https://www.oaic.gov.au/privacy/privacy-complaints/)

21. Modifications apportées à notre Politique de confidentialité

La présente Politique peut être modifiée, selon que nos activités commerciales changent ou que des Lois sur la protection des Renseignements personnels sont modifiées. Si tel est le cas, une mise à jour remplacera la présente Déclaration de confidentialité et pourra être consultée sur notre site Web.

22. Visiter notre site Web

Les sites Web d’InterCheck Australia, y compris [www.intercheck.com.au](http://www.intercheck.com.au/), comme la plupart des autres sites Web commerciaux, peuvent recueillir des informations lors de votre visite. Ces renseignements sont utilisés uniquement pour administrer et améliorer nos sites Web. Nous ne vous identifions pas personnellement. Nous pouvons recueillir les renseignements suivants lors de votre visite en utilisant des témoins. Les témoins sont de petits fichiers de données qui sont téléchargés à partir de nos serveurs Web et stockés sur votre disque dur. Un témoin n’identifie pas personnellement les personnes, mais il identifie les ordinateurs. La plupart des navigateurs peuvent être configurés de façon à refuser d’accepter les témoins. Vous pouvez également supprimer des témoins qui se trouvent sur votre disque dur. Cependant, cela peut nuire à l’URL et à la page Web (« site d’origine ») à partir desquelles vous avez accédé à notre site.

23. Renseignements supplémentaires et législation applicable

Cette politique de confidentialité s’applique à la loi de 2002 de la Commission australienne de lutte contre la criminalité (« Australian Crime Commission Act 2002 »).

Si vous avez besoin de renseignements supplémentaires sur la protection des Renseignements personnels, veuillez visiter le site suivant : [www.privacy.gov.au/](http://www.privacy.gov.au/).

Modalités d’utilisation du site Web - FR
----------------------------------------

### Version 1.3

##### Effective June 25th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**Modalités d’utilisation du site Web**

**Certn Holdings Inc.**

**Date d’entrée en vigueur : 11 novembre 2022**

Certn Holdings Inc., y compris ses sociétés affiliées Certn (Canada) Inc., Certn (États-Unis) Inc. et toute autre filiale en propriété exclusive (« **Certn** », « **nous** », « **notre** » ou « **nos** ») fournissent le contenu et les services accessibles sur ce site Web (le « **site Web** »). Sauf disposition contraire des présentes, les présentes conditions d’utilisation du site Web (les « **Modalités** ») régissent votre accès aux services et leur utilisation, y compris les fonctions et le contenu disponibles sur ce site Web et sur d’autres sites Web proposés par Certn, ses sociétés affiliées et ses partenaires, y compris, mais sans s’y limiter : l’obtention, la livraison et la gestion de rapports d’antécédents et de la documentation connexe; l’obtention d’informations sur l’état des rapports d’antécédents; les processus de Certn pour la production de rapports d’antécédents et la résolution d’éventuelles inexactitudes; la demande d’une copie de votre dossier de consommateur; et/ou tout litige lié à la vérification de vos antécédents (collectivement, les « **Services** »). Votre accès aux Services, votre examen et/ou votre utilisation des Services sont conditionnels à votre acceptation et à votre respect des présentes Modalités.

**_Généralités_**

1. En accédant au Site Web et/ou en utilisant les Services, vous acceptez d’être lié par les présentes Modalités et notre >, ainsi que par d’autres conditions de service supplémentaires régissant votre utilisation d’un Service particulier et qui sont toutes intégrées aux présentes par renvoi. Les dispositions contenues dans les présentes Modalités s’ajoutent à tout contrat de services signé relativement aux Services (le « **Contrat de services** ») et ne le remplacent pas. **SI VOUS N’ACCEPTEZ PAS CES MODALITÉS, VOUS NE POUVEZ PAS UTILISER LE SITE WEB OU Y ACCÉDER.**
2. Vous devez être âgé de 18 ans ou avoir atteint l’âge de la majorité dans votre territoire afin de générer une vérification des antécédents ou d’utiliser les Services. Ce site Web n’est pas destiné aux enfants de moins de 13 ans. Si vous êtes âgé de moins de 13 ans, vous ne pouvez pas nous fournir de Renseignements personnels, faire un achat sur le site Web ou vous inscrire sur le site Web.
3. Certn peut réviser les Modalités à tout moment sans préavis. Les Modalités révisées prendront effet dès leur publication sur le site Web. Nonobstant ce qui précède, Certn vous informera de toute révision susceptible d’avoir un impact sur le fond ou de restreindre votre utilisation du site Web et/ou des Services.
4. Les présentes Modalités s’appliquent à tous les consommateurs et utilisateurs des services de Certn, y compris, mais sans s’y limiter, les individus, les petites et grandes entreprises et les organismes à but non lucratif qui utilisent les Services, ainsi qu’à toutes les autres personnes qui accèdent aux Services, y compris, mais sans s’y limiter, les visiteurs du site Web et les utilisateurs des sites Web affiliés qui permettent l’accès aux Services de Certn (« **Consommateurs** », « **Clients** », « **Utilisateurs** », « **vous** » ou « **votre** ») y compris les héritiers, les ayants droit et les successeurs de chaque Utilisateur. Si vous utilisez les Services au nom d’une entité commerciale, vous déclarez et garantissez que vous avez le pouvoir de lier cette entité, que votre acceptation des Modalités sera considérée comme une acceptation par cette entité et que « vous » et « votre » utilisés aux présentes feront référence à cette entité.
5. Sous réserve des restrictions d’âge décrites ci-dessus, vous pourriez être en mesure de nous soumettre des renseignements par le biais de votre utilisation des Services. Vous acceptez de nous fournir des renseignements exacts à votre sujet, y compris tout renseignement que vous pouvez soumettre en vue des vérifications d’antécédents effectuées à votre sujet ou demandées par vous. Vous acceptez également que votre soumission de ces renseignements soit assujettie à notre Politique de confidentialité.
6. Dans la mesure où les présentes Modalités entrent en conflit avec votre Contrat de services, le Contrat de services prévaut. Si vous concluez une entente avec Certn en proposant des Modalités différentes ou supplémentaires concernant les Services et qu’il y a un conflit entre une disposition des présentes Modalités et une disposition d’un tel contrat, ce dernier prévaut en ce qui concerne la disposition en conflit.

**_Restrictions_**

7. Vous acceptez de ne pas accéder au site Web ou de ne pas l’utiliser à des fins illégales ou à toute fin autre que celle pour laquelle Certn le rend accessible. Vous reconnaissez que vous ne devez pas : a) transmettre des données illégales; nocives, menaçantes, insultantes, dérangeantes, injurieuses, obscènes, diffamatoires, inacceptables d’un point de vue racial ou ethnique; b) violer nos droits de propriété intellectuelle; c) recueillir illégalement des renseignements sur d’autres personnes; d) utiliser toute information obtenue du site Web afin de harceler ou de maltraiter une autre personne ou de lui faire du tort; e) tenter d’usurper l’identité d’un autre utilisateur ou d’une autre personne ou utiliser le nom d’utilisateur d’un autre utilisateur; f) publier ou transmettre autrement tout logiciel malveillant ou tout autre code informatique; fichier ou programme conçu pour interrompre, perturber ou restreindre le fonctionnement de notre site Web, notre logiciel informatique, notre matériel informatique, notre équipement de télécommunications ou pour perturber les transactions normales sur notre site Web; g) utiliser un robot, une araignée, un lecteur hors ligne, une recherche de site, une application d’extraction ou autre dispositif ou processus manuel ou automatique en vue d’extraire, d’indexer, d’explorer des données ou de reproduire ou de contourner de quelque manière que ce soit la structure ou la présentation du site Web, son contenu, ou toute donnée traitée; h) utiliser nos services de soutien de manière inappropriée; soumettre de fausses demandes, ou passer des commandes spéculatives ou frauduleuses de vérification des antécédents; i) modifier, adapter, concéder en sous-licence, « copier », « reproduire », traduire, vendre, désosser, décompiler ou désassembler une partie quelconque du site Web ou tenter autrement de dériver un code source ou des idées ou algorithmes sous-jacents d’une partie quelconque du site Web ou des Services qui y sont liés; j) utiliser, ou tenter d’utiliser, le site Web à des fins non autorisées; k) utiliser le site Web au profit d’un tiers sans l’autorisation écrite préalable de Certn; l) créer des œuvres dérivées fondées sur le site Web ou utiliser le site Web pour élaborer une offre concurrentielle de produits; ou m) modifier, supprimer ou dissimuler les droits d’auteur, marques de commerce, brevets ou autres avis ou légendes qui apparaissent sur le site Web.

**_Compte d’utilisateur_**

8. Vous devrez peut-être enregistrer un compte auprès de Certn afin d’utiliser les Services. Il vous incombe de préserver la confidentialité de votre compte, de votre nom d’utilisateur et de votre mot de passe et de restreindre l’accès à votre ordinateur. Vous acceptez d’assumer la responsabilité de toutes les activités qui se produisent avec votre permission ou autorisation en vertu de votre compte, votre nom d’utilisateur et/ou votre mot de passe. Si vous accédez et utilisez le site Web et les Services au nom de quelqu’un d’autre, vous déclarez avoir le pouvoir de lier cette personne en tant que mandant à toutes les Modalités prévues dans les présentes. Nous nous réservons le droit de refuser le service et/ou de résilier des comptes sans préavis si les présentes Modalités sont violées ou si nous décidons, à notre seule discrétion, qu’il serait dans notre meilleur intérêt de le faire.

**_Services fournis par des tiers_**

10. À votre seule discrétion, vous pouvez choisir de profiter de certains services offerts par le biais du site Web qui sont créés, offerts, soutenus et maintenus par des tiers (« **Développeurs tiers** ») non affiliés à Certn ou à ses sociétés affiliées (collectivement, les « **Services fournis par des tiers** »). Nonobstant toute disposition contraire des présentes Conditions, vous reconnaissez et acceptez que : a) vous accédez ou déployez des Services fournis par des tiers par le biais du site Web à votre seule discrétion; b) vous devez lire les conditions générales et les politiques de confidentialité associées à tout service fourni par des tiers qui régissent votre utilisation de ces services tiers; et c) Certn ne possède ni ne contrôle les Développeurs tiers ou les Services fournis par des tiers.
11. Certn ne garantit en aucun cas l’exactitude, la fiabilité, la sécurité, l’exhaustivité, l’utilité, l’absence de contrefaçon ou la qualité de tout Service fourni par des tiers. Vous convenez que vous assumez tous les risques associés à l’utilisation de Services fournis par des tiers ou au recours à ces derniers.

**_Propriété intellectuelle et licence restreinte_**

12. Tous les droits de propriété intellectuelle liés au site Web et aux services appartiennent à Certn dans leur intégralité. Ces droits comprennent les droits sur les bases de données, les brevets, les droits d’auteur, les marques (déposées ou non), les secrets commerciaux, les droits sur les dessins et modèles (déposés ou non), le savoir-faire, les travaux sur les masques, les droits moraux et tous les droits similaires qui peuvent exister actuellement ou ultérieurement dans toute juridiction, y compris, mais sans s’y limiter, toutes les demandes et tous les enregistrements relatifs à ce qui précède, et le nom Certn, les logos, les dessins, les noms de domaine, les graphiques, les icônes, les scripts, les marques de service, les caractéristiques, les fonctions, les textes, les graphiques, les icônes de boutons, les scripts, les marques de service, les images, les logiciels, les compilations de données et autres éléments de marque distinctifs, ainsi que la compilation et l’organisation de ceux-ci (collectivement, les « **Droits de propriété intellectuelle** »). Tous ces Droits de propriété intellectuelle sont et resteront la propriété exclusive de Certn et de ses filiales, sociétés affiliées, partenaires et concédants de licence, et sont protégés par les lois canadiennes, américaines et internationales, y compris les lois régissant le droit d’auteur et les marques de commerce. À l’exception de ce qui est explicitement prévu dans les présentes, ou de ce qui est requis par la loi applicable, rien dans les présentes Modalités ne vous donne le droit d’utiliser les Droits de propriété intellectuelle, et il est interdit d’utiliser, de reproduire, de dupliquer, de copier, de vendre, de revendre, d’accéder, de modifier ou d’exploiter autrement les Services ou toute partie du site Web, en tout ou en partie, à quelque fin que ce soit, sans notre consentement écrit exprès et préalable.
13. Sous réserve des présentes Modalités, Certn vous accorde une licence mondiale, restreinte, révocable et non exclusive vous autorisant à accéder au Site Web et aux Services et à utiliser ceux-ci, tels qu’ils vous sont fournis par Certn pour votre usage personnel et non commercial seulement. La licence est non transférable et non cessible, et vous ne devez pas accorder à un tiers quelconque un droit, une permission, une licence ou une sous-licence concernant l’un des droits accordés en vertu des présentes sans l’autorisation écrite préalable de Certn, qu’elle peut refuser à sa seule discrétion. Vous reconnaissez que Certn est le propriétaire et le concédant de licence des Droits de propriété intellectuelle et que votre utilisation des Droits de propriété intellectuelle ne vous confère aucun intérêt supplémentaire ni aucune titularité sur ces droits de propriété intellectuelle. La violation de toute disposition de cette licence peut entraîner la résiliation immédiate de la licence, à la seule discrétion de Certn.
14. Nous pouvons vous inviter à clavarder ou à participer à des blogues, des forums en ligne et à d’autres fonctionnalités et nous pouvons vous donner l’occasion de créer, de soumettre, de publier ou de diffuser du contenu et du matériel sur notre site Web et/ou par l’intermédiaire du site Web, des formulaires, des courriels, des agents de clavardage, des fenêtres contextuelles, y compris, sans s’y limiter, des textes, des écrits, des vidéos, de l’audio, des photographies, des graphiques, des commentaires, des suggestions ou d’autres documents (collectivement, les « **Contributions** »). Toute Contribution que vous transmettez à Certn sera traitée comme non confidentielle et non exclusive.

**Autorisation pour la vérification des antécédents et certains droits en vertu de la législation sur les droits des consommateurs, y compris la Loi sur l’évaluation équitable du crédit (« Fair Credit Reporting Act » ou « FCRA »)**
---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

15. Les Services peuvent vous permettre de demander une copie de la vérification de vos antécédents ou des rapports de vos antécédents. En demandant une copie, vous autorisez Certn et ses entrepreneurs/fournisseurs à utiliser les renseignements que vous nous fournissez aux fins de vérification de vos antécédents et de production de rapports pour vous. Vous convenez que Certn n’a aucune obligation de surveiller ou de modifier les renseignements que vous nous soumettez et que vous êtes seul responsable de leur exhaustivité et de leur exactitude.
16. Dans le cadre de la vérification des antécédents, Certn peut recueillir certaines données, y compris, sans s’y limiter, les dossiers en matière de véhicule à moteur, les casiers judiciaires et d’autres renseignements accessibles au public. Certn traitera ces données conformément à notre Politique de confidentialité.
17. Dans la mesure où votre demande ou votre utilisation des Services concerne un résident des États-Unis, vous accusez réception des trois avis prévus par la loi indiqués ci-dessous et certifiez les avoir examinés et pleinement compris :
    * [Résumé de vos droits en vertu de la Loi sur l’évaluation équitable du crédit (« Fair Credit Reporting Act ») (16 C.F.R. Part 601)](http://files.consumerfinance.gov/f/201504_cfpb_summary_your-rights-under-fcra.pdf) (en anglais uniquement)
    * [Corriger les effets du vol d’identité (« Remedying the Effects of Identity Theft »)](http://files.consumerfinance.gov/f/201410_cfpb_summary_remedying-the-effects-of-id-theft-fcra.pdf) (en anglais uniquement)
    * [Avis aux utilisateurs de rapports sur les consommateurs (« Notice to Users of Consumer Reports ») (16 C.F.R. partie 601)](https://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/CFR-2012-title12-vol8/pdf/CFR-2012-title12-vol8-part1022-appN.pdf) (en anglais uniquement)
18. Aucune disposition des présentes Modalités n’aura d’incidence sur votre droit : a) d’accéder à certains renseignements contenus dans votre dossier en communiquant avec nous, ou b) de nous en aviser et de nous demander de faire enquête sur les renseignements que vous jugez inexacts ou incomplets dans la vérification de vos antécédents, comme prévu à l’article 15 U.S.C. §§ 1681c-1, 1681g et 1681i de la FCRA.

**Frais**
---------

19. Dans le cadre de votre utilisation des Services, Certn peut facturer certains frais (« **Frais** ») lorsque vous commandez un rapport sur les antécédents. Vous acceptez de payer tous les Frais applicables en fonction des conditions alors en vigueur. Une fois les Services lancés, les Frais ne sont pas remboursables. Les services de traitement des paiements fournis par notre processeur de paiement tiers sont soumis à ses conditions.

**_Résiliation_**

20. Vous acceptez que Certn n’assume aucune responsabilité envers vous ou un tiers en cas de résiliation ou de limitation de votre accès au site Web ou de votre utilisation du site Web.

**_Avis de non-responsabilité_**

21. Sauf disposition contraire expresse, le site Web est fourni « en l’état » et « selon sa disponibilité ». Certn décline expressément toute garantie de quelque nature que ce soit, expresse ou implicite, y compris, mais sans s’y limiter, les garanties implicites de qualité marchande, d’adéquation à un usage particulier et d’absence de contrefaçon en ce qui concerne le site Web et tout le contenu fourni sur le site Web ou par son intermédiaire. Certn ne garantit pas que : a) le site Web ou son contenu répondra à vos exigences; b) le site Web sera disponible sans interruption, en temps opportun, en toute sécurité et sans erreur; c) les résultats qui peuvent être obtenus au moyen de l’utilisation du site Web, ou tout contenu fourni sur le site Web ou par son intermédiaire seront absolument exacts, exempts d’erreurs et fiables; ou d) tout contenu obtenu par vous sur le site Web ou par son intermédiaire répondra à vos attentes.
22. Vous reconnaissez que : i) le site Web utilise Internet pour le transfert de données et les serveurs connectés à Internet pour stocker des antécédents personnels, parfois avec des tiers fournisseurs, en recourant à des mesures de sécurité standard de l’industrie; et ii) aucune mesure de sécurité n’est efficace à 100 %.

**Indemnisation**
-----------------

23. Vous vous engagez à indemniser et à dégager de toute responsabilité Certn, ses sociétés affiliées et ses filiales, ainsi que leurs dirigeants, administrateurs, employés et agents respectifs, en cas de dommages, pénalités, pertes, responsabilités, jugements, règlements, récompenses, coûts et dépenses (y compris les honoraires et dépenses raisonnables d’avocats) découlant de ou en relation avec toute réclamation, affirmation, demande, cause d’action, poursuite, procédure ou autre action d’un tiers, que ce soit en droit ou en équité, liée de quelque manière que ce soit à : i) toute violation par vous des présentes Conditions ii) votre violation des lois ou ordonnances applicables, ou iii) votre négligence, votre mauvaise conduite, votre imprudence, ou vos erreurs ou omissions.

**Limitation de responsabilité**

24. DANS LA MESURE MAXIMALE PERMISE PAR LA LOI, CERTN ET SES FILIALES, SOCIÉTÉS AFFILIÉES, PARTENAIRES, CONCÉDANTS DE LICENCE, DIRECTEURS, DIRIGEANTS, LES EMPLOYÉS ET LES AGENTS NE SERONT PAS RESPONSABLES EN RAISON D’UN CONTRAT, D’UNE GARANTIE OU D’UN DÉLIT (Y COMPRIS LA NÉGLIGENCE) POUR a) LES INTERRUPTIONS DE SERVICES; b) LES RETARDS OU INTERRUPTIONS D’ACCÈS AU SITE; c) LA NON-LIVRAISON, LES ERREURS DE LIVRAISON, LA CORRUPTION OU LA DESTRUCTION DE DONNÉES, OU TOUTE AUTRE MODIFICATION DE CELLES-CI; d) LES PERTES OU DOMMAGES DE QUELQUE NATURE QUE CE SOIT DÉCOULANT D’INTERACTIONS AVEC LE SITE OU DE LA PRÉSENCE DE LIENS HORS SITE SUR LE SITE; e) LA PRÉSENCE DE VIRUS INFORMATIQUES, LES PANNES DE SYSTÈME, OU TOUTE DÉFAILLANCE QUI PEUVENT SURVENIR EN LIEN AVEC VOTRE UTILISATION DU SITE OU DES SERVICES; f) LES INEXACTITUDES, ERREURS OU OMISSIONS AU NIVEAU DU CONTENU OU g) LES ÉVÉNEMENTS INDÉPENDANTS DE NOTRE VOLONTÉ.
25. EN OUTRE, CERTN NE SERA PAS RESPONSABLE DANS LE CADRE D’UN CONTRAT, D’UNE GARANTIE OU D’UN DÉLIT (Y COMPRIS LA NÉGLIGENCE) OU DE TOUTE AUTRE THÉORIE JURIDIQUE POUR TOUT DOMMAGE INDIRECT, PUNITIF, SPÉCIAL, DE CONFIANCE, ACCESSOIRE, CONSÉCUTIF OU SIMILAIRE DE QUELQUE NATURE QUE CE SOIT (Y COMPRIS LA PERTE DE REVENUS OU DE PROFITS) DÉCOULANT DE OU LIÉ À CES CONDITIONS, AU SITE OU À VOTRE UTILISATION DE CELUI-CI, Y COMPRIS L’UTILISATION OU L’INCAPACITÉ D’UTILISER LES SERVICES, OU POUR TOUT RENSEIGNEMENT OBTENU À PARTIR DES SERVICES OU PAR LEUR INTERMÉDIAIRE, MÊME SI CERTN A ÉTÉ INFORMÉ DE LA POSSIBILITÉ DE TELS DOMMAGES, ET EN AUCUN CAS NE DÉPASSERA LE MONTANT PAYÉ À CERTN OU À SES PARTENAIRES POUR LES SERVICES AU COURS DE LA PÉRIODE DE DOUZE MOIS PRÉCÉDANT IMMÉDIATEMENT LE DÉBUT DE TOUTE RÉCLAMATION POUR DOMMAGES.
26. CERTN N'EST PAS RESPONSABLE DES RÉSULTATS OBTENUS. VOTRE RECOURS UNIQUE ET EXCLUSIF CONCERNANT LE CONTENU DES RAPPORTS EST DE CONTESTER LES RÉSULTATS.
27. LES PARAGRAPHES QUI PRÉCÈDENT N’EXCLUENT NI NE LIMITENT LA RESPONSABILITÉ À L’ÉGARD DE TOUTE RÉCLAMATION, DEMANDE OU ACTION EN DOMMAGES-INTÉRÊTS DÉCOULANT D’UNE NÉGLIGENCE GRAVE, D’UNE FRAUDE OU D’UNE FAUTE INTENTIONNELLE DE LA PART DE CERTN OU DE SES EMPLOYÉS.
28. Certains territoires n’autorisent pas les avis de non-responsabilité ou l’exclusion de certaines garanties de l’avis de non-responsabilité, de l’exclusion ou de la limitation de certaines responsabilités. Dans la mesure où ils sont jugés légalement invalides, les avis de non-responsabilité, les exclusions et les limitations énoncés dans les présentes Modalités ne s’appliquent pas à vous et toutes les autres Modalités resteront pleinement en vigueur.

**Loi applicable**

28. Toutes les questions relatives aux services et à votre accès au Site Web et au contenu fourni sur le Site Web ou par son intermédiaire, ainsi qu’à votre utilisation de ceux-ci, seront régies par les lois de la province de la Colombie-Britannique et les lois fédérales du Canada qui s’y appliquent.

**Divers**

29. Les parties sont des entrepreneurs indépendants. Aucune disposition des présentes Modalités ne doit être interprétée comme créant un emploi, une relation de mandataire, un partenariat, une franchise, une coentreprise ou toute autre forme de coentreprise ou d’autorité pour lier l’autre partie.
30. Toute renonciation à une disposition des présentes Modalités ne sera valide que si elle est fournie par écrit et ne s’applique qu’à l’événement particulier ainsi annulé. Le défaut d’appliquer une disposition ne constitue pas une renonciation.
31. Rien dans les présentes Modalités ne limitera la capacité d’une partie à solliciter un redressement équitable.
32. Les titres des chapitres ne doivent pas être utilisés pour l’interprétation des présentes.
33. Dans l’éventualité où l’une ou l’autre des dispositions du présent Contrat serait réputée invalide ou non exécutoire en tout ou en partie, toutes les autres dispositions continueront néanmoins d’être valides et exécutoires, et les éléments invalides ou non exécutoires seront retirés du reste des Modalités.

**Avis et consentement à recevoir des avis par voie électronique**

34. Vous consentez à obtenir auprès de nous tout contrat, avis, divulgation et autre communication (collectivement, les « **Avis** ») auxquels les présentes Modalités font référence par voie électronique, y compris, sans s’y limiter, par courriel ou en publiant des avis sur ce Site Web. Vous convenez que tous les Avis que nous vous fournissons par voie électronique satisfont à toute exigence légale selon laquelle ces communications doivent être faites par écrit.
35. Sauf indication contraire dans les présentes Modalités, tous les avis en vertu des présentes Modalités seront rédigés par écrit et seront réputés avoir été dûment donnés lorsqu’ils auront été reçus, s’ils ont été remis en mains propres ou envoyés par courrier certifié ou recommandé, avec accusé de réception lorsque la réception est confirmée par voie électronique, s’ils ont été transmis par télécopie ou par courriel; ou le jour suivant leur envoi, s’ils ont été envoyés pour une livraison le lendemain par un service de livraison de nuit reconnu.
36. Si vous avez des questions sur les présentes Modalités, vous pouvez contacter le service clientèle par courrier électronique à l’adresse support@certn.co.

OneID Consent - Portal Version (EN)
-----------------------------------

### Version 6.1

##### Effective December 11th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**Biometric Consent**

We need your consent to collect and process your biometric data for the purpose of verifying your identity on behalf of our client (the “**Company**”). Biometric data in this instance includes facial features from a real-time photo and information from your government-issued ID. We will store your biometric data securely and implement appropriate measures to safeguard such information against unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction.

By clicking “agree” below, you confirm that you have read and understood this Biometric Consent, as well as our [Biometric Notice](https://vault.pactsafe.io/s/5d800911-f26c-4e3a-884d-85117a81799b/legal.html?g=37964#contract-s1qa70-t6), and you agree to the collection and processing of your biometric data in accordance with these terms and our [Privacy Policy](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/). Further, you acknowledge and agree to the transfer of your biometric data to the Company in connection with your background check and verification and any applicable third-party sub-processors, solely for the purpose of completing your identity verification. This consent is given voluntarily and with the understanding that the data will be used exclusively for identity verification including the prevention and combat of fraud. Your biometric data, and where required by law, any information or copy of documents collected to support your identity verification, will be retained for the duration necessary to fulfill the intended purpose and as required by applicable laws, and will be securely deleted thereafter. If you choose not to consent, we may not be able to process your application or provide verification results for your background check.

You can revoke your consent at any time by notifying us in writing at [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co). Upon revocation, we will notify the Company and cease the collection, use, and retention of your biometric data. You have the right to request access to your biometric data and to request corrections or deletions of inaccuracies. If you require more information about the nature and scope of your data processing or for a copy of the information we hold about you, please contact Certn’s Privacy Officer at 1-844-987-0690 or [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co).

If you reside in a location that is different from our processing locations or the location of the Company, we may transfer your Personal Information for the purpose of completing the identity verification, in accordance with our [Privacy Policy](https://vault.pactsafe.io/s/5d800911-f26c-4e3a-884d-85117a81799b/legal.html?g=37964#contract-byeg-ihlj) and applicable privacy laws.

Canadian Criminal Consent - HR
------------------------------

### Version 1.0

##### Effective June 19th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

I hereby consent to a search of all currently available criminal records and information, including non-conviction information, charges before the court, findings of guilt or convictions and court orders or records registered in my name in the National Repository of Criminal Records, the Canadian Police Information Centre (“CPIC”) database, the Police Information Portal (“PIP”) and any other data sharing platform available to the police service provider for the purposes of delivering a criminal record check in relation to my application for employment with the Employer (the “Employer”).  

I understand that this criminal record check is based on the name(s), date of birth and, where used, the declared criminal record history I provide. I understand that the results are not being confirmed by fingerprint comparison which is the only true means by which to confirm if a criminal record exists in the National Repository of Criminal Records.

I certify that the information set out by me in this application is true and correct to the best of my ability. I consent to the release of the results of the criminal record check to Certn and the Employer. I acknowledge and agree that the Employer may collect, use and disclose the information collected for the purposes of evaluating my suitability for employment with the Employer.

I acknowledge that if I do not consent to Certn’s and/or the Employer’s collection, use and disclosure of the information, this may result in my conditional offer of employment being void. Without a conditional offer of employment, I will not have an employment relationship with the Employer for any purposes.

I hereby release and forever discharge all members and employees of the processing police service and the Royal Canadian Mounted Police from any and all actions, claims and demands for damages, loss or injury whatsoever arising which may hereinafter be sustained by me as a result of the disclosure of information to Certn and the Employer.

By clicking “I understand and agree” I consent to Certn collecting, processing and disclosing my personal information pursuant to the terms set out above and Certn’s [Privacy Policy](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/).

_You can request more information about the nature and scope of your criminal record check by contacting Certn’s Privacy Officer at 1-844-987-0690 or privacy@certn.co_

Canadian Criminal Consent - PM (FR)
-----------------------------------

### Version 1.0

##### Effective June 19th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

Je consens par la présente à une recherche de tous les dossiers et renseignements criminels actuellement disponibles, y compris les renseignements sur les non-condamnations, les accusations devant les tribunaux, les déclarations de culpabilité ou les condamnations, ainsi que les ordonnances ou les dossiers judiciaires enregistrés à mon nom dans le Répertoire national des casiers judiciaires, la base de données du Centre d'information de la police canadienne («**CPIC**»), le Portail d'information de la police («**PIP**») et toute autre plateforme de partage de données disponible pour le fournisseur de services de police aux fins de réalisation d'une vérification du casier judiciaire dans le cadre de ma demande auprès du propriétaire ou du gestionnaire immobilier, le cas échéant (le «**Propriétaire**»).

Je comprends que cette vérification des antécédents criminels est basée sur le(s) nom(s), la date de naissance et, le cas échéant, les antécédents criminels déclarés par moi-même. Je comprends que les résultats ne seront pas confirmés par comparaison d'empreintes digitales, qui est le seul moyen véritable de confirmer l'existence d'un casier judiciaire dans le Répertoire national des casiers judiciaires.

Je certifie que les informations fournies dans cette demande sont véridiques et correctes selon mes connaissances. Je consens à la divulgation des résultats de la vérification des antécédents criminels à Certn et au Locateur. Je reconnais et accepte que le Locateur puisse recueillir, utiliser et divulguer les informations recueillies aux fins d'évaluer ma demande.

Je libère par la présente et à jamais tous les membres et employés du service de police chargé du traitement ainsi que la Gendarmerie royale du Canada de toute action, réclamation et demande de dommages-intérêts, perte ou préjudice quelconque pouvant survenir à l'avenir du fait de la divulgation d'informations à Certn et au propriétaire.

En cliquant sur «Je comprends et j’accete», je consens à ce que Certn collecte, traite et divulgue mes informations personnelles conformément aux modalités précédemment énoncées et à la [Politique de confidentialité](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/) de Certn.

_Vous pouvez demander plus d'informations sur la nature et la portée de toute vérification de casier judiciaire à effectuer en contactant le responsable de la confidentialité de Certn au 844-987-0690 ou à_ [_privacy@certn.co_](mailto:privacy@certn.co)

Canadian Criminal Consent - HR (FR)
-----------------------------------

### Version 1.0

##### Effective June 19th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

Je consens par la présente à une recherche de tous les dossiers et renseignements criminels actuellement disponibles, y compris les renseignements sur les non-condamnations, les accusations devant les tribunaux, les déclarations de culpabilité ou les condamnations, ainsi que les ordonnances ou les dossiers judiciaires enregistrés à mon nom dans le Répertoire national des casiers judiciaires, la base de données du Centre d'information de la police canadienne («**CPIC**»), le Portail d'information de la police («**PIP**») et toute autre plateforme de partage de données disponible pour le fournisseur de services de police aux fins de réalisation d'une vérification du casier judiciaire dans le cadre de ma demande d'emploi auprès de l'Employeur («**l’Employeur**»).

Je comprends que cette vérification du casier judiciaire est basée sur le(s) nom(s), la date de naissance et, le cas échéant, l'historique du casier judiciaire déclaré que je fournis. Je comprends que les résultats ne sont pas confirmés par une comparaison d'empreintes digitales, qui est le seul moyen véritable de confirmer l'existence d'un casier judiciaire dans le Répertoire national des casiers judiciaires.

Je certifie que les informations que j'ai fournies dans cette demande sont véridiques et exactes au mieux de mes capacités. Je consens à la communication des résultats de la vérification du casier judiciaire à Certn et à l'Employeur. Je reconnais et accepte que l'Employeur puisse collecter, utiliser et divulguer les informations recueillies dans le but d’évaluer mon aptitude à l’emploi chez l'Employeur.

Je reconnais que le fait de ne pas consentir à la collecte, à l’utilisation et à la divulgation de ces renseignements par Certn et/ou l'Employeur pourrait entraîner l’annulation de mon offre d’emploi conditionnelle. Dans ce cas, je n’aurai pas de relation d’emploi avec l'Employeur à quelque fin que ce soit.

Par la présente, je libère et décharge à jamais tous les membres et employeurs du service de police traitant et de la Gendarmerie royale du Canada de toutes actions, réclamations et demandes de dommages, pertes ou blessures, quelles qu'elles soient, qui pourraient être subies par moi-même à la suite de la divulgation d'informations au Certn et à l'employeur.

En cliquant sur «Je comprends et j'accepte», je consens à ce que Certn recueille, traite et divulgue mes informations personnelles conformément aux modalités énoncées ci-dessus et à la [Politique de confidentialité](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/) de Certn.

_Vous pouvez demander plus d'informations sur la nature et la portée de toute vérification de casier judiciaire à effectuer en contactant le responsable de la confidentialité de Certn au 844-987-0690 ou à [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co)._

Background Screening Consent - HR English (Procom/Deloitte)
-----------------------------------------------------------

### Version 3.0

##### Effective July 24th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

I understand and acknowledge that I am agreeing to this consent electronically and by doing so, to the extent permitted by applicable law:  

(1) I hereby authorize Certn (and its designated representatives, as applicable) to collect, use, disclose and independently verify my Personal Information which may include, but is not limited to, my name, address, email address, date of birth, public criminal history, and my right to work (collectively, "Personal Information") for the purposes of delivering a background screening report in relation to my application for employment with the Company.

(2) I acknowledge and agree that the Company may collect, use and disclose the Personal Information for the purposes of evaluating my suitability for employment with the Company;

(3) I also authorize Certn to (i) contact the relevant law enforcement agencies as well as all other accessible private and public sector archives (including any other person, organization, or agency) and (ii) receive copies of verified results on me through any reasonable means including in writing, electronic transmission or over the phone;

(4) I understand and agree that, where my personal history requires background verifications to be carried out in countries where I have worked, studied, or resided, my Personal Information may be sent and verified in those relevant countries.

(5) I agree that an electronic copy of this consent is equally effective as an original signature for the purposes of validity, enforceability, and admissibility and authorize Certn to export this Background Screening Consent in a PDF document and present it to any of my referees which may request a proof of my consent for the purposes set out above;

(6) I acknowledge that I have read and understood Certn’s [Privacy Policy](https://secure-web.cisco.com/1wc00wjYeLByBcSKXsm-4zYU-k6lZjRXdE0pMYxWeCuCPG33vTBrTXBHLUEdP5E-m5ryzpStdUJjE0rWSLsAFMPhK0A6fq-VfDlZgA0pF2-z1dp8G6lui8GRFLe7S56es9a2LVrdfoaau59XZ4vgTCU9IGnA1QH8bSdFVRG11UX72ogoNGAd8Me_m5sMTCBZvIxNVb4MRImilqCKLWqySkr3xk2SLU-UvegPmkhX3yyexVMBKvxb9HVLfmuQ_SjDobOBAln7OKFR9h4f3G7wl0iBsA_Ibky4BLZY0hiW_e4emppWIh6wAnfRkhe2jNRaC/https://t.sidekickopen24.com/Ctc/2I+23284/ck6Xz04/Jks2-6q7W69sMD-6lZ3m2W5dnhln7S6XN8VD0g286TT3LvMWg5vBsNFBrW4hyR8K3-slJlW7HMJ1r5Kd1PXW5ghvwg9kyQ_8W7XJGSW7vTzjrW7NF6BY4CjqQvW1FYm764_xjzTN8ZzR72K1cRdN3nh2_BxvBPhW3Fw_5b4HwpVYW52cyjz8nQPNpW8C-s5Z7g6CdrW4C4pX01qRsBTW7YcgLv4mcKjBW7cz_gD4Jn3qRW64Zf076HKYhMVF2tRz5Rj3NtW30jHgk8Gvbflf7Y_qHs04 "https://secure-web.cisco.com/1wc00wjYeLByBcSKXsm-4zYU-k6lZjRXdE0pMYxWeCuCPG33vTBrTXBHLUEdP5E-m5ryzpStdUJjE0rWSLsAFMPhK0A6fq-VfDlZgA0pF2-z1dp8G6lui8GRFLe7S56es9a2LVrdfoaau59XZ4vgTCU9IGnA1QH8bSdFVRG11UX72ogoNGAd8Me_m5sMTCBZvIxNVb4MRImilqCKLWqySkr3xk2SLU-UvegPmkhX3yyexVMBKvxb9HVLfmuQ_SjDobOBAln7OKFR9h4f3G7wl0iBsA_Ibky4BLZY0hiW_e4emppWIh6wAnfRkhe2jNRaC/https://t.sidekickopen24.com/Ctc/2I+23284/ck6Xz04/Jks2-6q7W69sMD-6lZ3m2W5dnhln7S6XN8VD0g286TT3LvMWg5vBsNFBrW4hyR8K3-slJlW7HMJ1r5Kd1PXW5ghvwg9kyQ_8W7XJGSW7vTzjrW7NF6BY4CjqQvW1FYm764_xjzTN8ZzR72K1cRdN3nh2_BxvBPhW3Fw_5b4HwpVYW52cyjz8nQPNpW8C-s5Z7g6CdrW4C4pX01qRsBTW7YcgLv4mcKjBW7cz_gD4Jn3qRW64Zf076HKYhMVF2tRz5Rj3NtW30jHgk8Gvbflf7Y_qHs04") and hereby confirm that my consent is fully informed and freely given and I am aware that I can withdraw it at any time.

(7) I acknowledge that if I do not consent to Certn’s and/or the Company’s collection, use and disclosure of the information, this may result in my conditional offer being void. Without a conditional offer, I will not have a relationship with the Company for any purposes; and

(8) I acknowledge that if I am denied employment wholly or partly because of information received from a consumer reporting agency or credit information obtained from a person other than a consumer reporting agency, if required by law, the Company and/or Certn will notify me of that fact and, upon request by me within the time limits required by the applicable legislation, shall inform me of the nature and source of the information where the information is furnished by a person other than a consumer reporting agency; or of the name and address of the consumer reporting agency, where the information is furnished by a consumer reporting agency, and any other information required by law.

If you have any questions about the collection, use, disclosure, or storage of your Personal Information or if you would like to request more information about Certn’s privacy policies and procedures, please contact Certn’s Privacy Officer at 1-844-987-0690 or [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co "mailto:privacy@certn.co").

Canadian Criminal Consent - HR (Procom/Deloitte)
------------------------------------------------

### Version 2.0

##### Effective July 24th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

To the extent permitted by applicable law, I hereby consent to a search of all records and information available at the time the search is conducted, including non-conviction information, charges before the courts, findings of guilt or convictions and court orders registered in my name in the National Repository of Criminal Records, the Canadian Police Information Centre (“CPIC”) database and local records available to the police service for the purposes of delivering a background screening report in relation to my application for employment with the Employer (“the Employer”). The query may also include a search of court records and a query of records management systems in other police agencies' jurisdictions through the Police Information Portal (PIP) or other data sharing systems.  

I understand that this criminal record check is based on my identity verification including, but not limited to the name(s), date of birth and where used, the declared criminal record history provided by myself.

I acknowledge that for the completion of the criminal record check, reported criminal records may require me to provide fingerprints.

I acknowledge and agree that the Employer may collect, use and disclose the information collected for the purposes of evaluating my suitability for employment with the Company.

I acknowledge that I have read and understood Certn’s [Privacy Policy](https://secure-web.cisco.com/1wc00wjYeLByBcSKXsm-4zYU-k6lZjRXdE0pMYxWeCuCPG33vTBrTXBHLUEdP5E-m5ryzpStdUJjE0rWSLsAFMPhK0A6fq-VfDlZgA0pF2-z1dp8G6lui8GRFLe7S56es9a2LVrdfoaau59XZ4vgTCU9IGnA1QH8bSdFVRG11UX72ogoNGAd8Me_m5sMTCBZvIxNVb4MRImilqCKLWqySkr3xk2SLU-UvegPmkhX3yyexVMBKvxb9HVLfmuQ_SjDobOBAln7OKFR9h4f3G7wl0iBsA_Ibky4BLZY0hiW_e4emppWIh6wAnfRkhe2jNRaC/https://t.sidekickopen24.com/Ctc/2I+23284/ck6Xz04/Jks2-6q7W69sMD-6lZ3m2W5dnhln7S6XN8VD0g286TT3LvMWg5vBsNFBrW4hyR8K3-slJlW7HMJ1r5Kd1PXW5ghvwg9kyQ_8W7XJGSW7vTzjrW7NF6BY4CjqQvW1FYm764_xjzTN8ZzR72K1cRdN3nh2_BxvBPhW3Fw_5b4HwpVYW52cyjz8nQPNpW8C-s5Z7g6CdrW4C4pX01qRsBTW7YcgLv4mcKjBW7cz_gD4Jn3qRW64Zf076HKYhMVF2tRz5Rj3NtW30jHgk8Gvbflf7Y_qHs04) and hereby confirm that my consent is fully informed and freely given and I am aware that I can withdraw it at any time.

I acknowledge that if I do not consent to Certn’s and/or the Employer’s collection, use and disclosure of the information, this may result in my conditional offer of employment being void. Without a conditional offer of employment, I will not have an employment relationship with the Company for any purposes.

You may request more information about the nature and scope of any criminal record checks to be conducted by contacting Certn’s Privacy Officer at 1-844-987-0690 or [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co).

_You can request more information about the nature and scope of your criminal record check by contacting Certn’s Privacy Officer at 1-844-987-0690 or privacy@certn.co_

Dollarama Canadian Criminal Consent (English)
---------------------------------------------

### Version 2.0

##### Effective August 3rd 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

We need your consent to run a Canadian criminal record check

To the extent permitted by applicable law, I hereby consent to a search of all records and information available at the time the search is conducted, including non-conviction information, charges before the courts, findings of guilt or convictions and court orders registered in my name in the National Repository of Criminal Records, the Canadian Police Information Centre (“**CPIC**”) database and local records available to the police service for the purposes of delivering a background screening report in relation to my application for employment with Dollarama (“**Employer**”) through its Staffing Firm, Appyhere (“**Staffing Firm**”). The query may also include a search of court records and a query of records management systems in other police agencies' jurisdictions through the Police Information Portal (“**PIP”**) or other data sharing systems.

I understand that this criminal record check is based on the name(s), date of birth and where used, the declared criminal record history provided by myself.

I certify that the information set out by me in this application is true and correct to the best of my ability. I consent to the release of the results of the criminal record check to Certn, the Employer, and the Staffing Firm. I acknowledge and agree that the Employer and the Staffing Firm may collect, use and disclose the information collected for the purposes of evaluating my suitability for employment with the Employer.

I acknowledge that if I do not consent to Certn’s, the Employer’s and/or the Staffing Firm’s collection, use and disclosure of the information, this may result in my conditional offer of employment being void. Without a conditional offer of employment, I will not have an employment relationship with the Employer for any purposes.

I hereby release and forever discharge all members and employers of the processing police service and the Royal Canadian Mounted Police from any and all actions, clams and demands for damages, loss or injury whatsoever arising which may hereinafter be sustained by myself as a result of the disclosure of information to Certn, the Employer and the Staffing Firm.

You may request more information about the nature and scope of any criminal record checks to be conducted by contacting Certn’s Privacy Officer at 1-844-987-0690 or [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co).

Yes, I agree

No, I do not agree

BACKNEXT

By clicking “Yes, I agree” you consent to Certn collecting and disclosing your personal information pursuant to Certn’s [Privacy Policy](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/).

Dollarama Canadian Criminal Consent (French)
--------------------------------------------

### Version 1.0

##### Effective August 3rd 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

Nous avons besoin de votre consentement pour effectuer une vérification du casier judiciaire canadien

Dans la mesure où la loi applicable le permet, je consens par la présente à une recherche de tous les dossiers et renseignements disponibles me concernant au moment où la recherche est effectuée, y compris les renseignements sur les non-condamnations, les accusations portées devant les tribunaux, les déclarations de culpabilité ou les condamnations et les ordonnances judiciaires enregistrées à mon nom dans le Répertoire national des casiers judiciaires, la base de données du Centre d’information de la police canadienne (CIPC) et les dossiers locaux dont dispose le service de police dans le but de fournir un rapport de vérification des antécédents relativement à ma demande d’emploi auprès de Dollarama l’(« Employeur ») par l'intermédiaire de son cabinet de recrutement, AppyHere (le «Cabinet de recrutement »). La requête peut également comprendre une recherche dans les dossiers judiciaires et une interrogation des systèmes de gestion des dossiers dans les juridictions d’autres services de police par le biais du Portail d’informations policières (PIP) ou d’autres systèmes de partage de données.

Je comprends que cette vérification du casier judiciaire est basée sur le(s) nom(s), la date de naissance et, le cas échéant, les antécédents judiciaires que j’aurais déclarés moi-même.

Je certifie que les informations que j'ai fournies dans cette demande sont véridiques et exactes au mieux de mes capacités. Je consens à la communication des résultats de la vérification du casier judiciaire à Certn, à l'Employeur et au Cabinet de recrutement. Je reconnais et accepte que l'Employeur et le Cabinet de recrutement puissent collecter, utiliser et divulguer les informations recueillies dans le but d’évaluer mon aptitude à l’emploi chez l'Employeur.

Je reconnais que le fait de ne pas consentir à la collecte, à l’utilisation et à la divulgation de ces renseignements par Certn, l'Employeur et/ou le Cabinet de recrutement pourrait entraîner l’annulation de mon offre d’emploi conditionnelle. Dans ce cas, je n’aurai pas de relation d’emploi avec l'Employeur à quelque fin que ce soit.

Par la présente, je libère et décharge à jamais tous les membres et employeurs du service de police traitant et de la Gendarmerie royale du Canada de toutes actions, réclamations et demandes de dommages, pertes ou blessures, quelles qu'elles soient, qui pourraient être subies par moi-même à la suite de la divulgation d'informations à Certn,à l'Employeur ou au Cabinet de recrutement.

Vous pouvez demander de plus amples informations sur la nature et la portée des vérifications du casier judiciaire qui seront effectuées en téléphonant au responsable de la protection des renseignements personnels de Certn au 1 844 987-0690 ou par courriel à [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co).

Oui, je consens

Non, je ne consens pas

RETOUR SUIVANT

En cliquant « oui, je consens », vous consentez à ce que Certn collecte et divulgue vos informations personnelles conformément à sa [Politique de confidentialité](https://vault.pactsafe.io/s/5d800911-f26c-4e3a-884d-85117a81799b/legal.html?g=37964#contract-bylz4uhm3).

Tokenized Consent Placeholder - FR
----------------------------------

### Version 1.0

##### Effective August 11th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**AUTHORIZATION**

To evaluate your suitability for {{{application\_type\_purpose}}}, the Company has asked Certn and its parent, affiliates and subsidiaries, as applicable ("**Certn**", “**we**" or "**us**”) to {{{id\_verification}}}create and return your consumer report {{{usa\_report}}}(collectively your "**Report(s)**") comprised of: {{{checks\_ordered\_list}}} (the "**Services**”).

We will collect the following personal information for the prupose of completing the Services: {{{checks\_ordered\_information\_list}}}. We may collect Personal Information directly from you, the Company, or third parties such as {{{checks\_ordered\_third\_party\_services}}}. If necessary, we will compare information received from different sources for consistency.

It may be necessary for Certn to transfer and process Personal Information in multiple jurisdictions, specifically if you have lived, worked or attended school outside of the jurisdiction in which the Company has ordered the Report. Further, depending on the Services, and the location of the Company, your Personal Information may be processed by our employees in Canada, Australia, the United States, or the United Kingdom. Regardless of where Personal Information is processed, it will be handled in accordance with our privacy and security policies.

You can withdraw your consent, dispute the accuracy of a Report, or ask for a correction, deletion or copy of your Report at any time by contacting Certn’s Privacy Officer at 1-844-987-0690 or [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co). Further information regarding the collection, use, disclosure, or storage of your Personal Information can be found [here](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/).

OneID Consent - Portal Version (FR)
-----------------------------------

### Version 2.4

##### Effective December 11th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**Consentement à la Biométrie**

Nous avons besoin de votre consentement pour collecter et traiter vos données biométriques dans le but de vérifier votre identité au nom de notre client (la « **Société** »). Les données biométriques dans ce cas incluent les caractéristiques faciales d'une photo en temps réel et les informations de votre pièce d'identité émise par le gouvernement. Nous stockerons vos données biométriques de manière sécurisée et mettrons en œuvre des mesures appropriées pour protéger ces informations contre tout accès, divulgation, altération et destruction non autorisés.

En cliquant sur « accepter » ci-dessous, vous confirmez que vous avez lu et compris ce Consentement à la Biométrie, ainsi que notre [Avis Biométrique](https://vault.pactsafe.io/s/5d800911-f26c-4e3a-884d-85117a81799b/legal.html?g=37964#contract-sjl9lwojr), et vous acceptez la collecte et le traitement de vos données biométriques conformément à ces termes et à notre [Politique de Confidentialité](https://vault.pactsafe.io/s/5d800911-f26c-4e3a-884d-85117a81799b/legal.html?g=37964#contract-bylz4uhm3). De plus, vous reconnaissez et acceptez le transfert de vos données biométriques à la Société dans le cadre de votre vérification d'antécédents et de toute sous-traitance applicable à des tiers, uniquement dans le but de compléter votre vérification d'identité. Ce consentement est donné volontairement et avec la compréhension que les données seront utilisées exclusivement pour la vérification de votre identité, y compris la prévention et la lutte contre la fraude. Vos données biométriques, et lorsque la loi l'exige, toute information ou copie de documents collectés pour soutenir votre vérification d'identité, seront conservées pendant la durée nécessaire pour atteindre l'objectif prévu et tel que requis par les lois applicables, et seront supprimées de manière sécurisée par la suite. Si vous choisissez de ne pas consentir, nous pourrions ne pas être en mesure de traiter votre demande ou de fournir les résultats de vérification pour votre vérification d'antécédents.

Vous pouvez révoquer votre consentement à tout moment en nous en informant par écrit à [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co). Dès la révocation, nous informerons la Société et cesserons la collecte, l'utilisation et la conservation de vos données biométriques. Vous avez le droit de demander l'accès à vos données biométriques et de demander des corrections ou la suppression d'inexactitudes. Si vous avez besoin de plus d'information sur la nature et l'étendue du traitement de vos données ou pour obtenir une copie des informations que nous détenons à votre sujet, veuillez contacter le Responsable de la Protection des Renseignements Personnels de Certn au 1-844-987-0690 ou [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co) .

Si vous résidez dans un lieu différent de nos lieux de traitement ou de celui de la Société, nous pouvons transférer vos Informations Personnelles dans le but de compléter la vérification de votre identité, conformément à notre [Politique de Confidentialité](https://vault.pactsafe.io/s/5d800911-f26c-4e3a-884d-85117a81799b/legal.html?g=37964#contract-bylz4uhm3) et aux lois sur la protection de la vie privée applicables.

UK Generic - Portal Version (EN)
--------------------------------

### Version 1.0

##### Effective September 14th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

I understand and acknowledge that I am agreeing to this consent electronically and by doing so, to the extent permitted by applicable law:

(1) I hereby authorize Certn and its designated representatives, as applicable, to collect, use, disclose and independently verify my Personal Information which may include, but is not limited to, my name, address, email address, date of birth, my criminal history, and my right to work (collectively, "Personal Information") for the purposes of delivering a background screening report in relation to my application for employment with the Company.

(2) I acknowledge and agree that the Company may collect, use and disclose the Personal Information for the purposes of evaluating my suitability for employment with the Company;

(3) I also authorize Certn to (i) contact the relevant law enforcement agencies, data repositories, as well as all other accessible private and public sector archives (including any other person, organization, or agency) and (ii) receive copies of verified results on me through any reasonable means including in writing, electronic transmission or over the phone;

(4) I understand and agree that, where my personal history requires background verifications to be carried out in countries where I have worked, studied, or resided, my Personal Information may be sent and verified in those relevant countries.

(5) I understand that I have the right to be informed about the nature and scope of data processing, file a complaint, ask for correction, deletion, or a copy of the information Certn holds about me by contacting Certn’s Privacy Officer at +44 (0)1732 748 900 and dpo@credence.co.uk for UK-based applicants or +1-844-987-0690 and privacy@certn.co for any generic queries and non-UK application queries.

(6) I acknowledge that I have read and understood Certn’s Privacy Policy and hereby confirm that my electronic consent is fully informed and freely given and I am aware that I can withdraw it at any time.

DBS Consent - HR - French
-------------------------

### Version 2.0

##### Effective September 14th 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

Please review all statements below to allow us to apply for your criminal record check from the DBS:

1. I have read the basic [DBS Check Processing Privacy Policy](https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/basic-dbs-check-privacy-policy) for Applicants and I understand how the DBS will process my personal data.
2. I have provided complete and true information in support of the application and I understand that knowingly making a false statement for this purpose is a criminal offence.
3. I consent to Certn, submitting an application to DBS on my behalf for a basic DBS certificate.
4. I also consent to Certn receiving and viewing my basic disclosure certificate prior to me seeing it, and to the DBS providing an electronic result directly to the Responsible Organisation (i.e Certn) that submits my application. I understand that an electronic result contains a message that indicates either the certificate does not contain criminal record information or to await certificate which will indicate that my certificate contains criminal record information. In some cases the Responsible Organisation may provide this information directly to my employer prior to me receiving my certificate. I understand that if I do not consent to Certn receiving an electronic result, I must not proceed with this application and I should apply directly to the DBS.

To withdraw your consent whilst the application is in progress you can contact the DBS helpline 03000 200 190. You can also contact Certn [uk-support@certn.co](mailto:uk-support@certn.co). If your certificate has not yet been issued, your application will then be withdrawn.

Seneca College Non-Crim Consent
-------------------------------

### Version 1.0

##### Effective December 21st 2023

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**Consent to perform the requested backgroud check services**

I understand and acknowledge that I am agreeing to this consent electronically and by doing so, to the extent permitted by applicable law:

(1) I hereby authorize Certn (and its designated representatives, as applicable) to collect, use, disclose and independently verify my Personal Information which may include, but is not limited to, my name, address, email address, date of birth, employment history, earnings history, and professional credentials (collectively, "Personal Information") for the purposes of delivering a background screening report in relation to my application for employment with Seneca.

(2) I acknowledge and agree that Seneca may collect, use and disclose the Personal Information for the purposes of evaluating my suitability for employment with Seneca;

(3) I understand and agree that, where my personal history requires background verifications to be carried out in countries where I have worked, studied, or resided, my Personal Information may be sent and verified in those relevant countries.

(4) I agree that an electronic copy of this consent is equally effective as an original signature for the purposes of validity, enforceability, and admissibility and authorize Certn to export this Consent in a PDF document and present it to third parties (e.g., former employer) which may request a proof of my consent for the purposes set out above;

(5) I acknowledge that I have read and understood Certn’s Privacy Policy and hereby confirm that my consent is fully informed and freely given and I am aware that I can withdraw it at any time; and

(6) I acknowledge that declining consent for Certn's and/or Seneca's collection, use, and disclosure of information may result in voluntarily withdrawal of my job application.

If you have any questions about the collection, use, disclosure, or storage of your Personal Information or if you would like to request more information about Certn's privacy policies and procedures, please contact Certn’s Privacy Officer at 1-844-987-0690 or privacy@certn.co.

Consentement (collecte, traitement et rapport)
----------------------------------------------

### Version 4.2

##### Effective November 24th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**AUTORISATION**

Afin d'évaluer votre aptitude à participer à {{purpose}} , {{company\_name}} ("Société") a demandé à [Certn](https://certn.co/) de vérifier votre identité, de créer et de vous renvoyer un rapport de consommation (votre " Rapport") composé de : {{services\_list}} .

Nous collecterons les renseignements personnels suivants dans le but de fournir les services: {{personal\_information\_list}} . {{#if data\_providers\_list}}Nous pouvons collecter des renseignements personnels directement auprès de vous, de la Société ou de tiers tels que {{data\_providers\_list}} {{else}} Nous pouvons collecter des renseignements personnels directement auprès de vous ou de la Société{{/if}}. Nous comparerons les informations reçues de différentes sources pour en assurer la cohérence.

Il peut être nécessaire pour Certn de transférer et de traiter des renseignements personnels dans plusieurs juridictions, en particulier si vous avez vécu, travaillé ou fréquenté une école en dehors de la juridiction dans laquelle l'entreprise a commandé le rapport. En outre, vos renseignements personnels peuvent être traités par nos employés et sous-traitants au Canada, en Australie, aux États-Unis, au Royaume-Uni, en Afrique du Sud et aux Philippines. Quel que soit l'endroit où les informations personnelles sont traitées, elles le seront conformément à nos politiques de confidentialité et de sécurité.

Vous pouvez retirer votre consentement, contester l'exactitude d'un rapport ou demander une correction, une suppression ou une copie de votre rapport à tout moment en contactant le Responsable de la protection de la vie privée de Certn au 1-844-987-0690 ou à [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co). De plus amples informations concernant la collecte, l'utilisation, la divulgation ou le stockage de vos renseignements personnels sont disponibles [ici](https://vault.pactsafe.io/s/5d800911-f26c-4e3a-884d-85117a81799b/legal.html?g=37964#contract-bylz4uhm3).

SGP Biometric Consent (B2B) -EN
-------------------------------

### Version 4.1

##### Effective March 8th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

We need your consent to collect and process your biometric data for the purpose of verifying your identity on behalf of {{{company\_name}}}. Biometric data in this instance includes facial features from a real-time photo and information from your government-issued ID. We will store your biometric data securely and implement appropriate measures to safeguard such information against unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction.

By clicking “Yes, I agree” below, you confirm that you have read and understood this Biometric Consent, as well as our [Biometric Notice](https://vault.pactsafe.io/s/5d800911-f26c-4e3a-884d-85117a81799b/legal.html?g=37964#contract-s1qa70-t6), and you agree to the collection and processing of your biometric data in accordance with these terms and our Privacy Policy ([https://certn.co/privacy-policy/](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/) ). Further, you acknowledge and agree to the transfer of your biometric data to {{{company\_name}}} in connection with your background check and verification and any applicable third-party sub-processors, solely for the purpose of completing your identity verification. This consent is given voluntarily and with the understanding that the data will be used exclusively for identity verification. Your biometric data will be retained for the duration necessary to fulfill the intended purpose, and it will be securely deleted thereafter. If you choose not to consent, we may not be able to process your application or provide verification results for your background check.

You can revoke your consent at any time by notifying us in writing at [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co). Upon revocation, we will notify {{{company\_name}}} and cease the collection, use, and retention of your biometric data. You have the right to request access to your biometric data and to request corrections or deletions of inaccuracies. If you require more information about the nature and scope of your data processing or for a copy of the information we hold about you, please contact Certn’s Privacy Officer at 1-844-987-0690 or [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co).

If you reside in a location that is different from our processing locations or the location of {{{company\_name}}}, we may transfer your Personal Information for the purpose of completing the identity verification, in accordance with our Privacy Policy ([https://certn.co/privacy-policy/](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/)) and applicable privacy laws.

Biometric Notice
----------------

### Version 1.3

##### Effective September 11th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

Biometric Notice  

Please review the below information before providing your consent for Certn to process your Biometric Data.

“**Biometric Data**” is personal information resulting from specific technical processing relating to the physical, physiological or behavioral characteristics which allow or confirm the unique identification of that natural person.

**Why do you need my biometric data?**

As part of the remote background screening services we provide to our clients, we collect your Biometric Data to (i) remotely verify your identity, and (ii) prevent and combat fraud.

**How does it work?**

We will ask you to scan a copy of your government-issued ID, and take a selfie using your mobile device or laptop. We use an AI algorithm to measure certain features of your face in both your ID photo and your selfie, and compare them to one another to confirm the person completing background screening matches the person on the ID. This helps us combat fraud, and ensures we are providing accurate information to our clients.

**Who will have access to my Biometric Data?**

Except where required by law, your Biometric Data is accessible only to us and our service providers who require access to Biometric Data to help us provide our Services. We do not share Biometric Data with any other third parties. That said, we will provide certain information about you to the client on whose behalf we are performing the background check, which could include copies of the ID document and photo you provided us, and confirmation that we were or were not able to verify your identity.

Certn does not sell, lease, trade or otherwise profit from your Biometric Data.

**How will you protect my Biometric Data?**

The Company uses industry standard security safeguards to store and protect your Biometric Data, in accordance with our [Privacy Policy](https://vault.pactsafe.io/s/5d800911-f26c-4e3a-884d-85117a81799b/legal.html?g=37964#contract-byeg-ihlj). Unless required by law, once your identity has been verified, we will delete your biometric data from our systems within 30 days.

The location of Biometric Data storage is based on the location of our client. For example, if our client on whose behalf we are performing a background check is located in Canada, your Biometric Data will be stored in Canada. If you reside in a different country from our processing locations or the location of our client, we may transfer your Biometric Data for the purpose of completing the identity verification, in accordance with our Privacy Policy ([https://certn.co/privacy-policy/](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/)) and applicable privacy laws.

**What are my rights?**

You may choose not to consent to the processing of your Biometric Data. If you choose not to consent to biometric identity verification, we may not be able to process your application or provide verification results to our client.

You can also:

* revoke your consent to the processing of your Biometric Data,
* request a copy of your Biometric Data,
* request corrections to your Biometric Data, and
* request deletion of your Biometric Data,

at any time by contacting us at [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co). Upon receiving notice, we will notify our client on whose behalf we are performing the background check, and promptly respond to your request.

If you require more information about the nature and scope of your data processing, please contact Certn’s Privacy Officer at [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co).

SGP Biometric Consent (B2B) - FR
--------------------------------

### Version 7.0

##### Effective April 1st 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

Nous avons besoin de votre consentement pour collecter et traiter vos données biométriques pour vérifier votre identité au demandeur {{{company\_name}}}. Les données biométriques dans ce cas comprennent les traits du visage à partir d'une photo en temps réel et les informations de votre carte d'identité délivrée par le gouvernement. Nous conserverons vos données biométriques en toute sécurité et mettons en œuvre des mesures appropriées pour protéger ces informations contre tout accès, divulgation, modification et destruction non autorisés.  

En cliquant sur "Oui, j'accepte" ci-dessous, vous confirmez que vous avez lu et compris le présent consentement biométrique, ainsi que notre [Avis Biométrique](https://vault.pactsafe.io/s/5d800911-f26c-4e3a-884d-85117a81799b/legal.html?g=37964#contract-sjl9lwojr), et vous acceptez la collecte et le traitement de vos données biométriques conformément à ces conditions et à notre politique de protection de la vie privée ([https://certn.co/privacy-policy/](https://vault.pactsafe.io/s/5d800911-f26c-4e3a-884d-85117a81799b/legal.html?g=37964#contract-bylz4uhm3)). En outre, vous reconnaissez et acceptez le transfert de vos données biométriques à {{{company\_name}}} la vérification de vos antécédents et de tout sous-traitant applicable, dans le seul but de mener à bien la vérification de votre identité. Ce consentement est donné volontairement et en sachant que les données seront utilisées exclusivement pour la vérification de l'identité. Vos données biométriques seront conservées pendant la durée nécessaire à la réalisation de l'objectif visé et seront ensuite supprimées en toute sécurité. Si vous choisissez de ne pas donner votre consentement, il se peut que nous ne soyons pas en mesure de traiter votre candidature ou de vous fournir les résultats de la vérification de vos antécédents.

Vous pouvez révoquer votre consentement à tout moment en nous le notifiant par courriel à l'adresse suivante [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co). En cas de révocation, nous notifierons {{{company\_name}}} et cesserons la collecte, l'utilisation et la conservation de vos données biométriques. Vous avez le droit de demander l'accès à vos données biométriques et de demander la correction ou la suppression des inexactitudes. Si vous souhaitez obtenir plus d'informations sur la nature et la portée du traitement de vos données ou une copie des informations que nous détenons à votre sujet, veuillez contacter le responsable de la protection de la vie privée du Certn au 1-844-987-0690 ou à l'adresse suivante [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co) .

Si vous résidez dans un lieu différent de nos sites de traitement ou de l'emplacement de {{{company\_name}}}, nous pouvons transférer vos informations personnelles afin de procéder à la vérification d'identité, conformément à notre politique de confidentialité ([https://certn.co/privacy-policy/](https://vault.pactsafe.io/s/5d800911-f26c-4e3a-884d-85117a81799b/legal.html?g=37964#contract-bylz4uhm3)) et aux lois applicables en matière de protection de la vie privée.

Summary of California Consumer Rights
-------------------------------------

### Version 2.0

##### Effective March 12th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**SUMMARY OF CALIFORNIA CONSUMER RIGHTS**

The following information may be obtained from Certn at 1006 Fort Street, Unit 300, Victoria, BC, Canada V8V 3K4. Our office hours are 9:00am to 5:00pm PT. Our telephone number is 844-987-0690. For complete information about Certn’s privacy practices, including whether your personal information will be sent outside of the U.S. or its territories, Certn’s privacy policy can be viewed at [https://certn.co/privacy-policy/](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/)

You have rights when an investigative consumer report is obtained on you. The following are some of your rights:

1\. You have the right to contact the agency that made the report. You can do this in one of the following ways:

(a) You can go to the agency in person during the normal business hours and on reasonable notice. You can bring someone with you. You and that person may be required to present identification. You may be required to sign a paper allowing the agency to discuss your file with or to show your file to this person.

(b) You may receive your file by certified mail, if you have given written notice to the agency that you want information mailed to you or to another person you want to receive the file. You will be required to provide identification when you write for your file.

(c) You may be able to discuss your file over the telephone if you have given written instructions to the agency and have provided identification.

2\. You have the right to receive a copy of your file or your investigative consumer report at the agency. You may be charged up to $8.00 to obtain a copy of your report or file. However, you may receive a free copy if:

(a) Once during a twelve month period if you are unemployed and intend to seek employment within sixty (60) days or you receive public welfare assistance or you believe your file contains inaccurate information because of fraud.

(b) If you are receiving a copy from the agency relating to an investigation into the accuracy of information you have disputed or if information is put back into your file.

3\. You have the right to know the following information:

(a) The names of the persons and companies who have received a report about you in the last three (3) years. You may request their addresses and telephone numbers.

(b) Explanations of any codes or abbreviations used in your report, so you can understand the report.

4\. You have the right to dispute any information in your file. You must contact the agency directly to do so. The person who ordered a report is required to give you the name and address of the agency.

(a) The agency has thirty (30) days from the day it receives your dispute to complete the investigation.

(b) When the agency is done with the investigation, it must tell you of any changes made in the report as a result of the investigation.

(c) If the investigation does not remove the information disputed by you, you have the right to place your statement of the facts in your file. The agency has people to help you write the statement. The agency may limit your statement to five hundred (500) words.

(d) If information is removed or you add a statement to your file, you can request the agency to send the report, as changed or with your statement, to anyone who received the information in the last two (2) years.

(e) If information that is removed from your files is placed back in your file, you are entitled to receive written notice of that fact and you have the right to dispute the information added.

5\. You also have rights under federal law in regard to your report. A copy of those rights is given to you with this California statement of consumer rights. Many of these rights are also included within California law.

**DERECHOS DEL CONSUMIDOR EN CALIFORNIA**

Usted tiene derechos cuando un reporte de investigación del consumidor es obtenido respecto a usted. Los siguientes son algunos de sus derechos:

1\. Usted tiene derecho de contactar la agencia que hizo el reporte y puede hacer èsto de las maneras siguientes:

(a) Puede ir a la agencia en persona durante horas normales de trabajo y en la nota razonable. Puede traer a un acompañante. Usted y esa persona debe traer una identificación. Es posible que tenga que firmar un documento en el que usted dará derecho a la agencia de discutir lo que está en su archivo o de mostrar el archivo a la persona que lo acompaña.

(b) Usted puede recibir su archivo por correspondencia certificada si es que avisó a la agencia por escrito que desea información por carta o desea que otra persona reciba su archivo. Por lo tanto, usted deberá proveer una identificación cuando solicite la información.

(c) Usted podrá platicar respecto a su archivo por telèfono si es que dió instrucciones por escrito a la agencia y presentó una identificación.

2\. Usted tiene derecho de recibir una copia de su archivo o de su reporte de investigación del consumidor en la agencia y se le puede cobrar hasta 8.00 dólares para obtener una copia de su reporte o archivo. De cualquier manera, usted podrá recibir una copia gratis en las siguientes circunstancias:

(a) Si es que durante doce meses usted está desempleado o tiene intenciones de buscar empleo durante 60 días o si usted recibe asistencia pública o cree que su archivo contiene información incorrecta debido a fraude.

(b) Si usted recibe una copia de la agencia relacionada con la nvestigación para verificar la exactitud de la información que usted reportó o si es que la información fuè regresada a su archivo.

3\. Usted tiene derecho de saber la siguiente información:

(a) Los nombres de personas y de compañías quienes han recibido un reporte respecto a usted en los últimos 3 años y puede solicitar sus domicilios y números de telèfono.

(b) Usted puede solicitar que se le explique códigos o abreviasiones utilizadas en su reporte para que usted lo pueda comprender con más claridad.

4\. Usted tiene derecho de reclamar cualquier información que estè en su archivo pero deberá contactar a la agencia directamente. La persona que ordenó el reporte deberá darle a usted el nombre y domicilio de la agencia.

(a) La agencia tiene 30 días para completar la investigación.

(b) Una vez terminada la investigación, la agencia debe informarle a usted de cualquier cambio que se haya hecho al reporte como resultado de la investigación.

(c) Si es que la investigación no elimina información reportada por usted, entonces tiene derecho de agregar su declaración en el archivo. La agencia tiene personal que le puede ayudar a escribir su declaración siempre y cuando no exceda quinientas (500) palabras.

(d) Si usted elimina o agrega información a su archivo puede pedirle a la agencia que mande el reporte como “Cambiado” o con su declaración a cualquierea que haya recibido la información en los últimos dos años.

(e) Si hay información que fuè eliminada de su archivo y despuès vuelta a poner, usted tiene derecho a recibir por escrito lo sucedido y tiene derecho a reclamar la información agregada.

5\. Tambièn tiene derechos bajo la ley federal respecto a su reporte. Se le dará una copia de esos derechos con èsta declaración de derechos del consumidor de California.

You also have rights under federal law in regard to your report. [A copy of those rights](https://files.consumerfinance.gov/f/documents/bcfp_consumer-rights-summary_2018-09.pdf) is given to you with this California statement of consumer rights. Many of these rights are also included within California law.

California Disclosure Form - SGP
--------------------------------

### Version 1.0

##### Effective March 12th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**NOTICE REGARDING BACKGROUND INVESTIGATION**

**PURSUANT TO CALIFORNIA LAW**

**{{{company\_name}}}** has requested an "investigative consumer report" on you for the purpose of evaluating your current or potential employment through [Certn](https://certn.co/) (an investigative consumer reporting agency or “ **ICRA**”). In California, an "**investigative consumer report** " is a background screening report that may contain information regarding your domestic and international background history, including but not limited to, your social security number and identification documents, criminal history, sex offender registry status, credit history, employment history, education history, driving history, professional licenses, drug testing results and other information about you. It may bear upon your character, general reputation, personal characteristics, and/or mode of living. These reports may be used as a factor in making employment decisions. The source of any investigative consumer report (as that term is defined under California law) will be Certn (USA) Inc., 3820 Central Avenue #220, Cheyenne, WY 82001, 844-987-0690. Information regarding Certn's privacy practices (including information about whether any consumer personal information will be sent outside the U.S. or its territories) may be found [here](https://certn.co/) .

Under California Civil Code section 1786.22, you are entitled to review your file which can be obtained from the ICRA as follows:

* In person, by visual inspection of your file during normal business hours and upon reasonable notice. You also may request a copy of the information in person. The ICRA may not charge you more than the actual copying costs for providing you with a copy of your file.
* By requesting a copy be sent to a specified addressee by certified mail. ICRAs complying with requests for certified mailings shall not be liable for disclosures to third parties caused by mishandling of mail after such mailings leave the ICRAs.
* A summary of all information contained in the ICRA's file on you via telephone, if you have made a written request for telephone disclosure and the toll charge, if any, for the telephone call is prepaid by or charged directly to you.

If you cannot identify yourself with Proper Identification, the ICRA may require additional information concerning your employment and personal or family history in order to verify your identity. "**Proper Identification** " includes documents such as a valid driver's license, social security account number, military identification card, and credit cards.The ICRA will provide trained personnel to explain any information furnished to you and will provide a written explanation of any coded information contained in files maintained on you. This written explanation will be provided whenever a file is provided to you for visual inspection.  
  
You may be accompanied by one other person of your choosing, who must furnish reasonable identification. An ICRA may require you to furnish a written statement granting permission to the ICRA to discuss your file in such person's presence.  

Colorado Disclosure
-------------------

### Version 1.0

##### Effective March 13th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**State Consumers Have the Right to Obtain a Security Freeze**

You may obtain a security freeze on your consumer report to protect your privacy and ensure that credit is not granted in your name without your knowledge, except as provided by law. You have a right to place a security freeze on your consumer report to prohibit a consumer reporting agency from releasing any information in your consumer report without your express authorization or approval, except as the law allows.

You will not be initially charged to place a security freeze on your consumer report. However, you will be charged a fee of no more than ten dollars to temporarily lift the freeze for a period of time, to permanently remove the freeze from your consumer report, or when you make a subsequent request for a freeze to be placed on your consumer report. As well, you may be charged a fee of no more than twelve dollars to temporarily lift the freeze for a specific party.

The security freeze is designed to prevent credit, loans, and services from being approved in your name without your consent. When you place a security freeze on your consumer report, within five business days you will be provided procedures for the temporary release of your consumer report to a specific party or parties or for a period of time after the security freeze is in place. To provide that authorization, you must contact the consumer reporting agency and provide the proper information regarding the third party or parties who are to receive the consumer report or the period of time for which the report shall be available to users of the consumer report.

A consumer reporting agency that receives a request from a consumer to temporarily lift a security freeze on a consumer report shall comply with the request no later than three business days after receiving the request.

A security freeze does not apply to circumstances where you have an existing account relationship, and a copy of your report is requested by your existing creditor or its agents or affiliates for certain types of account review, collection, fraud control, or similar activities.

You should be aware that using a security freeze to take control over who gains access to the personal and financial information in your consumer report may delay, interfere with, or prohibit the timely approval of any subsequent request or application you make regarding new loans, credit, mortgage, insurance, government services or payments, rental housing, employment, investment, license, cellular phone, utilities, digital signature, internet credit card transaction, or other services, including an extension of credit at the point of sale. You should plan ahead and lift a security freeze either completely if you are shopping around, or specifically for a certain creditor a few days before actually applying for new credit.

You have the right to bring a civil action or submit to binding arbitration against a consumer reporting agency to enforce an obligation under the security freeze law after following specified dispute procedures and having received the necessary notice.

Oklahoma Free Copy Disclosure Notice
------------------------------------

### Version 1.0

##### Effective March 13th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

I have the right under Oklahoma law to request a free copy of your consumer report.

New York Article 23-A
---------------------

### Version 2.0

##### Effective March 13th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

ARTICLE 23-A

LICENSURE AND EMPLOYMENT OF PERSONS PREVIOUSLY CONVICTED OF ONE OR MORE CRIMINAL OFFENSES

750\. Definitions.

751\. Applicability.

752\. Unfair discrimination against persons previously convicted of one or more criminal offenses prohibited.

753\. Factors to be considered concerning a previous criminal conviction; presumption. 754. Written statement upon denial of license or employment.

755\. Enforcement.

§ 750. **Definitions.** For the purposes of this article, the following terms shall have the following meanings:

(1) "Public agency" means the state or any local subdivision thereof, or any state or local department, agency, board or commission.

(2) "Private employer" means any person, company, corporation, labor organization or association which employs ten or more persons.

(3) "Direct relationship" means that the nature of criminal conduct for which the person was convicted has a direct bearing on his fitness or ability to perform one or more of the duties or responsibilities necessarily related to the license, opportunity, or job in question.

(4) "License" means any certificate, license, permit or grant of permission required by the laws of this state, its political subdivisions or instrumentalities as a condition for the lawful practice of any occupation, employment, trade, vocation, business, or profession. Provided, however, that "license" shall not, for the purposes of this article, include any license or permit to own, possess, carry, or fire any explosive, pistol, handgun, rifle, shotgun, or other firearm.

(5) "Employment" means any occupation, vocation or employment, or any form of vocational or educational training. Provided, however, that "employment" shall not, for the purposes of this article, include membership in any law enforcement agency.

§ 751. **Applicability.** The provisions of this article shall apply to any application by any person for a license or employment at any public or private employer, who has previously been convicted of one or more criminal offenses in this state or in any other jurisdiction, and to any license or employment held by any person whose conviction of one or more criminal offenses in this state or in any other jurisdiction preceded such employment or granting of a license, except

where a mandatory forfeiture, disability or bar to employment is imposed by law, and has not been removed by an executive pardon, certificate of relief from disabilities or certificate of good conduct. Nothing in this article shall be construed to affect any right an employer may have with respect to an intentional misrepresentation in connection with an application for employment made by a prospective employee or previously made by a current employee.

§ 752. **Unfair discrimination against persons previously convicted of one or more criminal offenses prohibited.** No application for any license or employment, and no employment or license held by an individual, to which the provisions of this article are applicable, shall be denied or acted upon adversely by reason of the individual's having been previously convicted of one or more criminal offenses, or by reason of a finding of lack of "good moral character" when such finding is based upon the fact that the individual has previously been convicted of one or more criminal offenses, unless:

(1) there is a direct relationship between one or more of the previous criminal offenses and the specific license or employment sought or held by the individual; or

(2) the issuance or continuation of the license or the granting or continuation of the employment would involve an unreasonable risk to property or to the safety or welfare of specific individuals or the general public.

§ 753. Factors to be considered concerning a previous criminal conviction; presumption. 1. In making a determination pursuant to section seven hundred fifty-two of this chapter, the public agency or private employer shall consider the following factors:

(a) The public policy of this state, as expressed in this act, to encourage the licensure and employment of persons previously convicted of one or more criminal offenses.

(b) The specific duties and responsibilities necessarily related to the license or employment sought or held by the person.

(c) The bearing, if any, the criminal offense or offenses for which the person was previously convicted will have on his fitness or ability to perform one or more such duties or responsibilities.

(d) The time which has elapsed since the occurrence of the criminal offense or offenses. (e) The age of the person at the time of occurrence of the criminal offense or offenses. (f) The seriousness of the offense or offenses.

(g) Any information produced by the person, or produced on his behalf, in regard to his rehabilitation and good conduct.

(h) The legitimate interest of the public agency or private employer in protecting property, and the safety and welfare of specific individuals or the general public.

2\. In making a determination pursuant to section seven hundred fifty-two of this chapter, the public agency or private employer shall also give consideration to a certificate of relief from disabilities or a certificate of good conduct issued to the applicant, which certificate shall create a presumption of rehabilitation in regard to the offense or offenses specified therein.

§ 754. **Written statement upon denial of license or employment.** At the request of any person previously convicted of one or more criminal offenses who has been denied a license or employment, a public agency or private employer shall provide, within thirty days of a request, a written statement setting forth the reasons for such denial.

§ 755. **Enforcement.** 1\. In relation to actions by public agencies, the provisions of this article shall be enforceable by a proceeding brought pursuant to article seventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules.

2\. In relation to actions by private employers, the provisions of this article shall be enforceable by the division of human rights pursuant to the powers and procedures set forth in article fifteen of the executive law, and, concurrently, by the New York city commission on human rights.

Avis biométrique - FR
---------------------

### Version 1.2

##### Effective September 11th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

Avis biométrique

Veuillez prendre connaissance des informations ci-dessous avant de donner votre accord au Certn pour le traitement de vos données biométriques.

Les “données biométriques” sont des informations personnelles résultant d'un traitement technique spécifique relatif aux caractéristiques physiques, physiologiques ou comportementales qui permettent ou confirment l'identification unique de cette personne physique.

**Pourquoi avez-vous besoin de mes données biométriques ?**

Dans le cadre des services de vérification à distance des antécédents que nous fournissons à nos clients, nous collectons vos données biométriques pour (i) vérifier à distance votre identité, et (ii) prévenir et combattre la fraude.

**Comment cela fonctionne-t-il ?**

Nous vous demanderons de scanner une copie de votre pièce d'identité délivrée par le gouvernement et de prendre un selfie à l'aide de votre appareil mobile ou de votre ordinateur portable. Nous utilisons un algorithme d'intelligence artificielle pour mesurer certaines caractéristiques de votre visage sur la photo de votre pièce d'identité et sur votre selfie, et les comparer l'une à l'autre pour confirmer que la personne qui effectue la vérification des antécédents correspond à celle qui figure sur la pièce d'identité. Cela nous aide à lutter contre la fraude et à garantir que nous fournissons des informations exactes à nos clients.

**Qui aura accès à mes données biométriques ?**

Sauf si la loi l'exige, vos données biométriques ne sont accessibles qu'à nous et à nos fournisseurs de services qui ont besoin d'accéder aux données biométriques pour nous aider à fournir nos services. Nous ne partageons pas les données biométriques avec d'autres tiers. Cela dit, nous fournirons certaines informations vous concernant au client pour le compte duquel nous effectuons la vérification des antécédents, notamment des copies du document d'identité et de la photo que vous nous avez fournis, ainsi que la confirmation que nous avons été en mesure ou non de vérifier votre identité.

Le Certn ne vend pas, ne loue pas, n'échange pas et ne tire aucun profit de vos données biométriques.

**Comment protégez-vous mes données biométriques ?**

La société utilise des mesures de sécurité standard pour stocker et protéger vos données biométriques, conformément à notre politique de confidentialité. Sauf obligation légale, une fois votre identité vérifiée, nous supprimerons vos données biométriques de nos systèmes dans un délai de 30 jours.

Le lieu de stockage des données biométriques dépend de la localisation de notre client. Par exemple, si le client pour le compte duquel nous effectuons une vérification des antécédents est situé au Canada, vos données biométriques seront stockées au Canada. Si vous résidez dans un pays différent de nos sites de traitement ou de l'emplacement de notre client, nous pouvons transférer vos données biométriques dans le but de compléter la vérification d'identité, conformément à notre politique de confidentialité (https://certn.co/privacy-policy/) et aux lois applicables en matière de protection de la vie privée.

**Quels sont mes droits ?**

Vous pouvez choisir de ne pas consentir au traitement de vos données biométriques. Si vous choisissez de ne pas consentir à la vérification biométrique de l'identité, il se peut que nous ne soyons pas en mesure de traiter votre demande ou de fournir les résultats de la vérification à notre client.

Vous pouvez également

* révoquer votre consentement au traitement de vos données biométriques,
* demander une copie de vos données biométriques,
* demander des corrections à vos données biométriques, et
* demander la suppression de vos données biométriques,

à tout moment en nous contactant à l'adresse [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co). Dès réception de la notification, nous informerons notre client au nom duquel nous effectuons la vérification des antécédents, et nous répondrons rapidement à votre demande.

Si vous souhaitez obtenir de plus amples informations sur la nature et la portée du traitement de vos données, veuillez contacter le responsable de la protection de la vie privée du Certn à l'adresse suivante : [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co).  

Roomies Custom Criminal Consent
-------------------------------

### Version 1.0

##### Effective April 5th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

I hereby consent to a search of all currently available criminal records and information, including non-conviction information, charges before the court, findings of guilt or convictions and court orders or records registered in my name in the National Repository of Criminal Records, the Canadian Police Information Centre (“**CPIC**”) database, the Police Information Portal (“**PIP**”) and any other data sharing platform available to the police service provider for the purposes of delivering a criminal record check in relation to my application with the landlord or property manager, as applicable (the “**Landlord**”).  

I understand that this criminal record check is based on the name(s), date of birth and, where used, the declared criminal record history I provide. I understand that the results are not being confirmed by fingerprint comparison which is the only true means by which to confirm if a criminal record exists in the National Repository of Criminal Records.

I certify that the information set out by me in this application is true and correct to the best of my ability. I consent to the release of the results of the criminal record check to Certn and the Landlord. I acknowledge and agree that the Landlord may collect, use and disclose the information collected for the purposes of evaluating my application.

I hereby release and forever discharge all members and employees of the processing police service and the Royal Canadian Mounted Police from any and all actions, claims and demands for damages, loss or injury whatsoever arising which may hereinafter be sustained by me as a result of the disclosure of information to Certn and the Landlord.

By clicking “**I understand and agree**” I consent to Certn collecting, processing and disclosing my personal information pursuant to the terms set out above and Certn’s [Privacy Policy](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/).

_You can request more information about the nature and scope of your criminal record check by contacting Certn’s Privacy Officer at 1-844-987-0690 or [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co)_.

FCRA Authorization (Supernal,LLC)
---------------------------------

### Version 1.0

##### Effective May 22nd 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**AUTHORIZATION REGARDING BACKGROUND INVESTIGATION**

By signing below, I acknowledge receipt of the following separate documents (and certify that I have read and understood them):

* DISCLOSURE REGARDING BACKGROUND INVESTIGATION ON YOU;
* A SUMMARY OF YOUR RIGHTS UNDER THE FAIR CREDIT REPORTING ACT;
* ADDITIONAL NOTICE REGARDING INVESTIGATIVE CONSUMER REPORTS ON YOU;
* ADDITIONAL STATE LAW NOTICES.(In California, this notice is entitled “Notice Regarding Background Investigation Pursuant To California Law.”)  

By signing below, I also authorize law enforcement agencies, learning institutions (including public and private schools, colleges and universities), information service bureaus, credit bureaus, data repositories, courts (federal, state and local), motor vehicle records agencies, my past or present employers, the military, and other public or private individuals and institutions to furnish any and all information on me that is requested by Certn, the consumer reporting agency preparing reports about me for Supernal, LLC. The information that can be disclosed to Certn includes, but is not limited to, criminal history, national sex offender registry status, employment history, education history, a social security number check, a Global Sanctions and Terrorist Watchlist check, and other information about me as allowed by law.

By signing below, I also authorize **Supernal, LLC** to obtain "**consumer reports**" and "**investigative consumer reports**" about me for employment purposes in connection with my conditional offer of employment.

Name: {{{first\_name}}} {{{last\_name}}}

Date: {{{date}}}

\[END OF DOCUMENT\]

Canadian Criminal Record Consent Form NEW\*
-------------------------------------------

### Version 21.0

##### Effective August 16th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

CANADIAN CRIMINAL RECORD CHECK CONSENT

Personal Information on this form is collected under the authority of the Federal Privacy Act and any applicable Provincial privacy acts

|     |
| --- |
| ID Type: {{id\_type}} |
| Your Criminal Record Check will review all available law enforcement systems, including any local police records. This check will NOT include overseas or US records, traffic tickets, Motor Vehicle Act offences or municipal bylaw offences. The results of this check will not be forwarded to any third party without your prior written consent, subject to applicable privacy and data protection laws. |

|     |
| --- |
| {{#if (matchesValues check\_type 'BASIC\_CANADIAN\_CRIMINAL\_RECORD\_REPORT')}} |
| Criminal Record Check |
| The search will include: criminal convictions from CPIC and/or local databases; summary convictions (previous 5 years) when identified; and findings of guilt under the Youth Criminal Justice Act (YCJA) within the applicable disclosure period. Records for applicants under the age of 18 will only be provided to agencies that fall within Sec 119 (1)(o) of the YCJA. (e.g. Federal, Provincial and Municipal agencies)\*\* |
| {{/if}} |
| {{#if (matchesValues check\_type 'ENHANCED\_CANADIAN\_CRIMINAL\_RECORD\_REPORT')}} |
| Criminal Record and Judicial Matters Check (Enhanced) |
| The search will include: criminal convictions from CPIC and/or local databases; summary convictions (previous 5 years) when identified; outstanding entries such as charges, warrants, judicial orders, probation and prohibition orders; findings of guilt under the Youth Criminal Justice Act (YCJA) within the applicable disclosure period; and Absolute and Conditional Discharges (for 1 or 3 years respectively). Records for applicants under the age of 18 will only be provided to agencies that fall within Sec 119 (1)(o) of the YCJA. (e.g. Federal, Provincial and Municipal agencies)\*\* |
| {{/if}} |

|     |     |     |     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
| PERSONAL INFORMATION |     |     |     |     |     |
| LAST NAME: (applicant provided) | {{last\_name}} | FIRST NAME: (applicant provided) | {{first\_name}} | MIDDLE NAME(S): (applicant provided) | {{middle\_name}} |
| ALL PREVIOUS NAMES -LAST NAME, FIRST NAME: (including any name changes and birth/maiden name) |     |     | {{#each previous\_names}}{{this.last\_name}}, {{this.first\_name}}  <br>{{/each}} |     |     |
| GENDER: | {{gender}} | DATE OF BIRTH (applicant provided) | {{date\_of\_birth}} | PLACE OF BIRTH: | {{place\_of\_birth}} |
| CURRENT ADDRESS - STREET ADDRESS, CITY, PROV, POSTAL CODE, COUNTRY: |     |     | {{current\_address.street\_address}}, {{current\_address.locality}}, {{current\_address.administrative\_division\_1}}, {{current\_address.postal\_code}}, {{current\_address.country}} |     |     |
| E-MAIL ADDRESS: |     |     | {{email\_address}} |     |     |

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| PREVIOUS ADDRESSES: (LIST ALL ADDRESSES WITHIN THE LAST 5 YEARS - INCLUDING OUT OF COUNTRY) |     |
| {{#if previous\_addresses}} |
| {{#each previous\_addresses}} |
| STREET ADDRESS, CITY, PROV, POSTAL CODE, COUNTRY: | {{this.street\_address}}, {{this.locality}}, {{this.administrative\_division\_1}}, {{this.postal\_code}}, {{this.country}} |
| {{/each}} |
| {{/if}} |
| {{#unless previous\_addresses}} |
| STREET ADDRESS, CITY, PROV, POSTAL CODE, COUNTRY: |     |
| {{/unless}} |

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| DECLARATION OF A CRIMINAL RECORD (if applicable) |     |
| By declaring any offences of which you have been convicted, your criminal convictions record can be confirmed without needing to submit your fingerprints for verification of your identity and the processing delay that this causes.  <br>Please list below all offences of which a judge has convicted you (whether indictable or summary) and specifically identify the offence, date you were convicted, and place where the offence was committed.  <br>Do not disclose convictions for which you have received a pardon pursuant to the Criminal Records Act, or charges that were dismissed, stayed, or resulted in absolute or conditional discharges.  <br>Do not disclose offence convictions where you were found guilty of an offence committed while you were a "young person" (younger than eighteen years), pursuant to the Youth Criminal Justice Act. |     |
| List convictions or write N/A if nothing to declare and sign below |     |
| {{#if convictions}} |
| {{#each convictions}} |
| DATE OF CONVICTION, NATURE OF OFFENCE, JURISDICTION: | {{this.date}}, {{this.nature}}, {{this.jurisdiction}} |
| {{/each}} |
| {{/if}} |
| {{#unless convictions}} |
| DATE OF CONVICTION, NATURE OF OFFENCE, JURISDICTION: | N/A |
| {{/unless}} |

|     |     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| Signature: | {{first\_name}} {{last\_name}} | Date: | {{todays\_date}} |
| Name: | {{first\_name}} {{last\_name}} | Date of Birth (YYYY/MM/DD): | {{date\_of\_birth}} |

|     |     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| REASON FOR APPLICATION:  <br>Volunteer / Employment/ \*Other | {{reason\_for\_application}} | Requesting Organization Name: | {{requesting\_organization\_name}} |
| Key Contact Name: | {{key\_contact\_name}} | Requesting Organization Phone Number: | {{requesting\_organization\_phone\_number}} |
| \*Other - Details: |     | {{other\_details}} |     |

|     |
| --- |
| CONSENT TO SEARCH AND DISCLOSE AND LIABILITY RELEASE |     |
| I request and consent to the police partner, and its employees (the "Police Partner"), designated by Certn (Canada) Inc. ("Certn"), as a third party agency, to search any policing agency or court databases based on the information I have provided in order to locate any records and information in which I am referred to, and to confirm and report any criminal convictions (summary and indictable) and, if an enhanced check is ordered, any other relevant records including: absolute and conditional discharges; cases of not criminally responsible for reasons of mental disorder; and outstanding entries such as charges, judicial orders, probation and prohibition orders.  <br>I understand that information collected as a result of this Criminal Record Check will only be released to Certn and the third party organization referenced above, if any. If applicable, I understand that the organization referenced above, and not the Police Partner, will determine the impact of any reported search results. I understand that the accuracy of the reported information to be disclosed to me is not and cannot be guaranteed and may include errors or omissions.  <br>By my signature below, and for and in consideration of this Criminal Record Check being completed for me, the receipt and sufficiency of which I hereby acknowledge, I agree not to bring any legal actions, claims or demands, for losses or damages, including indirect or consequential, that I might sustain by reason of the Criminal Record Check being performed for me, against the respective municipality or Police Partner that completed the Criminal Record Check, its associated Police Board and any employees thereof, and to release them each from any and all liability and any actions, claims or demands, even if arising from their negligence or even gross negligence.  <br>I understand that I may be required to provide my fingerprints to confirm my identity before I can obtain results of my Criminal Record Check.  <br>I have read and understood this form, and in particular this section, and by signing below I am consenting to the above terms. By signing, I also certify that the information that I have provided is true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.  <br>I authorize the Police Partner to provide the results of the Criminal Record Check directly to Certn and the organization or Person requesting the Criminal Record Check referenced above. |     |

|     |     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| Signature: | {{first\_name}} {{last\_name}} | Date: | {{todays\_date}} |

Canadian Criminal Record Consent Form NEW\* (French)
----------------------------------------------------

### Version 3.0

##### Effective August 16th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

CONSENTEMENT À LA VÉRIFICATION DU CASIER JUDICIAIRE CANADIEN

Les informations personnelles figurant sur ce formulaire sont recueillies en vertu de la loi fédérale sur la protection de la vie privée et de toutes les lois provinciales applicables en la matière.

|     |
| --- |
| Type d'identification: {{id\_type}} |
| La vérification de votre casier judiciaire portera sur tous les systèmes d'application de la loi disponibles, y compris les dossiers de la police locale. Cette vérification n'inclura PAS les dossiers étrangers ou américains, les contraventions, les infractions à la loi sur les véhicules à moteur ou les infractions aux règlements municipaux. Les résultats de cette vérification ne seront pas transmis à un tiers sans votre consentement écrit préalable, sous réserve des lois applicables en matière de protection de la vie privée et des données. |

|     |
| --- |
| {{#if (matchesValues check\_type 'BASIC\_CANADIAN\_CRIMINAL\_RECORD\_REPORT')}} |
| Vérification du casier judiciaire |
| La recherche portera sur les condamnations pénales figurant dans le CIPC et/ou les bases de données locales, les condamnations sommaires (cinq dernières années), le cas échéant, et les déclarations de culpabilité en vertu de la Loi sur le système de justice pénale pour les adolescents (LSJPA) au cours de la période de divulgation applicable. Les dossiers des candidats âgés de moins de 18 ans ne seront communiqués qu'aux organismes visés par l'article 119 (1)(o) de la LSJPA. (p. ex. organismes fédéraux, provinciaux et municipaux)\*\*. |
| {{/if}} |
| {{#if (matchesValues check\_type 'ENHANCED\_CANADIAN\_CRIMINAL\_RECORD\_REPORT')}} |
| Vérification du casier judiciaire et des affaires judiciaires (renforcée) |
| La recherche portera sur les condamnations pénales figurant dans le CIPC et/ou les bases de données locales, les condamnations sommaires (5 dernières années) lorsqu'elles sont identifiées, les inscriptions en suspens telles que les accusations, les mandats, les ordonnances judiciaires, les ordonnances de probation et d'interdiction, les déclarations de culpabilité en vertu de la loi sur le système de justice pénale pour les adolescents (LSJPA) au cours de la période de divulgation applicable, et les libérations absolues et conditionnelles (pour 1 ou 3 ans, respectivement). Les dossiers des candidats âgés de moins de 18 ans ne seront communiqués qu'aux organismes visés à l'article 119, paragraphe 1, point o), de la loi sur le système de justice pénale pour les adolescents (LSJPA). (p. ex. agences fédérales, provinciales et municipales)\*\*. |
| {{/if}} |

|     |     |     |     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
| LES INFORMATIONS PERSONNELLES |     |     |     |     |     |
| NOM DE FAMILLE: (Fournie par le demandeur) | {{last\_name}} | PRÉNOM: (Fournie par le demandeur) | {{first\_name}} | DEUXIÈME(S) PRÉNOM(S): (Fournie par le demandeur) | {{middle\_name}} |
| TOUS LES NOMS ANTÉRIEURS - NOM DE FAMILLE, PRÉNOM: (y compris tout changements de nom et nom de naissance/de jeune fille) |     |     | {{#each previous\_names}}{{this.last\_name}}, {{this.first\_name}}  <br>{{/each}} |     |     |
| GENRE: | {{gender}} | DATE DE NAISSANCE (Fournie par le demandeur) | {{date\_of\_birth}} | LIEU DE NAISSANCE: | {{place\_of\_birth}} |
| ADRESSE ACTUELLE - RUE, VILLE, PROV, CODE POSTAL, PAYS: |     |     | {{current\_address.street\_address}}, {{current\_address.locality}}, {{current\_address.administrative\_division\_1}}, {{current\_address.postal\_code}}, {{current\_address.country}} |     |     |
| NUMÉRO DE TÉLÉPHONE: | {{phone\_number}} |     | ADRESSE ÉLECTRONIQUE: | {{email\_address}} |     |

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| ADRESSES PRÉCÉDENTES : (INDIQUER TOUTES LES ADRESSES AU COURS DES CINQ DERNIÈRES ANNÉES, Y COMPRIS À L'ÉTRANGER) |     |
| {{#if previous\_addresses}} |
| {{#each previous\_addresses}} |
| ADRESSE ACTUELLE - RUE, VILLE, PROV, CODE POSTAL, PAYS: | {{this.street\_address}}, {{this.locality}}, {{this.administrative\_division\_1}}, {{this.postal\_code}}, {{this.country}} |
| {{/each}} |
| {{/if}} |
| {{#unless previous\_addresses}} |
| ADRESSE ACTUELLE - RUE, VILLE, PROV, CODE POSTAL, PAYS: |     |
| {{/unless}} |

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| DÉCLARATION D'UN CASIER CRIMINEL (le cas échéant) |     |
| En déclarant les infractions pour lesquelles vous avez été condamné, votre casier judiciaire peut être confirmé sans qu'il soit nécessaire de soumettre vos empreintes digitales pour vérification de votre identité et le délai de traitement que cela entraîne.  <br>Veuillez énumérer ci-dessous toutes les infractions pour lesquelles un juge vous a condamné (qu'il s'agisse d'un acte criminel ou d'une procédure sommaire) en précisant l'infraction, la date à laquelle vous avez été condamné et le lieu où l'infraction a été commise.  <br>Ne divulguez pas les condamnations pour lesquelles vous avez été gracié en vertu de la loi sur le casier judiciaire, ni les accusations qui ont fait l'objet d'un non-lieu, d'un sursis ou d'une absolution inconditionnelle ou conditionnelle.  <br>Ne divulguez pas les condamnations pour infraction si vous avez été reconnu coupable d'une infraction commise alors que vous étiez un "jeune" (moins de dix-huit ans), conformément à la loi sur le système de justice pénale pour les mineurs (Youth Criminal Justice Act). |     |
| Indiquez les condamnations ou inscrivez "N/A" si vous n'avez rien à déclarer et signez ci-dessous. |     |
| {{#if convictions}} |
| {{#each convictions}} |
| DATE DE LA CONDAMNATION, NATURE DE L'INFRACTION, JURIDICTION: | {{this.date}}, {{this.nature}}, {{this.jurisdiction}} |
| {{/each}} |
| {{/if}} |
| {{#unless convictions}} |
| DATE DE LA CONDAMNATION, NATURE DE L'INFRACTION, JURIDICTION | N/A |
| {{/unless}} |

|     |     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| Signature: | {{first\_name}} {{last\_name}} | Date: | {{todays\_date}} |
| Nom: | {{first\_name}} {{last\_name}} | Date de naissance (AAAA/MM/JJ): | {{date\_of\_birth}} |

|     |     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| MOTIF DE LA DEMANDE:  <br>Bénévolat / Emploi / \*Autre | {{reason\_for\_application}} | Nom de l'organisation requérante: | {{requesting\_organization\_name}} |
| Nom du contact principal: | {{key\_contact\_name}} | Numéro de téléphone de l'organisation requérante: | {{requesting\_organization\_phone\_number}} |
| \*Autres - Détails: |     | {{other\_details}} |     |

|     |
| --- |
| CONSENTEMENT À LA RECHERCHE ET À LA DIVULGATION D'INFORMATIONS ET DÉCHARGE DE RESPONSABILITÉ |     |
| Je demande et je consens à ce que le partenaire policier et ses employés (le "partenaire policier"), désignés par le Certn (Canada) Inc. ("Certn"), en tant qu'agence tierce, à effectuer des recherches dans les bases de données des services de police ou des tribunaux sur la base des informations que j'ai fournies, afin de localiser les dossiers et les informations auxquels je fais référence, de confirmer et de signaler toute condamnation pénale (par procédure sommaire ou par acte d'accusation) et, si une vérification approfondie est ordonnée, tout autre dossier pertinent, y compris : les libérations absolues et conditionnelles ; les cas de non-responsabilité criminelle pour cause de troubles mentaux ; et les entrées en suspens telles que les accusations, les ordonnances judiciaires, les ordonnances de probation et les ordonnances d'interdiction.  <br>Je comprends que les renseignements recueillis à la suite de cette vérification du casier judiciaire ne seront communiqués qu'au Certn et à l'organisation tierce mentionnée ci-dessus, le cas échéant. Le cas échéant, je comprends que c'est l'organisation susmentionnée, et non le partenaire policier, qui déterminera l'impact des résultats de la recherche. Je comprends que l'exactitude des informations qui me seront communiquées n'est pas et ne peut pas être garantie et qu'elle peut comporter des erreurs ou des omissions.  <br>Par ma signature ci-dessous, et pour et en considération de la vérification de mon casier judiciaire, dont je reconnais par la présente la réception et la suffisance, j'accepte de ne pas intenter d'actions en justice, de réclamations ou de demandes, pour des pertes ou des dommages, y compris indirects ou consécutifs, que je pourrais subir en raison de la vérification de mon casier judiciaire, contre la municipalité ou le partenaire policier qui a effectué la vérification du casier judiciaire, son conseil de police associé et ses employés, et de les libérer de toute responsabilité et de toute action, réclamation ou demande, même si elles découlent de leur négligence ou même d'une négligence grave.  <br>Je comprends qu'il peut m'être demandé de fournir mes empreintes digitales pour confirmer mon identité avant d'obtenir les résultats de la vérification de mon casier judiciaire.  <br>J'ai lu et compris ce formulaire, et en particulier cette section, et en signant ci-dessous, je consens aux conditions susmentionnées. En signant, je certifie également que les informations que j'ai fournies sont, à ma connaissance, exactes et correctes.  <br>J'autorise le partenaire policier à fournir les résultats de la vérification du casier judiciaire directement au Certn et à l'organisation ou à la personne qui demande la vérification du casier judiciaire mentionnée ci-dessus. |     |

|     |     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| Signature: | {{first\_name}} {{last\_name}} | Date: | {{todays\_date}} |

Identity Fraud Notice
---------------------

### Version 2.0

##### Effective October 9th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

Para información en español, visite www.consumerfinance.gov/learnmore o escribe a la Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, 1700 G Street N.W., Washington, DC 20552.

Remedying the Effects of Identity Theft

You are receiving this information because you have been notified a consumer reporting company that you believe that you are a victim of identity theft. Identity theft occurs when someone uses your name, Social Security number, date of birth, or other identifying information, without authority, to commit fraud. For example, someone may have committed identity theft by using your personal information to open a credit card account or to get a loan in your name. For more information, visit [www.consumerfinance.gov/learnmore](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/www.consumerfinance.gov/learnmore) or write to: Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, 1700 G Street N.W., Washington, DC 20552.

The Fair Credit Reporting Act (FCRA) gives you specific rights when you are, or believe that you are, the victim of identity theft. Here is a brief summary of the rights designed to help you recover from identity theft.

1. You have the right to ask that nationwide consumer reporting companies place “fraud alerts” in your file to let potential creditors and others know that you may be a victim of identity theft. A fraud alert can make it more difficult for someone to get credit in your name because it tells creditors to follow certain procedures to protect you. It also may delay your ability to obtain credit. You may place a fraud alert in your file by calling just one of the three nationwide consumer reporting agencies. As soon as the agency processes your fraud alert, it will notify the other two, which then also must place fraud alerts in your file.

o Equifax: 1-800-525-6285; [www.equifax.com](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/www.equifax.com)

o Experian: 1-888-397-3742; [www.experian.com](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/www.experian.com)

o TransUnion: 1-800-680-7289; [www.transunion.com](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/www.transunion.com)

An initial fraud alert stays in you file for at least 90 days. An extended alert stays in your file for seven years. To place either of these alerts, a consumer reporting agency will require you to provide appropriate proof of your identity, which may include your Social Security number. If you ask for an extended alert, you will also have to provide an identity theft report. An identity theft report includes a copy of a report you have files with a federal, state, or local law enforcement agency, and additional information a consumer reporting agency may require you to submit. For more detailed information about the identity theft report, visit [www.consumerfinance.gov/learnmore](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/www.consumerfinance.gov/learnmore) .

2. **You have the right to free copies of the information in your file (your “file disclosure”).**

An initial fraud alert entitles you to a copy of all the information in your file at each of the three nationwide agencies, and an extended alert entitles you to two free file disclosures in a 12-month period following the placing of the alert. These additional disclosures may help you detect signs of fraud, for example, whether fraudulent accounts have been opened in your name or whether someone has reported a change in your address. Once a year, you also have the right to a free copy of the information in your file at any consumer reporting agency, if you believe it has inaccurate information due to fraud, such as identity theft. You also havethe ability to obtain additional free file disclosures under other provisions of the FCRA. See [www.consumerfinance.gov/learnmore](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/www.consumerfinance.gov/learnmore).

**3.** **You have the right to obtain documents relating to fraudulent transactions made or** **accounts opened using your personal information.** A creditor or other business must give you copies of applications and other business records relating to transactions and accounts that resulted from the theft of your identity, if you ask for them in writing. A business may ask you for proof of your identity, a police report, and an affidavit before giving you the documents. It also may specify an address for you to send your request. Under certain circumstances, a business can refuse to provide you with these documents. See [www.consumerfinance.gov/learnmore](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/www.consumerfinance.gov/learnmore) .

4\. You have the right to obtain information from a debt collector. If you ask, a debt collector must provide you with certain information about the debt you believe was incurred in you name by an identity thief - like the name of the credit and the amount of the debt.

**5.** **If you believe information in your file results from identity theft, you have the right to** **ask that a consumer reporting agency block that information from your file.** An identity thief may run up bills in your name and not pay them. Information about the unpaid bills may appear on your consumer report. Should you decide to ask a consumer reporting agency to block the reporting of this information, you must identity the information to block, and provide the consumer reporting agency with proof of your identity and a copy of your identity theft report. The consumer reporting agency can refuse or cancel your request for a block if, for example, you don’t provide the necessary documentation, or where the block results from an error or a material misrepresentation of fact made by you. If the agency declines or rescinds the block, it must notify you. Once a debt resulting from identity theft has been blocked, a person or business with notice of the block may not sell, transfer, or place the debt for collection.

**6.** You also may prevent businesses from reporting information about you to consumer reporting agencies if you believe the information is a result of identity theft. To do so, you must send your request to the address specified by the business that reports the information to the consumer reporting agency. The business will expect you to identify what information you do not want reported and to provide an identity theft report.

To learn more about identity theft and how to deal with its consequences, visit [www.consumerfinance.gov/learnmore](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/www.consumerfinance.gov/learnmore), or write to the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau.

You may have additional rights under state law. For more information, contact your local consumer protection agency or your state Attorney General.

In addition to the new rights and procedures to help consumers deal with the effects of identity theft, the FCRA has many other important consumer protections. They are described in more detail at [www.consumerfinance.gov/learnmore](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/www.consumerfinance.gov/learnmore) .

California Credit Disclosure
----------------------------

### Version 5.0

##### Effective October 18th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**NOTICE REGARDING CREDIT INFORMATION**

**PURSUANT TO CALIFORNIA LAW**

{{company\_name}} intends to obtain credit information about you from a consumer credit reporting agency for employment purposes (“ **Consumer Credit Reports**”). Consumer Credit Reports may include information about your credit history. The reports obtained by the Company may be used as a factor in making employment decisions. The source of your “Consumer Credit Report” (as that term is defined under California Law) will be Certn (USA) Inc., 3820 Central Avenue #220, Cheyenne, WY 82001, 844-987-0690. Information regarding Certn’s privacy practices (including information about whether any consumer personal information will be sent outside the U.S. or its territories) may be found at: https://certn.co.

The Company intends to obtain a consumer credit report on you for the permissible purpose under California Labor Code 1024.5: \[

\[ {{1024\_5\_a\_1}} \] The job for which you are applying (or if current employee, already occupy) is a managerial position.

\[ {{1024\_5\_a\_2}} \] The job for which you are applying (or if current employee, already occupy) is with the state Department of Justice.

\[ {{1024\_5\_a\_3}} \] The job for which you are applying (or if current employee, already occupy) is a sworn peace officer or other law enforcement position.

\[ {{1024\_5\_a\_4}} \] The job for which you are applying (or if current employee, already occupy) is a position for which the information contained in the report is required by law to be disclosed or obtained.

\[ {{1024\_5\_a\_5}} \] The job for which you are applying (or if current employee, already occupy) is a position that involves regular access, for any purpose other than the routine solicitation and processing of credit card applications in a retail establishment, to all of the following types of information of any one person:

(A)Bank or credit card account information;

(B)Social security number; and

(C)Date of birth.

\[ {{1024\_5\_a\_6}} \] The job for which you are applying (or if current employee, already occupy) is a position in which you would be (any of the following):

A named signatory on the bank or credit card account of the employer;

(B)Authorized to transfer money on behalf of the employer; and

(C)Authorized to enter into financial contracts on behalf of the employer.

\[ {{1024\_5\_a\_7}} \] The job for which you are applying (or if current employee, already occupy) is a position that involves access to confidential or proprietary information, including a formula, pattern, compilation, program, device, method, technique, process or trade secret that: (i) derives independent economic value, actual or potential, from not being generally known to, and not being readily ascertainable by proper means by, other persons who may obtain economic value from the disclosure or use of the information, and (ii) is the subject of an effort that is reasonable under the circumstances to maintain secrecy of the information.

\[ {{1024\_5\_a\_8}} \] The job for which you are applying (or if current employee, already occupy) is a position that involves regular access during the workday to cash totaling Ten Thousand ($10,000) Dollars or more and which belongs to the employer, a customer or client (Depends what was ordered by the End User on the screening page).

Wallet Authorization - EN
-------------------------

### Version 4.2

##### Effective October 29th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**Authorization**

You have asked [Certn](https://certn.co/) to collect, process and deliver the following verifiable credentials through the MyCertn Wallet: {{{services\_list}}}. In order to complete this request, you will be asked to provide the following personal information: {{{personal\_information\_list}}}. We may collect information regarding you directly from you or third parties such as {{{data\_providers\_list}}}. We will compare information received from different sources for consistency.

It may be necessary for Certn to transfer and process your information in multiple jurisdictions, specifically if you have lived, worked or attended school outside of the jurisdiction in which you made the request. Regardless of where Personal Information is processed, it will be handled in accordance with our privacy and security policies.

You can withdraw your consent, dispute the accuracy of your credentials, or ask for a correction, deletion or copy of your information at any time by contacting Certn’s Privacy Officer at 1-844-987-0690 or [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co). Further information regarding the collection, use, disclosure, or storage of your Personal Information can be found in our Privacy Policy ( [https://certn.co/privacy-policy/](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/) ).

DISCLOSURE: INVESTIGATIVE CONSUMER REPORT
-----------------------------------------

### Version 3.1

##### Effective October 30th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**DISCLOSURE: INVESTIGATIVE CONSUMER REPORT**

{{{company\_name}}} has requested {{{requested\_verification\_check\_names}}} which may be defined as an "investigative consumer report” for the purpose of evaluating your current or potential {{{purpose}}} through [Certn](https://certn.co/), a consumer reporting agency. An "**investigative consumer report**" is a background screening report generated through personal interviews with sources such as your co-workers, managers, references or associates.

In order to complete an investigative consumer report, Certn may collect information regarding your {{{verification\_history\_types}}} history from certain knowledgeable individuals for the benefit of the Company. The information contained in the investigative consumer report may bear upon your character, general reputation, personal characteristics, and/or mode of living.

You have the right, upon written request, to be informed of whether or not an investigative consumer report has been requested. You may inspect and receive a copy of the applicable report by contacting {{{certn\_location}}}, 844-987-0690, or [compliance@certn.co](mailto:compliance@certn.co). Information regarding Certn's privacy practices (including information about whether any consumer personal information will be sent outside the U.S. or its territories) may be found in our [privacy policy](https://vault.pactsafe.io/s/5d800911-f26c-4e3a-884d-85117a81799b/legal.html?g=37964#contract-byeg-ihlj).

You have the right to request additional information regarding the nature and scope of any "investigative consumer report" directly from the Company.

Consent (collect, process and report)
-------------------------------------

### Version 1.3

##### Effective November 24th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**AUTHORISATION**

To evaluate your suitability for {{purpose}}, {{company\_name}} (the "**Company**") has asked [Certn](https://certn.co/) to assemble and return a consumer report (your "**Report**") consisting of: {{services\_list}}.

Certn will collect the following personal information for the purpose of completing the Report: {{personal\_information\_list}}. {{#if data\_providers\_list}}Certn may collect Personal Information directly from you, the Company, or third parties such as {{data\_providers\_list}} {{else}}Certn may collect Personal Information directly from you or the Company{{/if}}. Certn will compare information received from different sources for consistency.

It may be necessary for Certn to transfer and process Personal Information in multiple jurisdictions, specifically if you have lived, worked or attended school outside of the jurisdiction in which the Company has ordered the Report. Your Personal Information may be processed by our employees and contractors in Canada, Australia, the United States, the United Kingdom, South Africa, and the Philippines. Regardless of where Personal Information is processed, it will be handled in accordance with our privacy and security policies.

You can withdraw your consent, dispute the accuracy of a Report, or ask for a correction, deletion or copy of your Report at any time by contacting Certn’s Privacy Officer at 1-844-987-0690 or [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co). Further information regarding the collection, use, disclosure, or storage of your Personal Information can be found [here](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/).  

Wallet Authorization en-GB
--------------------------

### Version 2.1

##### Effective October 28th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**Authorisation**

You have asked [Certn](https://certn.co/) to collect, process and deliver the following verifiable credentials through the MyCertn Wallet: {{{services\_list}}}. In order to complete this request, you will be asked to provide the following personal information: {{{personal\_information\_list}}}. We may collect information directly from you or third parties such as {{{data\_providers\_list}}}. We will compare information received from different sources for consistency.

It may be necessary for Certn to transfer and process your information in multiple jurisdictions, specifically if you have lived, worked or attended school outside of the jurisdiction in which you made the request. Regardless of where Personal Information is processed, it will be handled in accordance with our privacy and security policies.

You can withdraw your consent, dispute the accuracy of your credentials, or ask for a correction, deletion or copy of your information at any time by contacting Certn’s Privacy Officer at 1-844-987-0690 or [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co). Further information regarding the collection, use, disclosure, or storage of your Personal Information can be found in our [Privacy Policy](https://vault.pactsafe.io/s/5d800911-f26c-4e3a-884d-85117a81799b/legal.html?g=37964#contract-byeg-ihlj).

Applicant Terms of Use
----------------------

### Version 1.1

##### Effective October 28th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**APPLICANT TERMS OF USE**

Certn collects and processes information, including personal data, for the purpose of providing background screening and verification services (the “**Services**”). By accessing and utilizing the Services, you agree to be bound by the following terms and conditions ("**Terms**"). Before you proceed, please read the Terms below carefully.

**License.**

Certn grants you a license to use the web or mobile application (the “**App**”), along with any updates, documentation, and related services.

**Your Account.**

To access the app, create an account with your name, email, and password, or use single sign-on (SSO) login. You agree to provide accurate, current, and complete information during the registration process, and to update such information as necessary to keep it accurate, current, and complete. Certn will not be responsible for any inaccuracies or third-party decisions resulting from incorrect or incomplete information submitted by you.

You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your account, username, and password and for restricting unauthorized access thereto. You agree to accept responsibility for all activities that occur with your permission or authorization under your account. You agree to notify Certn immediately of any unauthorized use of your account or password, or any other breach of security.

The personal information collected through the App will be used exclusively for the purpose of conducting the Services. Certn will not disclose this information to third parties without your explicit consent, except as required by law.

**Access to Dashboard**.

Certn will provide you with a dashboard that contains, among other things, requests for information, tasks to complete and a repository of completed background checks and verifications, including verifiable credentials, as defined below (“**Results**”). Certn does not, and cannot, provide legal advice or other related services to you. Certn also does not guarantee that any third party you consent to share your Results with will comply with applicable local, provincial, state or federal laws, rules, regulations, and requirements (“**Applicable Laws**”) in their collection or use of such Results.

**Verifiable Credentials.**

If you are using the wallet feature of the App (only available on the mobile app) (“**MyCertn** **Wallet**”) to store, share and verify personal credentials (“**verifiable** **credentials**”) the following terms apply:

* Certn shall not be responsible for any correspondence or relationship between you and any end users with whom you choose to share your personal information.
* You can share verifiable credentials with third parties at any time and for as long as you choose.
* It is your responsibility to ensure that you are comfortable with, and to request and review the privacy policy of, any third party with whom you share your personal information.
* Certn, and the third party issuers providing verifiable credentials to the MyCertn Wallet, do not guarantee that the Services will be error-free, complete, or accurate at all times.
* Certn makes no representation, warranty, or assurance regarding the suitability of the MyCertn Wallet or its services for any particular purpose.
* Certn does not guarantee that the MyCertn Wallet, your use of it, or any Services provided through it will comply with, or help you comply with, any applicable laws or regulations.
* You may download the MyCertn Wallet onto your device for personal use only.
* You may not transfer the MyCertn Wallet or access to the Services to others, except as otherwise stated in this agreement.
* You may withdraw your consent to share your verifiable credentials at anytime, however, if you share your verifiable credential with a third party, you acknowledge that they may retain and use the information as required by law.
* Certn is not responsible for verifying the third party, so we recommend only sharing verifiable credentials with trusted individuals and organizations.

**Device Requirements.**

By using the mobile App, including the MyCertn Wallet, if applicable, you agree to us collecting and using technical information about your device and related software, hardware and peripherals to improve our products and to provide the Services to you.

Use of the App, including the MyCertn Wallet, if applicable, may require that your device meets minimum operating requirements, including memory or operating systems. We will inform you of any minimum system requirements from time to time. If you do not meet the minimum specifications detailed for the App, you may experience limited use or be unable to use or access the MyCertn Wallet or Services entirely.

**Update to the App and Services.**

From time to time we may automatically update the App and revise the Services to improve performance, enhance functionality, reflect changes to the operating system or address security issues (“**Updates**”). Alternatively we may ask you to update the App for these reasons. Updates may modify or delete certain features and/or functionalities. You agree that Certn has no obligation to (i) provide any Updates, or (ii) continue to provide or enable any particular features and/or functionalities of the App.

If you opt out of automatic updates you may not be able to continue using the App or the Services.

We are not responsible for other websites or content. The App may contain links to other independent websites and display, include or make available third-party content (including data, information, applications and other products services) or provide links to third-party websites or services (“**Third-Party Services**”) which are not provided by Certn. Such Third-Party Services are not under Certn’s control, and we are not responsible for and have not checked and approved their content or their privacy policies (if any).

Notwithstanding anything to the contrary in these Terms, you acknowledge and agree that: (a) you access or deploy Third-Party Services through the App at your sole discretion; (b) you should read the terms and conditions and privacy policies associated with any Third-Party Services which govern your use of such Third-Party Services; and (c) Certn does not own or control Third-Party Services.

Certn does not in any way warrant the accuracy, reliability, security, completeness, usefulness, non-infringement, or quality of any Third-Party Services. You agree that you bear all risks associated with using or relying on Third-Party Services.

**Using our Services.**

By using the Services and App you agree and confirm that:

* You will use the Services and App in accordance with the Terms and all Applicable Laws.
* You are of legal age in your jurisdiction.
* You have the right to provide the information submitted to Certn.
* The information provided is true, accurate, and not misleading.
* You are the individual the information pertains to.
* The information does not infringe any third-party legal obligations or rights, including intellectual property or privacy rights.

**Your Privacy.**

In accordance with applicable data protection legislation, we are required to provide you with certain information about who we are, how we process your personal information and for what purposes, and your rights in relation to your personal information and how to exercise them. This information is provided within the Certn [Privacy Policy](https://vault.pactsafe.io/s/5d800911-f26c-4e3a-884d-85117a81799b/legal.html?g=37964#contract-byeg-ihlj), unless you are using a specific Service to which a different privacy policy applies, which we will make available to you.

By providing your personal information, you consent to Certn sharing such information with the necessary third-party service providers required to fulfill your request to complete the Services. These third-parties shall be entitled to rely on this consent to collect information about you, solely for the purpose of fulfilling the Services.

In the event that Certn or a third party ceases operating or otherwise ceases to make available the Services to you, your personal information will be purged from our systems, upon notice to you and any third party with whom you shared your information, in accordance with applicable data protection legislation.

Your information, which may include personal information, financial information, login credentials, communication data, and sensitive personal data, that we hold on our servers is encrypted at rest using the industry standard AES-256 encryption algorithm, and encrypted in flight using TLS 1.2 as a minimum. We only store your information as long as it is needed, in accordance with applicable laws and regulations.

**Access to Results.**

Certn will provide you with Results as well as status updates related to the Results through the App. The Results provided will be based on information provided to Certn by third-party sources, and Certn cannot guarantee the accuracy, completeness, or timeliness of the information contained in the Results. You acknowledge and agree that Certn is not responsible for any errors, omissions, or inaccuracies within the Results.

**Disputes, Corrections, Deletions**.

If you wish to dispute any Results, or correct any inaccuracies associated with your personal information, you can do so within the App. You can also request access to or for the deletion of any information that was previously provided to or shared by Certn.

**Restrictions**.

You agree not to access or use the App for any unlawful purpose or for any other purpose other than that for which Certn makes it available.

You specifically acknowledge that you shall not:

* Provide or transmit data that is illegal, harmful, threatening, insulting, disturbing, injurious, obscene, defamatory, unacceptable from a racial or ethnic perspective.
* Violate any of Certn’s intellectual property rights.
* Unlawfully gather or disclose information about others through the App.
* Use any information obtained from the App in order to harass, abuse, or harm another person.
* Attempt to impersonate another user or person or use the username of another user.
* Transmit malicious software or any programs designed to disrupt the App or Certn’s systems.
* Misuse Certn's support services or submit false requests or background check orders.
* Disassemble, decompile, or reverse engineer any part of the App or otherwise attempt to derive any source code or underlying ideas or algorithms of any part of the App or Services or create derivative works based on it.
* Use, or attempt to use, the App for unauthorized purposes.
* Use the App for the benefit of any third party without Certn’s prior written permission.
* Modify, remove, or obscure any copyright, trademark, patent or other notices or legends that appear on the App.
* Create liability for Certn or its service providers or cause Certn to lose the services of our service providers.
* Rent, lease, sub-license, or make the App or Services available to others without prior written consent from Certn.

**Intellectual Property**.

All Intellectual Property Rights (as defined below) related to the App and Services shall be owned by Certn absolutely and in their entirety. These rights include database rights, patents, copyrights, trademarks (whether registered or unregistered), trade secrets, design rights (whether registered or unregistered) know-how, mask works, moral rights, and all similar rights that may exist now or later in any jurisdiction, including without limitation any applications and registrations for the foregoing, and the Certn name, logos, designs, domain names, graphics, icons, scripts, service marks, features, functions, text, graphics, button icons, images, software, data compilations and other distinctive brand features, and the compilation and organization thereof (“**Intellectual Property Rights**”).

Subject to these Terms, Certn grants you a worldwide, limited, revocable, non-exclusive license to access and use the App and Services as they are provided to you by Certn for your personal, non-commercial use only. The license is non-transferable and non-assignable, and you shall not grant to any third party any right, permission, license or sublicense with respect to any of the rights granted hereunder without Certn’s prior written permission, which it may withhold in its sole discretion. You do not acquire any ownership or other intellectual property rights in the App or the Services beyond this limited right of use. Violation of any provision of this license may result in immediate termination of the license, in Certn’s sole discretion.

**Responsibilities.**

The App and the Services are not intended to provide legal, tax or financial advice. The Services, or certain portions and/or functionalities thereof, are provided with the understanding that neither we nor our third-parties are engaged in rendering accounting, investment, tax, legal, or other professional services. Certn specifically disclaims any liability, loss, or risk which is incurred as a consequence, directly or indirectly, of the use and application of any of the content on the App. Further, we and our third-party service providers are not responsible for any credit, insurance, employment or investment decisions or any damages or other losses resulting from decisions that arise in any way from the use of the Services or any materials or information accessible through it. Past performance does not guarantee future results.

YOU AGREE YOUR USE OF THE SERVICES AND ALL INFORMATION AND CONTENT (INCLUDING THAT OF THIRD PARTIES) IS AT YOUR RISK AND IS PROVIDED ON AN “AS IS” AND “AS AVAILABLE” BASIS. WE, AND OUR THIRD PARTY PROVIDERS, DISCLAIM ALL WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND AS TO THE USE OF THE SERVICES, WHETHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. WE, AND OUR ISSUERS, MAKE NO WARRANTY THAT THE SERVICES (i) WILL MEET YOUR REQUIREMENTS, (ii) WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED, TIMELY, SECURE, OR ERROR-FREE, (iii) THE RESULTS THAT MAY BE OBTAINED FROM THE SERVICES WILL BE ACCURATE OR RELIABLE, (iv) THE QUALITY OF ANY PRODUCTS, SERVICES, INFORMATION, OR OTHER MATERIAL OBTAINED BY YOU THROUGH THE SERVICES WILL MEET YOUR EXPECTATIONS, OR (v) ANY ERRORS IN THE SERVICES OR TECHNOLOGY WILL BE CORRECTED. ANY MATERIAL DOWNLOADED OR OTHERWISE OBTAINED THROUGH THE USE OF THE SERVICES IS DONE AT YOUR OWN DISCRETION AND RISK AND YOU ARE SOLELY RESPONSIBLE FOR ANY DAMAGE TO YOUR COMPUTER SYSTEM OR LOSS OF DATA THAT RESULTS FROM THE DOWNLOAD OF SUCH MATERIAL. WE, ON BEHALF OF OURSELVES AND ALL THIRD-PARTY PROVIDERS, EXPRESSLY DISCLAIM ANY TYPE OF REPRESENTATION OR WARRANTY REGARDING THE AVAILABILITY OR RESPONSE TIME OF THE SERVICES OR CONTENT OR INFORMATION OBTAINED THROUGH THE SERVICES OR THAT SUCH ACCESS WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED OR ERROR-FREE AND, EXCEPT AS EXPRESSLY PROVIDED FOR HEREIN, EXPRESSLY DISCLAIM THE ACCURACY, COMPLETENESS AND CURRENCY OF ALL INFORMATION COLLECTED ON YOUR BEHALF. NO ADVICE OR INFORMATION, WHETHER ORAL OR WRITTEN, OBTAINED BY YOU FROM US OR OUR PROVIDERS THROUGH OR FROM THE SERVICES WILL CREATE ANY WARRANTY NOT EXPRESSLY STATED IN THESE TERMS.

YOU AGREE THAT WE (INCLUDING OUR OFFICERS, DIRECTORS, EMPLOYEES AND AGENTS) AND OUR THIRD-PARTY PROVIDERS WILL NOT BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, CONSEQUENTIAL OR EXEMPLARY DAMAGES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO DAMAGES FOR LOSS OF PROFITS, GOODWILL, USE, DATA OR OTHER LOSSES, EVEN IF WE HAVE BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES, RESULTING FROM (i) THE USE OR THE INABILITY TO USE THE SERVICES AT OUR WEBSITE/MOBILE APPLICATION OR OF ANY THIRD PARTY ACCOUNT PROVIDER’S WEBSITE/MOBILE APPLICATION; (ii) THE COST OF GETTING SUBSTITUTE GOODS AND SERVICES, (iii) ANY PRODUCTS, DATA, INFORMATION OR SERVICES PURCHASED OR OBTAINED OR MESSAGES RECEIVED OR TRANSACTIONS ENTERED INTO, THROUGH OR FROM THE SERVICES, (iv) UNLESS CAUSED BY CERTN, UNAUTHORIZED ACCESS TO OR ALTERATION OF YOUR TRANSMISSION OR DATA, (v) STATEMENTS OR CONDUCT OF ANYONE ON THE SERVICES, (vi) THE USE, INABILITY TO USE, UNAUTHORIZED USE, PERFORMANCE OR NON-PERFORMANCE OF ANY THIRD PARTY SITE, EVEN IF THE PROVIDER HAS BEEN ADVISED PREVIOUSLY OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES, OR (vii) ANY OTHER MATTER RELATING TO THE SERVICES.

CERTN’S LIABILITY TO YOU OR ANY THIRD PARTY FOR ANY CLAIM ARISING OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH YOUR USE OF THE WALLET OR YOUR CREDENTIAL SHALL BE LIMITED TO CAD $1,000.

While Certn strives to provide a reliable and accessible App, Certn does not guarantee uninterrupted access. Maintenance, updates, or unforeseen issues may temporarily impact the availability of the App.

The App is intended for personal and private use. If you use the App for commercial, business, or resale purposes, we will not be liable for any losses, including loss of profit, loss of business, business interruption, or loss of business opportunity.

To the extent permitted by law, we are not responsible for delays, delivery failures, or other loss or damage resulting from the transmission of data over communications networks, including the internet. You acknowledge that using the internet, mobile networks, and other communications media involves risks, such as viruses, data security issues, piracy, service availability, and data transmission reliability. If our provision of the Services or support for the MyCertn Wallet is delayed due to an event outside our control, we will inform you as soon as possible and take steps to minimize the impact of the delay.

**Termination**.

Certn may terminate your access to the App and your Results at any time, with or without cause or notice. Upon termination, you agree to immediately cease using the App.

These Terms are subject to change from time to time. Certn will notify you of any material change within the App. Your continued use of the App will indicate your acceptance of the revised terms.

**Electronic Transaction**.

By using the Services you warrant that you have agreed to transact electronically through the App. You agree that an electronic signature is the legal equivalent of a manual signature. You further warrant that the use of a keypad, mouse or other device to select an item, button, icon or similar act/action, constitutes a valid signature as if actually signed in writing. You also warrant that no certification authority or other third-party verification is necessary to validate an electronic signature, and that the lack of such certification or third-party verification will not in any way affect the enforceability of the electronic signature. After authorizing the use of your electronic signature, you may still withdraw your consent within the App or by reaching out to support@certn.co.

**Governing Law**.

All matters relating to the Services and your access to, and use of, the App, will be governed by the laws in the province of British Columbia and the federal laws of Canada applicable therein.

**Miscellaneous.**

Nothing contained in these Terms shall be construed as creating any employment, agency, partnership, franchise, joint venture, or other form of joint enterprise or authority to bind the other party.

Certn shall not be responsible for any failure or delay in its performance under these Terms due to causes beyond its reasonable control, including, but not limited to, labor disputes, strikes, lockouts, internet or telecommunications failures, shortages of or inability to obtain labor, energy, or supplies, war, terrorism, riot, acts of God or governmental action, pandemic, acts by hackers or other malicious third parties and problems with the Internet generally, and such performance shall be excused to the extent that it is prevented or delayed by reason of any of the foregoing.

Any waiver of a provision of these Terms will only be valid if provided in writing and applies only to the specific occurrence so waived. Failure to enforce any provision will not constitute a waiver.

In the event that any of the provisions in the Terms are held to be invalid or unenforceable in whole or in part, all other provisions will nevertheless continue to be valid and enforceable with the invalid or unenforceable parts severed from the remainder of the Terms.

Certn may update these Terms from time to time. Any changes will be effective upon posting on the App. It is your responsibility to review these Terms regularly.

**Support**.

You can request support via email sent to [support@certn.co](mailto:support@certn.co).

**Notices and Consent to Receive Notices Electronically.**

You consent to receive any agreements, notices, disclosures and other communications (collectively, “**Notices**”) to which these Terms refer electronically including without limitation by e-mail or by posting notices on the App. You agree that all Notices provided electronically satisfy any legal requirement that such communications be in writing. If you have any questions about these Terms, you can contact customer support within the App or via email at [support@certn.co](mailto:support@certn.co).

“**Certn**” is inclusive of Certn Holdings Inc. and each of its subsidiaries.

mg - la - con-648
-----------------

### Version 43.0

##### Effective October 31st 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

Income Verification Terms of Use
--------------------------------

### Version 1.0

##### Effective November 5th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

Income Verification Terms of Use
================================

By completing this income verification request and/or creating a verifiable credential regarding your income verification (“**Services**”), you’re agreeing to follow a few additional terms (“**Terms**”).

**Using our Services.**

You agree and confirm that:

* You will use the Services in accordance with the Terms and all applicable laws.
* You are of legal age in your jurisdiction.
* You have the right to provide the information submitted to Certn.
* You are the individual the information pertains to.
* The information does not infringe any third-party legal obligations or rights, including intellectual property or privacy rights.

**Restrictions**.

You agree not to access or use this Service for any unlawful purpose or for any other purpose other than that for which Certn makes it available.

You specifically acknowledge that you shall not:

* Provide or transmit data that is illegal, harmful, threatening, insulting, disturbing, injurious, obscene, defamatory, unacceptable from a racial or ethnic perspective.
* Violate any of Certn’s intellectual property rights.
* Unlawfully gather or disclose information about others through the Services.
* Use any information obtained from these Services in order to harass, abuse, or harm another person.
* Attempt to impersonate another user or person or use the username of another user.
* Transmit malicious software or any programs designed to disrupt Certn’s systems. Publish or otherwise transmit any malicious software or other computer codes, files or programs designed to interrupt, disrupt or restrict the operation of these Services, Certn’s computer software, hardware, telecommunications equipment or to disrupt the normal transactions on the Services.
* Misuse Certn's support services or submit false requests or background check orders. Make improper use of Certn’s support services, submit false requests, or make any speculative or fraudulent background request orders.
* Disassemble, decompile, or reverse engineer any part of the Services or otherwise attempt to derive any source code or underlying ideas or algorithms of any part of the Services or create derivative works based on it.
* Use, or attempt to use, the Services for unauthorized purposes.
* Use the Services for the benefit of any third party without Certn’s prior written permission.
* Create derivative works based on the Services or use the Services to develop a competitive product offering.
* Modify, remove, or obscure any copyright, trademark, patent or other notices or legends that appear in the Services.
* Create liability for us or our service providers or cause us to lose the services of our service providers.
* Rent, lease, sub-license, or make the Services available to others without prior written consent from Certn.

**Your Income Verification Request.**

You agree to provide accurate, current, and complete information during the check process, and to update such information as necessary to keep it accurate, current, and complete. Certn will not be responsible for any inaccuracies resulting from incorrect or incomplete information submitted by you.

You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your account, username, and password and for restricting unauthorized access thereto. You agree to accept responsibility for all activities that occur with your permission or authorization under your account. You agree to notify Certn immediately of any unauthorized use of your account or password, or any other breach of security.

The personal information collected for this income verification request will be used exclusively for the purpose of conducting the Services. Certn will not disclose this information to third parties without your explicit consent, except as required by law.

Certn is acting independently, and not on behalf of any third party, in providing its application or Services.

**Your Privacy.**

In accordance with applicable data protection legislation, we are required to provide you with certain information about who we are, how we process your personal information and for what purposes and your rights in relation to your personal information and how to exercise them. This information is provided within the Certn [Privacy Policy](https://vault.pactsafe.io/s/5d800911-f26c-4e3a-884d-85117a81799b/legal.html?g=37964#contract-byeg-ihlj).

By providing your personal information and requesting income verification, you consent to Certn sharing your information with the necessary service providers, required to fulfill your request to complete the Services. You may revoke this authorization at any time. Your data (passwords, usernames, PINS, personal information) can be used for the Services, to offer products and services, and for other permissible business purposes. The service providers may reproduce, display, adapt, enhance, aggregate, transmit, distribute and otherwise use your data as necessary or reasonable to provide the Services or to use your data in anonymized and aggregated form to improve the Services provided. The service providers shall be entitled to rely on this consent to collect information about you, solely for the purpose of fulfilling the Services.

If you wish to dispute any information contained in your income verification results or request to have any identified inaccuracies associated with your personal information corrected, you can submit your request to [support@certn.co](mailto:support@certn.co) or within your applicable Certn platform. You may also ask Certn to delete any information that was previously provided to a third party.

In the event that Certn or a third party ceases operating or otherwise ceases to make available the Services to you, your personal information will be purged from our systems, upon notice to you and any third party with whom you shared your information, in accordance with applicable data protection legislation.

**Security.**

Your information, which may include personal information, financial information, login credentials, communication data, and sensitive personal data, that we hold on our servers is encrypted at rest using the industry standard AES-256 encryption algorithm, and encrypted in flight using TLS 1.2 as a minimum. We only store your information as long as it is needed, in accordance with applicable laws and regulations.

You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your account, username, and password and for restricting unauthorized access thereto. You agree to accept responsibility for all activities that occur with your permission or authorization under your account. You agree to notify Certn immediately of any unauthorized use of your account or password, or any other breach of security.

**Income Verification Limitations.**

Income verification does not represent an official record of your account, may not reflect your most recent transactions, and should not be relied on for transactional purposes.

**Intellectual Property Rights.**

All intellectual property rights in the Services are owned by us or our licensors and are licensed to you under a limited, non-exclusive license. This license grants you the right to use the Services solely in accordance with these terms. You do not acquire any ownership or other intellectual property rights in the Services beyond this limited right of use. You agree that Certn and our service providers, as applicable, retain all ownership and proprietary rights in the Services, associated content, technology, mobile applications and websites.

**Responsibilities.**

The Services are not intended to provide legal, tax or financial advice. The Services, or certain portions and/or functionalities thereof, are provided with the understanding that neither we nor our service providers are engaged in rendering accounting, investment, tax, legal, or other professional services. If legal or other professional advice including financial, is required, the services of a competent professional person should be sought. We and our service providers specifically disclaim any liability, loss, or risk which is incurred as a consequence, directly or indirectly, of the use and application of any of the content contained in your income verification result. Further, we and our service providers are not responsible for any credit, insurance, employment or investment decisions or any damages or other losses resulting from decisions that arise in any way from the use of the Services or any materials or information accessible through it. Past performance does not guarantee future results.

YOU AGREE YOUR USE OF THE SERVICES AND ALL INFORMATION AND CONTENT (INCLUDING THAT OF THIRD PARTIES) IS AT YOUR RISK AND IS PROVIDED ON AN “AS IS” AND “AS AVAILABLE” BASIS. WE, AND OUR SERVICE PROVIDERS, DISCLAIM ALL WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND AS TO THE USE OF THE SERVICES, WHETHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. WE, AND OUR SERVICE PROVIDERS, MAKE NO WARRANTY THAT THE SERVICES (i) WILL MEET YOUR REQUIREMENTS, (ii) WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED, TIMELY, SECURE, OR ERROR-FREE, (iii) THE RESULTS THAT MAY BE OBTAINED FROM THE SERVICES WILL BE ACCURATE OR RELIABLE, (iv) THE QUALITY OF ANY PRODUCTS, SERVICES, INFORMATION, OR OTHER MATERIAL OBTAINED BY YOU THROUGH THE SERVICES WILL MEET YOUR EXPECTATIONS, OR (v) ANY ERRORS IN THE SERVICES OR TECHNOLOGY WILL BE CORRECTED. ANY MATERIAL DOWNLOADED OR OTHERWISE OBTAINED THROUGH THE USE OF THE SERVICES IS DONE AT YOUR OWN DISCRETION AND RISK AND YOU ARE SOLELY RESPONSIBLE FOR ANY DAMAGE TO YOUR COMPUTER SYSTEM OR LOSS OF DATA THAT RESULTS FROM THE DOWNLOAD OF SUCH MATERIAL. WE, ON BEHALF OF OURSELVES AND ALL THIRD-PARTY SERVICE PROVIDERS, EXPRESSLY DISCLAIM ANY TYPE OF REPRESENTATION OR WARRANTY REGARDING THE AVAILABILITY OR RESPONSE TIME OF THE SERVICES OR CONTENT OR INFORMATION OBTAINED THROUGH THE SERVICES OR THAT SUCH ACCESS WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED OR ERROR-FREE AND, EXCEPT AS EXPRESSLY PROVIDED FOR HEREIN, EXPRESSLY DISCLAIM THE ACCURACY, COMPLETENESS AND CURRENCY OF ALL INFORMATION COLLECTED ON YOUR BEHALF. NO ADVICE OR INFORMATION, WHETHER ORAL OR WRITTEN, OBTAINED BY YOU FROM US OR OUR SERVICE PROVIDERS THROUGH OR FROM THE SERVICES WILL CREATE ANY WARRANTY NOT EXPRESSLY STATED IN THESE TERMS.

YOU AGREE THAT WE (INCLUDING OUR OFFICERS, DIRECTORS, EMPLOYEES AND AGENTS) AND OUR THIRD-PARTY SERVICE PROVIDERS WILL NOT BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, CONSEQUENTIAL, PUNITIVE, TORT, OR EXEMPLARY DAMAGES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO DAMAGES FOR LOSS OF PROFITS, GOODWILL, USE, DATA OR OTHER LOSSES, EVEN IF WE HAVE BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES, RESULTING FROM (i) THE USE OR THE INABILITY TO USE THE SERVICES AT OUR WEBSITE/MOBILE APPLICATION OR OF ANY THIRD PARTY ACCOUNT PROVIDER’S WEBSITE/MOBILE APPLICATION; (ii) THE COST OF GETTING SUBSTITUTE GOODS AND SERVICES, (iii) ANY PRODUCTS, DATA, INFORMATION OR SERVICES PURCHASED OR OBTAINED OR MESSAGES RECEIVED OR TRANSACTIONS ENTERED INTO, THROUGH OR FROM THE SERVICES, (iv) UNLESS CAUSED BY CERTN, UNAUTHORIZED ACCESS TO OR ALTERATION OF YOUR TRANSMISSION OR DATA, (v) STATEMENTS OR CONDUCT OF ANYONE ON THE SERVICES, (vi) THE USE, INABILITY TO USE, UNAUTHORIZED USE, PERFORMANCE OR NON-PERFORMANCE OF ANY THIRD PARTY SITE, EVEN IF THE PROVIDER HAS BEEN ADVISED PREVIOUSLY OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES, (vii) YOUR DATA MADE AVAILABLE THROUGH THE US DATA ACCESS METHOD, OR (viii) ANY OTHER MATTER RELATING TO THE SERVICES. YOU ACKNOWLEDGE AND AGREE THAT WHEN CERTN OR ITS SERVICE PROVIDERS ACCESS AND RETRIEVE INFORMATION FROM THIRD PARTIES, SUCH ACTS ARE AT YOUR REQUEST AND WITH YOUR PERMISSION AND AUTHORIZATION, AND NOT ON BEHALF OF THE THIRD PARTIES THEMSELVES.

CERTN’S LIABILITY TO YOU OR ANY THIRD PARTY FOR ANY CLAIM ARISING OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH YOUR USE THIS INCOME VERIFICATION REQUEST SHALL BE LIMITED TO CAD $1,000.

Service providers do not warrant that the Services comply with the requirements of the FINRA or those of any other organization anywhere in the world.

Notwithstanding the foregoing, we do not limit or exclude our liability to you where it would be unlawful to do so.

To the extent permitted by law, we and our service providers are not responsible for delays, delivery failures, or other loss or damage resulting from the transmission of data over communications networks, including the internet. You acknowledge that using the internet, mobile networks, and other communications media involves risks, such as viruses, data security issues, piracy, service availability, and data transmission reliability. If our provision of the Services or support is delayed due to an event outside our control, we will inform you as soon as possible and take steps to minimize the impact of the delay.

**Third-Party Accounts.**

With respect to any third-party sites you may access through the Services or with respect to any non-financial institution accounts you include in the Services, you agree:

* You are responsible for all fees charged by the third party in connection with any non- Financial Institution accounts and transactions.
* You agree to comply with the terms and conditions of those accounts and agree that this Agreement does not amend any of those terms and conditions.
* If you have a dispute or question about any transaction on a non- Financial Institution account, you agree to direct these to the account provider.
* Any links to third party sites that we may provide are for your convenience only, and we and our service providers do not sponsor or endorse those sites.
* Any third-party services, which you may be able to access through the Services, are services of those third parties.
* Neither Certn nor our service providers have any responsibility for any transactions and inquiries you initiate at third party sites.
* You are solely responsible for any services you select on third-party sites.
* Certn and our service providers are not liable for any damages or costs of any type arising out of or in any way connected with your use of those third-party services.

**Export Restrictions.**

The Services comply with U.S. export regulations, and you must adhere to these laws.

**Termination and Changes.**

Certn and our service providers reserve the right to change, suspend or discontinue any or all of the Services at any time without prior notice. If the Services are discontinued, your information shall be retained in accordance with applicable data privacy laws and our privacy policies.

**Electronic Transaction**.

By using the Services you warrant that you have agreed to transact electronically. You agree that an electronic signature is the legal equivalent of a manual signature. You further warrant that the use of a keypad, mouse or other device to select an item, button, icon or similar act/action, constitutes a valid signature as if actually signed in writing. You also warrant that no certification authority or other third-party verification is necessary to validate an electronic signature, and that the lack of such certification or third-party verification will not in any way affect the enforceability of the electronic signature. After authorizing the use of your electronic signature, you may still withdraw your consent by reaching out to support@certn.co.

**Governing Law**.

All matters relating to the Services and your access to, and use of, the Services, will be governed by the laws in the province of British Columbia and the federal laws of Canada applicable therein.

**Miscellaneous.**

This Agreement is not assignable. A determination that any provision of this Agreement is unenforceable or invalid shall not render any other provision of this Agreement unenforceable or invalid.

These terms of use are subject to change from time to time. Certn will notify you of any material change. Your continued use of the Services will indicate your acceptance of the revised terms.

**Notices and Consent to Receive Notices Electronically.**

You consent to receive any agreements, notices, disclosures and other communications (collectively, “**Notices**”) to which these Terms refer electronically including without limitation by e-mail or by posting notices with the Services. You agree that all Notices provided electronically satisfy any legal requirement that such communications be in writing.

If you have any questions about these Terms, you can contact customer support via email at [support@certn.co](mailto:support@certn.co).

Conditions D'Utilisation Du Demandeur
-------------------------------------

### Version 1.1

##### Effective November 18th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**CONDITIONS D’UTILISATION DU** **DEMANDEUR**

Certn recueille et traite des renseignements, y compris des données personnelles, dans le but de fournir des services de vérification et de validation des antécédents (les « **Services** »). En accédant aux Services et en les utilisant, vous acceptez d’être lié par les conditions générales suivantes (les « **Conditions »).** Avant de continuer, veuillez lire attentivement les conditions ci-dessous.

**License.**

Certn vous accorde une licence pour utiliser l’application Web ou mobile (l’« **Application** »), ainsi que toute mise à jour, documentation et services connexes.

**Votre compte.**

Pour accéder à l’application, créez un compte avec votre nom, votre adresse de courriel et votre mot de passe, ou utilisez une connexion à identification unique (IU). Vous acceptez de fournir des renseignements exacts, à jour et complets pendant le processus d’inscription, et de mettre à jour ces renseignements au besoin pour les garder exacts, à jour et complets. Certn ne sera pas responsable des inexactitudes ou de décisions de tiers résultant de renseignements incorrects ou incomplets que vous avez soumis.

Vous êtes responsable du maintien de la confidentialité de votre compte, de votre nom d’utilisateur et de votre mot de passe ainsi que de la restriction de l’accès non autorisé à ceux-ci. Vous acceptez d’assumer la responsabilité de toutes les activités qui se produisent avec votre permission ou votre autorisation en vertu de votre compte. Vous acceptez d’aviser immédiatement Certn de toute utilisation non autorisée de votre compte ou de votre mot de passe, ou de toute autre violation de la sécurité.

Les renseignements personnels recueillis par l’entremise de l’Application seront utilisés exclusivement aux fins de fournir les Services. Certn ne divulguera pas ces renseignements à des tiers sans votre consentement explicite, sauf si la loi l’exige.

**Accès au tableau de bord**.

Certn vous fournira un tableau de bord qui contient, entre autres, des demandes d’information, des tâches à effectuer et un répertoire de vérification et de validation des antécédents terminés, y compris les données d’authentification vérifiables, telles que définis ci-dessous (les « **Résultats** »). Certn ne fournit pas, et ne peut pas fournir de conseils juridiques ou d’autres services connexes. Certn ne garantit pas non plus qu’un tiers avec lequel vous consentez à partager vos Résultats se conformera aux lois, aux règles, aux réglementations et aux exigences locales, provinciales, étatiques ou fédérales en vigueur (les « **Lois en vigueur** ») dans leur collecte ou leur utilisation de ces Résultats.

**Identifications vérifiables.**

Si vous utilisez la fonctionnalité de portefeuille de l’Application (disponible uniquement sur l’application mobile) (le « **MyCertn Wallet (Portefeuille MyCertn)** ») pour stocker, partager et vérifier les références personnelles (les « **références vérifiables** »), les conditions suivantes s’appliquent :

* Certn ne sera pas responsable de toute communication ou relation entre vous et tout utilisateur final avec lequel vous choisissez de partager vos renseignements personnels.
* Vous pouvez partager des données d’authentification vérifiables avec des tiers à tout moment et aussi longtemps que vous le souhaitez.
* Il est de votre responsabilité de vous assurer que vous êtes à l’aise avec la politique de protection de la vie privée de tout tiers avec lequel vous partagez vos informations personnelles, et de demander et de consulter cette politique.
* Certn et les émetteurs tiers fournissant des données d’authentification vérifiables au portefeuille MyCertn ne garantissent pas que les Services seront exempts d’erreurs, complets ou exacts en tout temps.
* Certn ne fait aucune déclaration, garantie ou assurance concernant la pertinence du portefeuille MyCertn ou de ses services à un usage particulier.
* Certn ne garantit pas que le portefeuille MyCertn, votre utilisation de celui-ci ou les services fournis par son intermédiaire respecteront ou vous aideront à respecter toute loi ou réglementation en vigueur.
* Vous pouvez télécharger le portefeuille MyCertn sur votre appareil pour un usage personnel seulement.
* Vous ne pouvez pas transférer le portefeuille MyCertn ou l’accès aux services à d’autres, sauf indication contraire dans la présente entente.
* Vous pouvez retirer votre consentement à partager vos données d’authentification vérifiables à tout moment. Toutefois, si vous partagez vos données d’authentification vérifiables avec un tiers, vous reconnaissez qu’il peut conserver et utiliser les renseignements comme l’exige la loi.
* Certn n’est pas responsable de la vérification du tiers; nous recommandons donc de ne partager des données d’authentification vérifiables qu’avec des personnes et des organisations de confiance.

**Exigences relatives à l’appareil.**

En utilisant l’application mobile, y compris le portefeuille MyCertn, le cas échéant, vous nous autorisez à recueillir et à utiliser des renseignements techniques sur votre appareil et les logiciels, le matériel et les périphériques connexes, pour améliorer nos produits et vous fournir les services.

L’utilisation de l’application, y compris le portefeuille MyCertn, le cas échéant, peut nécessiter que votre appareil réponde aux exigences minimales de fonctionnement, notamment en ce qui concerne la mémoire ou les systèmes d’exploitation. Nous vous informerons de toute exigence système minimale de temps à autre. Si vous ne répondez pas aux spécifications minimales détaillées pour l’Application, vous pourriez éprouver une utilisation limitée ou ne pas être en mesure d’utiliser ou d’accéder entièrement au portefeuille ou aux services MyCertn.

**Mise à jour de l’application et des services.**

De temps à autre, nous pouvons mettre à jour automatiquement l’Application et réviser les Services pour rehausser la performance, améliorer les fonctionnalités, refléter les changements apportés au système d’exploitation ou résoudre des problèmes de sécurité (les « **Mises à jour** »). Nous pouvons également vous demander de mettre à jour l’Application pour ces raisons. Les mises à jour peuvent modifier ou supprimer certaines caractéristiques ou fonctionnalités. Vous convenez que Certn n’a aucune obligation (i) de fournir des Mises à jour, ou (ii) de continuer à fournir ou à activer des caractéristiques et/ou fonctionnalités particulières de l’Application.

Si vous vous désabonnez des mises à jour automatiques, vous pourriez ne pas être en mesure de continuer à utiliser l’Application ou les Services.

Nous ne sommes pas responsables des autres sites Web ou contenus. L’Application peut contenir des liens vers d’autres sites Web indépendants et afficher, inclure ou rendre disponible du contenu tiers (y compris des données, des informations, des applications et d’autres services de produits) ou fournir des liens vers des sites Web ou des services tiers (les « **Services tiers** ») qui ne sont pas fournis par Certn. Ces Services tiers ne sont pas sous le contrôle de Certn, et nous ne sommes pas responsables de leur contenu ou de leurs politiques de confidentialité (le cas échéant) et nous n’avons pas vérifié et approuvé leur contenu ou leurs politiques de confidentialité.

Nonobstant toute disposition contraire dans les présentes Conditions, vous reconnaissez et acceptez que : (a) vous accédez aux Services de tiers ou les déployez par l’entremise de l’Application à votre seule discrétion; (b) vous devez lire les conditions générales et les politiques de confidentialité associées aux Services de tiers qui régissent votre utilisation de ces Services de tiers; et (c) Certn ne possède pas ou ne contrôle pas les Services de tiers.

Certn ne garantit en aucun cas l’exactitude, la fiabilité, la sécurité, l’exhaustivité, l’utilité, le respect du droit d’auteur ou la qualité de tout Service tiers. Vous convenez que vous assumez tous les risques associés à l’utilisation ou à l’utilisation de services de tiers.

**Utilisation de nos Services.**

En utilisant les Services et l’Application, vous acceptez et confirmez que :

* Vous utiliserez les Services et l’Application conformément aux Conditions et à toutes les Lois en vigueur.
* Vous avez l’âge légal dans votre juridiction.
* Vous avez le droit de fournir les renseignements soumis à Certn.
* Les renseignements fournis sont véridiques, exacts et non trompeurs.
* Vous êtes la personne concernée par les informations.
* Les renseignements ne violent aucune obligation ou aucun droit juridique de tiers, y compris les droits de propriété intellectuelle ou de confidentialité.

**Votre vie privée.**

Conformément à la législation en vigueur en matière de protection des données, nous sommes tenus de vous fournir certains renseignements sur qui nous sommes, comment nous traitons vos renseignements personnels et à quelles fins, et sur vos droits en ce qui concerne vos renseignements personnels et comment les exercer. Ces renseignements sont fournis dans la [Politique de confidentialité](https://vault.pactsafe.io/s/5d800911-f26c-4e3a-884d-85117a81799b/legal.html?g=37964#contract-bylz4uhm3) de Certn, à moins que vous utilisiez un Service spécifique auquel une politique de confidentialité différente s’applique, que nous mettrons à votre disposition.

En fournissant vos renseignements personnels, vous consentez à ce que Certn partage ces renseignements avec les fournisseurs de services tiers nécessaires pour répondre à votre demande de prestation des Services. Ces tiers ont le droit de se fier à ce consentement pour recueillir des renseignements à votre sujet, uniquement dans le but de fournir les Services.

Dans l’éventualité où Certn ou un tiers cesse d’exploiter ou cesse autrement de vous rendre les Services, vos renseignements personnels seront supprimés de nos systèmes, sur préavis, à vous et à tout tiers avec lequel vous avez partagé vos renseignements, conformément à la législation en vigueur en matière de protection des données.

Vos renseignements, qui peuvent inclure des renseignements personnels, des renseignements financiers, des identifiants de connexion, des données de communication et des données personnelles sensibles que nous détenons sur nos serveurs, sont chiffrés au repos à l’aide de l’algorithme de chiffrement AES-256 standard du secteur et chiffrés durant leur transfert à l’aide de TLS 1.2 au minimum. Nous conservons vos renseignements aussi longtemps qu’il est nécessaire seulement, conformément aux lois et aux règlements en vigueur.

**Accès aux Résultats.**

Certn vous fournira des Résultats ainsi que des mises à jour sur l’état des Résultats par le biais de l’Application . Les Résultats fournis seront basés sur les informations fournies à Certn par des sources tierces, et Certn ne peut garantir l’exactitude, l’exhaustivité ou l’actualité des informations contenues dans les résultats. Vous reconnaissez et acceptez que Certn n’est pas responsable des erreurs, des omissions ou des inexactitudes dans les Résultats.

**Litiges, corrections, suppressions.**

Si vous souhaitez contester des Résultats ou corriger des inexactitudes associées à vos renseignements personnels, vous pouvez le faire dans l’application. Vous pouvez également demander l’accès à toute information ou la suppression de toute information qui a déjà été fournie ou partagée par Certn.

**Restrictions.**

Vous acceptez de ne pas accéder à l’Application ou de ne pas l’utiliser à des fins illégales ou à des fins autres que celles pour laquelle Certn la rend disponible.

Vous reconnaissez expressément que vous ne devez pas :

* Fournir ou transmettre des données illégales, nuisibles, menaçantes, insultantes, dérangeantes, préjudiciables, obscènes, diffamatoires, inacceptables d’un point de vue racial ou ethnique.
* Enfreindre l’un des droits de propriété intellectuelle de Certn.
* Recueillir ou divulguer illégalement des renseignements sur d’autres personnes par l’entremise de l’Application.
* Utiliser toute information obtenue de l’Application afin de harceler, d’abuser ou de nuire à une autre personne.
* Tenter d’usurper l’identité d’un autre utilisateur ou d’une autre personne ou d’utiliser le nom d’utilisateur d’un autre utilisateur.
* Transmettre des logiciels malveillants ou tout programme conçu pour perturber l’Application ou les systèmes de Certn.
* Utiliser à mauvais escient les services de soutien de Certn ou soumettre de fausses demandes ou commandes de vérification des antécédents.
* Démonter, décompiler ou désosser une partie de l’Application ou tenter autrement de dégager un code source ou des idées ou algorithmes sous-jacents de toute partie de l’Application ou des Services ou de créer des œuvres dérivées basées sur celle-ci.
* Utiliser ou tenter d’utiliser l’application à des fins non autorisées.
* Utiliser l’Application au profit d’un tiers sans l’autorisation écrite préalable de Certn.
* Modifier, supprimer ou masquer tout droit d’auteur, marque de commerce, brevet ou autre avis ou légende qui apparaissent sur l’Application.
* Créer une responsabilité pour Certn ou ses fournisseurs de services ou faire en sorte que Certn perde les services de nos fournisseurs de services.
* Louer, céder sous bail, concéder en sous-licence ou rendre l’Application ou les Services disponibles à d’autres sans le consentement écrit préalable de Certn.

**Propriété intellectuelle.**

Tous les Droits de propriété intellectuelle (tels que définis ci-dessous) liés à l’Application et aux Services seront la propriété de Certn de manière absolue et dans leur intégralité. Ces droits comprennent les droits à la base de données, brevets, droits d’auteur, marques de commerce (qu’elles soient enregistrées ou non), secrets commerciaux, droits sur la conception (enregistrés ou non); savoir-faire, dessins préliminaires, droits moraux et tout droit similaire qui peuvent exister actuellement ou dans le futur dans n’importe quelle juridiction, y compris, mais sans s’y limiter, toute demande et tout enregistrement pour ce qui précède, ainsi que le nom Certn, les logos, les dessins, les noms de domaine, les graphiques, les icônes, le langage de programmation, les marques de service, les caractéristiques, les fonctions, les textes, les icônes de boutons, les images, les logiciels, les compilations de données et les autres caractéristiques distinctives de la marque, ainsi que la compilation et l’organisation de ces éléments. (« **Droits de propriété intellectuelle** »).

Sous réserve des présentes Conditions, Certn vous accorde une licence mondiale, limitée, révocable et non exclusive pour accéder et utiliser l’Application et les Services tels qu’ils vous sont fournis par Certn pour votre usage personnel et non commercial uniquement. La licence est non transférable et non cessible, et vous ne devez pas accorder à un tiers un droit, une permission, une licence ou une sous-licence concernant l’un des droits accordés en vertu des présentes sans l’autorisation écrite préalable de Certn, qu’elle peut refuser à sa seule discrétion. Vous n’acquérez aucun droit de propriété ou autre droit de propriété intellectuelle sur l’Application ou les Services au-delà de ce droit d’utilisation limité. La violation de toute disposition de cette licence peut entraîner la résiliation immédiate de la licence, à la seule discrétion de Certn.

**Responsabilités.**

L’Application et les Services ne sont pas destinés à fournir des conseils juridiques, fiscaux ou financiers. Les Services, ou certaines parties et/ou fonctionnalités de ceux-ci, sont fournis avec la compréhension que ni nous ni nos tiers ne sommes engagés dans la prestation de services comptables, d’investissement, fiscaux, juridiques ou autres services professionnels. Certn décline spécifiquement toute responsabilité, perte ou risque qui est encouru en conséquence, directement ou indirectement, de l’utilisation et de l’application de tout contenu sur l’Application. De plus, nous et nos fournisseurs de services tiers ne sommes pas responsables des décisions de crédit, d’assurance, d’emploi ou d’investissement ou de tout dommage ou autre perte résultant de décisions qui découlent de l’utilisation des Services ou de tout matériel ou information accessible par son intermédiaire. Le rendement passé ne garantit pas les résultats futurs.

VOUS CONVENEZ QUE VOTRE UTILISATION DES SERVICES ET DE TOUS LES RENSEIGNEMENTS ET CONTENUS (Y COMPRIS CEUX DE TIERS) EST À VOS RISQUES ET EST FOURNIE « TELLE QUELLE » ET « SELON LA DISPONIBILITÉ ». NOUS, ET NOS FOURNISSEURS TIERS, DÉCLINONS TOUTE GARANTIE DE QUELQUE NATURE QUE CE SOIT QUANT À L’UTILISATION DES SERVICES, EXPRESSE OU IMPLICITE, Y COMPRIS, MAIS SANS S’Y LIMITER, LES GARANTIES IMPLICITES DE QUALITÉ MARCHANDE, D’ADÉQUATION À UN USAGE PARTICULIER ET DE RESPECT DU DROIT D’AUTEUR. NOUS, ET NOS ÉMETTEURS, NE GARANTISSONS PAS QUE LES SERVICES (i) RÉPONDRONT À VOS EXIGENCES, (ii) SERONT ININTERROMPUS, LIVRÉS DANS UN DÉLAI RAISONNABLE, SÛRS OU SANS ERREUR, (iii) LES RÉSULTATS QUI PEUVENT ÊTRE OBTENUS PAR LES SERVICES SERONT EXACTS OU FIABLES, (iv) LA QUALITÉ DE TOUT PRODUIT, SERVICE, INFORMATION OU AUTRE MATÉRIEL OBTENU PAR VOUS PAR L’ENTREMISE DES SERVICES RÉPONDRONT À VOS ATTENTES, OU (v) QUE TOUTE ERREUR DANS LES SERVICES OU LA TECHNOLOGIE SERA CORRIGÉE. TOUT MATÉRIEL TÉLÉCHARGÉ OU AUTREMENT OBTENU PAR L’UTILISATION DES SERVICES EST EFFECTUÉ À VOTRE PROPRE DISCRÉTION ET À VOS PROPRES RISQUES ET VOUS ÊTES SEUL RESPONSABLE DE TOUT DOMMAGE À VOTRE SYSTÈME INFORMATIQUE OU DE TOUTE PERTE DE DONNÉES RÉSULTANT DU TÉLÉCHARGEMENT DE CE MATÉRIEL. NOUS, EN NOTRE NOM ET AU NOM DE TOUS LES FOURNISSEURS TIERS, DÉCLINONS EXPRESSÉMENT TOUT TYPE DE DÉCLARATION OU DE GARANTIE CONCERNANT LA DISPONIBILITÉ OU LE TEMPS DE RÉPONSE DES SERVICES OU DU CONTENU OU DES RENSEIGNEMENTS OBTENUS PAR L’INTERMÉDIAIRE DES SERVICES OU QUE CET ACCÈS SERA ININTERROMPU OU EXEMPT D’ERREURS ET, SAUF DISPOSITION EXPRESSE DES PRÉSENTES, DÉCLINONS EXPRESSÉMENT L’EXACTITUDE, L’EXHAUSTIVITÉ ET L’ACTUALITÉ DE TOUS LES RENSEIGNEMENTS RECUEILLIS EN VOTRE NOM. AUCUN CONSEIL OU RENSEIGNEMENT, ORAL OU ÉCRIT, QUE VOUS OBTENIEZ DE NOUS OU DE NOS FOURNISSEURS PAR L’INTERMÉDIAIRE DES SERVICES OU DE CEUX-CI NE CRÉERA DE GARANTIE NON EXPRESSÉMENT ÉNONCÉE DANS LES PRÉSENTES CONDITIONS.

VOUS CONVENEZ QUE NOUS (Y COMPRIS NOS DIRIGEANTS, DIRECTEURS, EMPLOYÉS ET AGENTS) ET NOS FOURNISSEURS TIERS NE SERONT PAS RESPONSABLES DE TOUT DOMMAGE INDIRECT, ACCIDENTEL, SPÉCIAL, CONSÉCUTIFS OU EXEMPLAIRES, Y COMPRIS, MAIS SANS S’Y LIMITER LES DOMMAGES POUR PERTE DE PROFITS, DE VOLONTÉ, D’UTILISATION, DE DONNÉES OU AUTRES PERTES, MÊME SI NOUS AVONS ÉTÉ AVISÉS DE LA POSSIBILITÉ DE TELS DOMMAGES, RÉSULTANT (i) DE L’UTILISATION OU DE L’INCAPACITÉ D’UTILISER LES SERVICES SUR NOTRE SITE WEB OU NOTRE APPLICATION MOBILE OU SUR LE SITE WEB OU L’APPLICATION MOBILE D’UN FOURNISSEUR DE COMPTE TIERS; (ii) DU COÛT DE L’OBTENTION DE BIENS ET DE SERVICES DE REMPLACEMENT, (iii) DE TOUT PRODUIT, DONNÉE, INFORMATION OU SERVICE ACHETÉ OU OBTENU, DE TOUT MESSAGE REÇU OU TOUTE TRANSACTION EFFECTUÉE, PAR L’INTERMÉDIAIRE OU À PARTIR DES SERVICES, (iv) L’ACCÈS NON AUTORISÉ OU L’ALTERATION DE VOTRE TRANSMISSION OU DE VOS DONNÉES, SAUF SI CERTN EN EST LA CAUSE, (vi) L’UTILISATION, L’INCAPACITÉ D’UTILISATION, L’UTILISATION NON AUTORISÉE, LE RENDEMENT OU LE NON-RENDEMENT DE TOUT SITE TIERS, MÊME SI LE FOURNISSEUR A ÉTÉ INFORMÉ AU PRÉALABLE DE LA POSSIBILITÉ DE TELS DOMMAGES, OU (vii) TOUTE AUTRE QUESTION RELATIVE AUX SERVICES.

LA RESPONSABILITÉ DE CERTN ENVERS VOUS OU TOUT TIERS POUR TOUTE RÉCLAMATION DÉCOULANT DE VOTRE UTILISATION DU PORTEFEUILLE OU EN LIEN AVEC CELLE-CI OU DE VOS DONNÉES D’IDENTIFICATION SERA LIMITÉE À 1 000 $ CA.

Bien que Certn s’efforce de fournir une Application fiable et accessible, Certn ne garantit pas un accès ininterrompu. Les problèmes d’entretien, de mises à jour ou imprévus peuvent temporairement affecter la disponibilité de l’Application.

L’application est destinée à un usage personnel et privé. Si vous utilisez l’Application à des fins commerciales, d’affaires ou de revente, nous ne serons pas responsables des pertes, y compris la perte de profit, la perte d’affaires, l’interruption des activités ou la perte d’occasions d’affaires.

Dans la mesure permise par la loi, nous ne sommes pas responsables des retards, des défaillances de livraison ou d’autres pertes ou dommages résultant de la transmission de données sur les réseaux de communication, y compris Internet. Vous reconnaissez que l’utilisation d’Internet, des réseaux mobiles et d’autres médias de communication comporte des risques, comme des virus, des problèmes de sécurité des données, le piratage, la disponibilité des services et la fiabilité de la transmission des données. Si notre prestation des Services ou notre soutien pour le portefeuille MyCertn est retardée en raison d’un événement hors de notre contrôle, nous vous en informerons dès que possible et prendrons des mesures pour minimiser l’impact du retard.

**Résiliation.**

Certn peut mettre fin à votre accès à l’Application et à vos Résultats à tout moment, avec ou sans motif ou préavis. En cas de résiliation, vous acceptez de cesser immédiatement d’utiliser l’Application.

Les présentes Conditions peuvent être modifiées de temps à autre. Certn vous informera de tout changement important dans l’Application. Votre utilisation continue de l’Application indiquera que vous acceptez les conditions révisées.

**Transaction électronique**.

En utilisant les Services, vous garantissez que vous avez accepté de faire des transactions par voie électronique par l’entremise de l’Application. Vous convenez qu’une signature électronique est l’équivalent légal d’une signature manuscrite. Vous garantissez également que l’utilisation d’un clavier, d’une souris ou d’un autre appareil pour sélectionner un élément, un bouton, une icône ou un geste/action similaire constitue une signature valide comme si elle était effectivement signée par écrit. Vous garantissez également qu’aucune autorité de certification ou autre vérification par un tiers n’est nécessaire pour valider une signature électronique, et que l’absence d’une telle certification ou vérification par un tiers n’aura aucune incidence sur l’applicabilité de la signature électronique. Après avoir autorisé l’utilisation de votre signature électronique, vous pouvez toujours retirer votre consentement dans l’Application ou en communiquant avec support@certn.co.

**Loi en vigueur.**

Toutes les questions relatives aux Services et à votre accès à l’Application et à son utilisation seront régies par les lois de la province de la Colombie-Britannique et les lois fédérales du Canada qui s’y appliquent.

**Divers**.

Aucune disposition des présentes Conditions ne doit être interprétée comme créant un emploi, une agence, un partenariat, une franchise, une coentreprise ou toute autre forme de coentreprise ou d’autorité pour lier l’autre partie.

Certn ne sera pas responsable de tout éventuel manquement ou retard dans son exécution des obligations que lui imposent les Conditions qui découlerait de causes indépendantes de sa volonté, y compris, mais sans s’y limiter, les conflits du travail, les grèves, les lock-out, les pannes d’Internet ou de télécommunications, les pénuries ou l’impossibilité d’obtenir de la main-d’œuvre, de l’énergie ou des fournitures, la guerre, le terrorisme, les émeutes, les catastrophes naturelles ou les actions gouvernementales, les pandémies, les actes de pirates informatiques ou d’autres tiers malveillants et les problèmes liés à Internet en général, et cette exécution sera excusée dans la mesure où elle est empêchée ou retardée en raison de l’un des éléments susmentionnés.

Toute renonciation à une disposition des Conditions ne sera valable que si elle est établie par écrit et qu’elle ne s’applique qu’à l’élément spécifique mentionné. Le défaut d’appliquer une disposition ne saurait constituer une renonciation à ladite disposition.

Dans l’éventualité où l’une ou l’autre des dispositions de ces Conditions serait réputée invalide ou inapplicable en tout ou en partie, toutes les autres dispositions continueront néanmoins d’être valides et exécutoires, et les éléments invalides ou inapplicables seront retirés du reste des présentes Conditions.

Certn peut mettre à jour ces Conditions de temps à autre. Toute modification entrera en vigueur dès sa publication sur l’Application. Il est de votre responsabilité d’examiner régulièrement ces Conditions.

**Soutien.**

Vous pouvez demander du soutien par un courriel envoyé à [support@certn.co](mailto:support@certn.co).

**Avis et consentement à recevoir des avis par voie électronique.**

Vous consentez à recevoir tous les accords, avis, divulgations et autres communications (collectivement, les « **Avis »)** auxquels les présentes Conditions font référence par voie électronique, y compris, mais sans s’y limiter, par courriel ou par publication d’avis sur l’Application. Vous acceptez que tous les Avis fournis par voie électronique satisfont à toute exigence légale selon laquelle ces communications doivent être faites par écrit. Si vous avez des questions au sujet des présentes Conditions, vous pouvez communiquer avec le service à la clientèle dans l’Application ou par courriel à l’adresse [support@certn.co](mailto:support@certn.co).

« **Certn** » comprend Certn Holdings Inc. et chacune de ses filiales.

FCRA Disclosure
---------------

### Version 1.2

##### Effective November 21st 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**DISCLOSURE**

**CONSUMER REPORT**

{{company\_name}} (the “**Company**") has requested a "consumer report" on you for the purpose of {{purpose}}, through [Certn](https://certn.co/) (a consumer reporting agency). A "**consumer report**" is a background screening report that may contain information regarding your domestic and international background history, including but not limited to, your social security number and identification documents, criminal history, sex offender registry status, credit history, employment history, education history, driving history, professional licenses, drug testing results and other information about you.

NYC Fair Housing Notice
-----------------------

### Version 2.0

##### Effective December 9th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

Int. No. 632-A

Section 1. The administrative code of the city of New York is amended by adding a new section 8-102a to read as follows:

8-102a. For purposes of paragraph (o) of subdivision 5 of section 8-107, the following terms have the following meanings:

Criminal background check. The term “criminal background check” means the following actions:

1\. Asking an individual, orally or in writing, if they have a criminal history;

2\. Searching publicly available records, including through a third party, such as a consumer reporting agency, private database, or website, for information about an individual’s criminal history; or

3\. Otherwise gathering records or information relating to an individual’s criminal history.

Criminal history. The term “criminal history” means an individual’s conviction history, non-convictions and excludable matters, and pending cases.

Excludable matters. The term “excludable matters” means:

1\. A criminal action that was resolved in favor of an individual, including actions concluded in one of the following ways:

(a) Termination in favor of the individual;

(b) Adjudication as a youthful offender or for juvenile delinquency;

(c) Conviction of a violation; or

(d) Conviction that has been sealed;

2\. Criminal charges pending for which a court has issued an adjournment in contemplation of dismissal pursuant to sections 170.55, 170.56, 210.46, 210.47, or 215.10 of the New York criminal procedure law, or pursuant to a comparable law of another jurisdiction that is in effect; and

3\. A disposition of a criminal matter under federal law or the laws of another jurisdiction that results in a status comparable to what results from an “excludable matter” under New York law.

Pending case. The term “pending case” means a criminal accusation or an arrest based on a criminal accusation that has not yet been adjudicated to a verdict or dismissed at the time the criminal background check or analysis is conducted by a covered entity. An action that has been adjourned in contemplation of dismissal shall not be considered a pending case unless, prior to the time the criminal background check or analysis is conducted by a covered entity the order to adjourn in contemplation of dismissal is revoked and the case is restored to the calendar for further prosecution.

Reviewable criminal history. 1. The term “reviewable criminal history” means:

(a) Any conviction registered on the New York sex offense registry maintained by the state division of criminal justice services pursuant to section 168b of the New York corrections law, on the federal sex offense registry created pursuant to section 20902 of title 34 of the United States code, or on a register in any other jurisdiction for which an individual is required to register as a sex offender;

(b) Any other misdemeanor conviction under the laws of New York or another jurisdiction where less than three years have passed from (a) the date of release from incarceration, or (b) the date of sentencing for an individual who was not sentenced to a period of incarceration;

(c) Any other felony conviction under the laws of New York or another jurisdiction where less than five years have passed from (a) the date of release from incarceration, or (b) the date of sentencing for an individual who was not sentenced to a period of incarceration.

2\. However, the term “reviewable criminal history” shall not include:

(a) Convictions that have been sealed, expunged, the subject of an executive pardon, the subject of a certificate of relief from disabilities, or otherwise legally nullified or vacated;

(b) Convictions in another jurisdiction for (i) having sought, obtained, provided, or facilitated reproductive or gender-affirming care, as defined in section 10-184.1 of the administrative code, outside the state of New York under circumstances where the conduct would have been lawful had it occurred in the state of New York; (ii) having engaged in “legally protected health activity” as defined in section 570.17 of the New York criminal procedure law; or (iii) conviction for the possession of cannabis that would not constitute a felony in the state of New York; or

(c) Excludable matters.

§ 2. Subdivision 5 of section 8-107 of title 8 of the administrative code of the city of New York is amended by adding a new paragraph (o) to read as follows:

(o) _Protections based on criminal history; housing._

(1) It shall be an unlawful discriminatory practice for the owner, lessor, lessee, sublessee, assignee, or managing agent of, or other person having the right to sell, rent or lease or approve the sale, rental or lease of a housing accommodation, constructed or to be constructed, or an interest therein, or any agent or employee thereof, or any real estate broker or agent or employee thereof to:

(A) Refuse to sell, rent, lease, approve the sale, rental or lease or otherwise deny to or withhold from any individual such a housing accommodation or an interest therein because of such individual’s criminal history, other than an individual’s reviewable criminal history obtained and considered in conformity with this paragraph;

(B) Discriminate against any individual in the terms, conditions, or privileges of the sale, rental, or lease of any such housing accommodation or an interest therein or in the furnishing of facilities or services in connection therewith, because of such individual’s criminal history;

(C) Represent to any individual that any housing accommodation or an interest therein is not available for inspection, sale, rental, or lease because of such individual’s criminal history, except when consideration of such criminal history is permitted by, and the covered entity has complied with, the procedures required under this paragraph;

(D) Declare, print, or circulate, or cause to be declared, printed, or circulated, any statement, advertisement, or publication, or use any form of application for the purchase, rental or lease of such a housing accommodation or an interest therein, which expresses, directly or indirectly, any limitation, specification, or discrimination in housing because of an individual’s criminal history; except as permitted under this paragraph; or

(E) Conduct a criminal background check in connection with the prospective purchase, or prospective or continuing rental or lease, of a housing accommodation, except where conducted in conformity with this paragraph.

(2) Nothing in subparagraph (1) shall prohibit a covered entity from taking any lawful adverse action against an individual, including a current occupant, for reasons other than such individual’s criminal history, including acts of physical violence committed by such individual against other persons or property on the premises, or other acts that would adversely affect the health, safety, or welfare of other residents, nor shall such paragraph excuse a covered entity from complying with applicable laws relating to victims of domestic violence, sex offenses, or stalking.

(3) Nothing in subparagraph (1) shall:

(A) Prohibit a covered entity from making any statement, communication, advertisement, publication, or application that is required or specifically authorized by a federal, state or local law, rule, or regulation, provided that any such statement, communication, advertisement, publication, or application shall include a citation to the law, rule, or regulation that requires or permits such action;

(B) Prohibit a covered entity from denying a housing accommodation based on an individual’s criminal history where such denial is required or specifically authorized by federal, state, or local law, rule, or regulation, provided that such covered entity shall provide such individual with notice of the law, rule, or regulation that requires or specifically authorizes such action and, where the law permits but does not require an adverse action, provided that such covered entity complies with the requirements of subparagraphs (4), (5), and (6) of this paragraph; or

(C) Prohibit a covered entity from conducting a criminal background check pursuant to any federal, state, or local law, rule, or regulation that requires or specifically authorizes a criminal background check for housing eligibility, provided that, where the law permits but does not require an adverse action, such covered entity complies with the requirements of subparagraphs (4), (5), and (6) of this paragraph.

(4) _Preliminary determination and notice of criminal background check._ Except where following this process would conflict with a requirement of federal or state law, rule, or regulation, a covered entity that intends to conduct a criminal background check of an individual in connection with a prospective purchase, or prospective or continuing rental or lease of a housing accommodation, shall not conduct such criminal background check until such covered entity has taken the following actions:

(A) In the case of a transaction involving the purchase of housing or shares in housing, the seller has accepted an offer and agreed in writing that the seller will not revoke the acceptance or change the conditions of the deal on the basis of the buyer’s criminal history except as permitted by this paragraph;

(B) In the case of any other transaction involving lease or rental, the covered entity has provided to such individual a rental or lease agreement that commits the housing accommodation to the applicant, which may only be revoked based on a criminal background check conducted in accordance with the fair chance housing process set forth in subparagraph (5), or upon an unrelated material omission, misrepresentation, or change in the qualifications for tenancy that was not known at the time of the conditional offer;

(C) In all such cases, has provided such individual notice of such criminal background check and a written copy of the city’s fair chance housing notice summarizing the rights in this paragraph, which shall be created and made publicly available by the commission.

(5) _Fair chance housing process._ After providing notice of a criminal background check, and prior to taking any adverse action because of an individual’s reviewable criminal history, and except where such action conflicts with a requirement of federal or state law, rule, or regulation, the covered entity shall:

(A) Provide the applicant a written copy of:

(i) Any information or records about reviewable criminal history based on which the covered entity intends to take adverse action;

(ii) Any information about such individual’s criminal history, other than their reviewable criminal history, that the covered entity received, even if the covered entity did not consider such information in making its determination; and

(iii) Provide notice that such individual may, no later than five business days following the receipt of such information, submit to the covered entity any information identifying errors in the criminal history information provided by the covered entity, and any supplemental or mitigating information in support of their application for purchase, rental, or lease.

(6) _Adverse action based on reviewable criminal history._ If, after conducting the fair chance housing process pursuant to subparagraph (5) of this paragraph, a covered entity considers taking adverse action because of an individual’s reviewable criminal history, such covered entity shall first:

(A) Conduct an individualized assessment of the individual’s reviewable criminal history and timely information submitted by such individual pursuant to subparagraph (5) of this paragraph; and

(B) Provide such individual with a written copy of the reason for the adverse action, including:

(i) A copy of supporting documents that were reviewed; and

(ii) A written statement of the reason for such adverse action, demonstrating: (i) how the individual’s reviewable criminal history is relevant to a legitimate business interest of the property owner, and (ii) how any information submitted in support of such individual’s tenancy was taken into account.

(7) If a covered entity utilizes a third party to conduct a consumer background check or criminal background check on their behalf, such covered entity shall take reasonable steps to ensure that such check is conducted consistent with the provisions of this paragraph. Except where a covered entity’s actions are required or authorized pursuant to federal, state, or local law, a covered entity may be liable for relying on criminal history other than reviewable criminal history if the covered entity failed to take reasonable steps to ensure compliance with this paragraph. Where a covered entity knowingly receives criminal history information other than reviewable criminal history information, such receipt creates a rebuttable presumption that the covered entity relied on such information in violation of this paragraph, which such covered entity may rebut by affirmatively showing that they complied with the fair housing process described in subparagraphs (4), (5), and (6) and did not rely on such information in making a determination about a sale, rental, or lease.

(8) This paragraph shall not apply to the sale or rental of:

(A) A housing accommodation, other than a publicly-assisted housing accommodation, in a building that contains housing accommodations for not more than two families living independently of each other, if the owner or members of the owner's family reside in one of such housing accommodations; or

(B) A room or rooms in a housing accommodation, other than a publicly-assisted housing accommodation, if such rental is by the occupant of the housing accommodation or by the owner of the housing accommodation and the owner or members of the owner's family reside in such housing accommodation.

(9) A covered entity shall be immune from liability in any civil action arising as a result of an alleged act of an individual with a criminal history based on the claim that the covered entity should not have sold, rented or leased, or otherwise granted a housing accommodation or an interest therein, to such individual or as a result of a covered entity's decision not to perform a criminal background check.

§ 3. This local law takes effect January 1, 2025.

OneID Consent - Portal Version (EN) (Copy)
------------------------------------------

### Version 1.0

##### Effective December 11th 2024

* * *

### Table of Contents

* * *

**Biometric Consent**

We need your consent to collect and process your biometric data for the purpose of verifying your identity on behalf of {{{company\_name}}} (the “**Company**”). Biometric data in this instance includes facial features from a real-time photo and information from your government-issued ID. We will store your biometric data securely and implement appropriate measures to safeguard such information against unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction.

By clicking “agree” below, you confirm that you have read and understood this Biometric Consent, as well as our [Biometric Notice](https://vault.pactsafe.io/s/5d800911-f26c-4e3a-884d-85117a81799b/legal.html?g=37964#contract-s1qa70-t6), and you agree to the collection and processing of your biometric data in accordance with these terms and our [Privacy Policy](https://certn.co/privacy-policy/). Further, you acknowledge and agree to the transfer of your biometric data to the Company in connection with your background check and verification and any applicable third-party sub-processors, solely for the purpose of completing your identity verification. This consent is given voluntarily and with the understanding that the data will be used exclusively for identity verification including the prevention and combat of fraud. Your biometric data, and where required by law, any information or copy of documents collected to support your identity verification, will be retained for the duration necessary to fulfill the intended purpose and as required by applicable laws, and will be securely deleted thereafter. If you choose not to consent, we may not be able to process your application or provide verification results for your background check.

You can revoke your consent at any time by notifying us in writing at [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co). Upon revocation, we will notify the Company and cease the collection, use, and retention of your biometric data. You have the right to request access to your biometric data and to request corrections or deletions of inaccuracies. If you require more information about the nature and scope of your data processing or for a copy of the information we hold about you, please contact Certn’s Privacy Officer at 1-844-987-0690 or [privacy@certn.co](mailto:privacy@certn.co).

If you reside in a location that is different from our processing locations or the location of the Company, we may transfer your Personal Information for the purpose of completing the identity verification, in accordance with our [Privacy Policy](https://vault.pactsafe.io/s/5d800911-f26c-4e3a-884d-85117a81799b/legal.html?g=37964#contract-byeg-ihlj) and applicable privacy laws.

* * *

Copyright © 2024, [Certn](http://certn.co/)
